Okie do. I suppose everybody's pretty
tired at this point, but I hope that
I can keep your attention and keep
you awake through this presentation.
This is about Dossiers.
I think that this is actually one of the
more profound topics that this
community could be like you know
thought leaders and world experts on
there's a lot of untapped potential in
this and I don't think we realize
how cool that potential is. So, I hope I
can convince you and get you guys
excited about this.
This topic represents
kind of the synthesis of a bunch of
stuff that I've been working on in the
telco space, but it really is not a
telco topic.
I remember when I first heard Sam talk
about ACDC's circa 2019.
He came to a Trust over IP working
group meeting and started talking
about ACDC theory and Sam mentioned
This phrase that ACDC's are a
verifiable data graph and at the time I
thought oh that's cool and it didn't
really like impinge on my consciousness
that deeply but I have since come to
feel that's actually quite a
profound statement and there's more to
it than we give it credit for and we
could use this to solve some problems
that people can't solve elsewhere.
So let me describe the problem as I
encountered it in telco.
I came to telco from a background in
verifiable credentials.
And in verifiable credentials the
assumption is that you prove something
to a verifier and you the party who is
proving something are having a direct
interaction with the verifier.
Right? the verifier sends you a proof
request or something and the proof
request arrives at your wallet and
you get you know it gets your attention
and you make a decision and then the
proof flows back the other way. Well,
guess what? That does not work in telco,
at least in the use cases I was
exploring, because for one thing, we
wanted it to be the case that the party
that emitted a communication and signed
something
Could have that thing that they're
trying to prove verified all along the
way.
Not only that, the party on the other
side doesn't have a channel to go back
yet.
So we needed basically one-way multi-
multipleparty verification
and not only that I needed verification
to be possible
Completely out of the out of band as
well like having an auditor or a
regulator pull a transcript of the
conversation and verify it a day later a
year later or whatever to see if we were
taking the right actions.
And again that's not really what
verifiable credentials are built to do.
This is all setting aside the more
fundamental problems which are, you
know, verifiable credentials have
mutable schemas and all those other
things. But anyway, if you set all that
aside, I still couldn't solve the
problem, right?
so the other thing that became very
obvious is that we needed a much richer
evidence model than the typical
verifiable credential would provide.
Almost 100% of the verifiable credential
workflows that you see demoed or
discussed
anywhere out in the community are single
credential workflows.
show me your driver's license or show me
some subset of the driver's license,
right? Or show me your passport or show
me your COVID thing or whatever. But
there are all kinds of scenarios in real
life every day that call for very rich
collections of evidence.
I listed a few up here and I put
them under kind of headings because I
see these patterns showing up. So,
there's all kinds of processes in the
real world that are evidenceoriented
that deal with applications, right?
You're going to apply for a grant.
You're going to apply to go to college.
You're going to submit a regulatory
filing. You're going to apply for a
job. All of these are processes. They're
typically multi-step processes where a
large body of evidence has to be
assembled and submitted.
That's not the same pattern as this nice
tidy request response
Of verifiable credentials.
There's also research activities that
happen. you're conducting a scientific
study and you want to compile a whole
bunch of evidence
and if you'd like to solve the
problems that we have in the world of
academic research with a
nonreproducibility, you'd like that
evidence that you compile to be
verifiable, right?
Investigative journalism,
Criminal investigations,
all of these fall into this category
as well. And notice here, the evidence
that you're putting in a lot of these
things accretes over time. It's not just
evidence that you just have in one
issuance event and then you're done.
When you're trying to document
something, maybe you're trying to prove
Some things about the reasons why
your company was valued a particular way
to regulators or investors, or you're
trying to capture the results of a
forensic accounting audit. Or you're
trying to submit documents for a
court case,
A court filing. All of these are
cases where evidence is quite important
and verifiability is quite important.
But the simple trust triangle that we
talk about in the verifiable credentials
world is really quite different from
what the patterns of behavior are.
Another thing that became really
clear to me is in realworld hardcore
ambitious use cases,
Lifespans of evidence,
Is a big deal.
This it's surprising now that
I've kind of become sensitized to it.
It's almost shocking to me that this is
never said, but you'll hear somebody
analyzing you know c can we prove xyz
with let's let's say with
certificates or with credentials or
whatever and they'll go through a whole
deep analysis about whether it can be
proved
and they'll completely omit the fact
that they've got four different kinds of
evidence that they're trying to prove
with. And the evidence has different
lifespans,
right? So, one piece of evidence that
they're building from has a year-long
lifespan.
Another piece of evidence has a 20
minute lifespan.
And when you combine those two, what's
the combined lifespan of the thing? 20
minutes. But nobody ever analyzes it
that way. And so, they're the very naive
views about lifespan of evidence.
And you know, I just kind of
randomly picked it. Three different
categories. You could group evidence
into very different lifespan categories
than these ones I picked. But the
point is we need to start thinking about
the lifespan of evidence a little bit
more carefully. And if we do, we're
going to realize that the simple way
that we've been trying to solve certain
problems is really quite inadequate.
another thing is that the purpose of
the different constituent pieces of
evidence that you might assemble in a
collection could be quite different and
have very different assumptions.
You don't see this when you're only
doing kind of I it's it's dismissive
for me to say Mickey Mouse
demonstrations, but when you're doing
demonstrations are really quite
simplistic and you're using one
credential and you're saying I can
either show you all of my driver's
license or part of it, you don't realize
this, but as soon as you start
assembling
Evidence to solve a real world
problem, you find that the different
kinds of evidence that you're grouping
together introduce some interesting
complexity. So in this particular slide,
I'm imagining what's the evidence that a
loan officer has to assemble to get you
qualified for a mortgage. Okay? And I
just grouped I just profiled four
different kinds. So one piece of
evidence that a loan officer has to
assemble is your last three payubs.
Right? Now, how those last three pay
stubs are stubs are verified is pretty
different from some of the other things
up here. And how long those payubs can
be useful is different from some of the
other things up here and so forth. So,
that's the last three payubs. And the
purpose of putting it together in this
collection is you know, you're trying
to prove that the person has a certain
kind of income. And that means my red
text there. These have to be three
consecutive payubs and they have to be
recent and you know all these other
rules apply to that right then how about
proof of employment that's a whole
different kind of evidence
and proof of employment is probably you
want quite recent proof of
employment maybe a different recency
standard than you have to meet with the
pay stubs
and the kind of credential you're
using to prove this is quite different
as well and it has a different issuer,
right?
How about the credit report? Yet
another issuer,
yet another standard, yet another
governance so forth. So if you're really
trying to solve a serious use case
with rich evidence,
what you have to model about that
evidence and prove about that
evidence to achieve what Sam said years
ago about, you know, a verifiable data
graph is really quite sophisticated.
It's it's not as simple as, oh, show
somebody a credential and you're done.
You also kind of need to know what's
the purpose of the collection of the
evidence you're putting together. You're
not just stuffing evidence in a drawer
somewhere so you can call upon it. In
the case of the loan, going back to
that, all of these pieces of evidence
that I was talking about are going
to be evaluated at funding.
That's the time of the
evaluation or the verification. Now,
actually, in the case of a mortgage,
they're pre-evaluated once or twice
before that and re-evaluated at funding.
After funding, they don't get evaluated
anymore. So, you have to kind of know
when you're building up a collection of
evidence what you're building it up for
and when you plan to have it be
verified.
Ideally, you want to be able to verify
it forever, but in the context of the
event that was important. So,
you're never going to ask the question,
would I give somebody this loan today, a
year after they got their mortgage, but
you might go back a year after they got
their mortgage, and say, were they
qualified for this loan when they got
it, which is a different question.
Okay.
So as we wrestled with issues like
this, and I used the mortgage example
here just so that you wouldn't think I'm
only thinking about telco, but you know,
again, it was telco that was forcing me
to think about this. People were asking,
well, how can I prove and then fill in
the blank with a bunch of telco related
questions and I was grappling with all
of these issues. And this is where I
kind of ended up. And I feel like I
kind of came back to, oh, KERI has a
superpower that I wasn't giving enough
credit to before.
So first of all, we started
calling this construct of a bunch of
evidence that you've assembled a
dossier, for lack of a better word, seem
to resonate with people. I could have
called it a file, but that's so generic
that I just picked dossier.
You notice that I'm I'm using these
icons here to represent the fact that
it's a collection of different evidence
types
and you have some kind of a process
that feeds all this evidence in
and then you go through this curation
process.
You basically get the evidence to the
point where you like it. This is like
going to the loan officer and
saying, "Okay, I've got all my documents
in. Now you can evaluate and decide
whether to give me a loan." Right?
Now you actually might have more than
now you actually might have more than
one of those points. You might evaluate
it one time or seven times. Or you
could evaluate it for a very long time
to come. But you need to know what your
plans are about that. And
the idea here is that this dossier is
intended to be shown to somebody but not
presented in the sense of a
verifiable presentation,
right? It's you don't have to prove
that you are the issue of everything in
the dossier.
I mean let's say it's an
investigative journalism dossier.
you're not proving, you know,
entitlements with this thing and you
don't but you have to prove that all
of these interviews that happened with
certain sources really took place or
whatever. So, it's not the simple model
that you get with verifiable credentials
where you're saying here's the thing and
I'm proving it for myself on behalf of
myself and I'm entitled to something.
Okay.
Once you have a dossier, this is this
is the other thing that I became very
comfortable with in the telco context.
The world's telco systems are built
to move very small amounts of
metadata.
So let's take the case of SMS. When you
send an SMS message, in theory, you're
sending 140 characters or less.
Nowadays, phones will send stuff over
RCS instead of SMS. And so you can
exceed that limit. But the original S
SNPP protocol wanted to move 140
character or less things. And so now
imagine that you were trying to move the
equivalent of let's say a verifiable
credential or even an ACDC in the
headers of that.
You have headers that are like five
times as big as the message itself.
That's not very effective.
So what we can do though is we can
derive and this is part of car's
superpower. We can derive from a
dossier. If it's really a verifiable
data graph, that means it has a set,
right?
Which means I can just send the SAID in
this really light form and somebody on
the other side who understands that it's
a set can say, "Oh, I bet there's a
whole bunch of data behind that." And go
fetch it and it works.
And we can make that a little bit more
convenient by turning the set into a
newbie.
So basically now I can take something
and here I wrote token. This is a word
that I don't like a lot. I kind of
roll my eyes when people talk about
security and tokens. But in some
contexts that's the way security is
enforced. So in the in the case of
voice calls for example, every VOIPE
system in the world carries a JWT
With every well it can it's built to
KERI a JWT with every SIP invite. So
when you pull out your phone and you
dial a phone number and you hit the
dial button, your phone is causing a SIP
invite, which is a small message to
flow over the world, the
internet. And typically it uses
the real internet for parts of the
transmission and then it flows over
specialized telco circuits for other
parts of the conversation. But anyway,
somehow your SIP invite ends up on the
other side and that's when the phone
starts ringing is because the SIP invite
arrived at the other location.
That SIP invite looks very much like an
HTTP request and it has headers. The SIP
protocol and the HTTP protocol are
kissing cousins. They look so similar.
They even to the point where 400 range
errors in SIP are 400 range errors in
HTTP and everything
intentionally.
Yeah, they very deliberately copied
HTTP when they built SIP. So all that
you're doing really with that
infrastructure if you want to decorate
Your call with evidence is you're
putting a header
And think of it like an HTTP header.
It's almost identical. It says identity
colon space and then a bunch of stuff
that's B 64 encoded. And that B 64
encoding is
that B 64 encoding is the JWT that
I'm talking about.
And that JWT can have a field in it, a
claim that is the URL to your evidence.
That's basically all we're doing.
But this same technique can be applied
well outside of telco.
And that's why I'm interested in this.
So you can derive any number of tokens
that keep referring back to the same
piece of evidence. And that's what we're
doing over and over again when you make
phone calls. If you're Microsoft and
you're making outbound calls,
every outbound call that you make
carries a hyperlink back to the same
evidence, but a new signature, right?
There's a new signature on the DWT,
but the evidence behind it, the stable
evidence doesn't change.
So what does a dossier actually
look like? In for those of you who
are ACDC people this is a
trivially simplified version of an
ACDC, I have JSON and in it I have
a field called A and a field called E.
You know what those mean, attributes and
edges. All that a dossier is really
is a particular kind of ACDC or maybe I
should say a flavor of ACDC
where the A fields are used to KERI
curation metadata like who built and
assembled this thing when was it
assembled under what governance rules
was it assembled what are the
assumptions about how it's going to be
used that kind of stuff but none of the
credential content
is in the A field.
All of the credentials are then in
edges.
So, you're just saying, okay, I
assembled, you know, I'm applying for a
loan. Here's my mortgage
qualification packet. That's all up
here. And then every individual piece of
evidence that I submitted is down in the
edges.
The edges just point to another ACDC.
That's right. The edges just point to
another ACDC.
And this is where we get verifiable data
graphs. Yeah. So
now there's a lot of different kinds of
evidence that you might want to put in a
verifiable data graph. The obvious
one is credentials. All of us think
about credentials a lot. But in fact,
the more I have worked on this, the more
I think these other ones on the left
side of this slide are maybe more
compelling in some ways. I want to put
A signed PDF in my evidence. I want
to put an MP3 file in my evidence
because I'm a journalist and I
interviewed somebody. I want to put
a movie in there because I captured some
video. I want to put an AutoCAD
drawing in there. I mean anything you
can imagine we can embed
In an ACDC simply by using the
attachment mechanism
and that's quite important. Some of
these might be so big that we don't
actually want to put them in an ACDC.
We just want to put a hash. So like a
genome, your full DNA. I don't think
you'd want to put a 40 gigabyte genome
inside of an ACDC, but you could
certainly put a hash of your 40 gigabyte
genome inside the ACDC along with a URL
of where to find it or something like
that.
Anyway, so these two techniques,
embedding and wrapping are what I'm
contrasting on this slide. The idea with
embedding is you have data that's not
credential oriented, but it's still data
that's important.
Scientific readings you know, all
these other examples I went through. So,
you want your assembly of evidence to
reference it.
Let's suppose you're an NTSB crash
scene investigator and a plane crashed
and now you want to you're trying to
take photographs of all these different
parts of the plane and how the wreckage
was spread out and all this other stuff.
you would be, you know, embedding JPEGs
or hashes of JPEGs in your dossier when
you're filing your accident report.
Wrapping is relevant when the thing
that you want to put in your verifiable
data graph is another form of verifiable
data, but it's what I would call foreign
to the ACDC world. So if you have an
X509 certificate and you want to put it
in your verifiable data graph or if you
have a W3C verifiable credential and you
want to put it in your data graph, you
can do that. The tech now you can do it
by doing an embedding but I don't think
that's a good idea and I'll explain why
in a second. So what I would recommend
is this wrapping. What you're
essentially doing is you're verifying
the evidence with its native stack
and then you're issuing a new ACDC that
says on such and such a date I so and so
verified this credential and it was
legit on that date and you're making an
explicit claim one way or the other
about whether you take any
responsibility for revocation status.
You can say, "I explicitly disclaim any
responsibility for telling you if you
know in the ACDC land, I'm not going to
reflect the revocation status. So all
I'm telling you is it was valid on this
date." The end. Or you could say, "No,
I'm a really super fancy service and
this kind of evidence is really
important and I will just, you know, I
within one day of latency, I'll tell you
if the other thing gets revoked, I'll
revoke the ACDC wrapper." That's
kind of up to the person, but the
wrapping is the name of the technique
that I'm talking about. And I could
imagine doing this because it builds a
very nice bridge. You can stick an ISO
mobile driver's license in this. You can
stick a verifiable credential W3C1
generation 1 or generation 2. You can
stick in a nonredit presentation in
that, whatever you want.
Okay.
So I anticipated that at this
conference there might be some people
here who know a lot more about
verifiable presentations than I do and
that they might be asking, well, isn't
this the same thing as a verifiable
presentation
In
VC land?
And the answer is it does have some
similarities. That top line of this
table, both of these are cryptogra
cryptographically verifiable containers
of evidence.
But there are some profound differences
too. And these differences lead to a
very different set of addressable use
cases.
So without belaboring the point too
much, I'll simply say that
the life cycle is really
crucial here. A verifiable presentation
is intended to be verified when it's
generated and then it's thrown away.
It's ephemeral.
A dossier is not right. You don't throw
it away. Yes, you make a decision about
whether to fund the loan for the
mortgage on a particular date, but I
guarantee every one of you that has a
mortgage your loan officer has a
file somewhere in their back room or
whatever that has all the data that you
ever submitted and they can look it up
whenever they want because that's
important data to keep on file.
And the same thing would be true if
we're talking about investigative
journalism. If we're talking about crash
scene investigations or if we're talking
in my case about the reputation of
Microsoft and proof that it can use the
world's telco infrastructure in a
particular way, it needs to be on file
and kept.
the other line that I want to just call
out here is the bottom one.
Really the meaning of these is a little
bit different.
In the case of a dossier, what you're
saying as the person who assembles
the dossier is here's a bunch of data
that I put together that I'm signing
over it, but I'm not necessarily
asserting that everything in this data
is something I believe. Like if I'm an
investigative journalist, I could well
have interviewed a bunch of people who
lied to me on camera or while I
was taking notes. And I want to document
that they lied to me. And I'm not
necessarily asserting that they told me
the truth just because I signed over it.
I'm asserting when I sign that I was
the collector of this body of
evidence and collectively it represents
some purpose that's described in the
metadata about that dossier.
Right? So maybe I'm assembling all of
the evidence from somebody who lied
to me because I want to, you know, take
him to court later. So it could be
full of lies. Everything that I put in
the dossier on purpose.
The again the metadata of the dossier
tells you the purpose. Whereas a
verifiable presentation is always about
proving enough to get me the
entitlement.
Okay.
I feel like I'm just talking and
talking. Everybody's listening quietly.
I want to shake the room up and do
something, but I don't know what to do.
Anybody have any questions? Richard,
when we talk about a verifiable
presentation, the protocol includes the
ability to make claims across the
different credentials ination.
Does the dossier I don't know if it's
going to be a protocol. We haven't got
to that part of the conversation, but
does it include the ability to say this
name on this one is supposed to
reference name on that one?
But it doesn't do that because of
the dossier. It does that because that's
a native feature of ACDC's. When you
declare an edge in an ACDC, you can say
this edge must be related to that edge
in the following way. There's an
operator that you can declare the
dossier spec by the way to kind of
prefigure your question about protocols.
A dossier is not really a protocol, but
it is a data format. It's a
specialized form of ACDC and there's
enough kind of extra rules that we
want to attach to a dossier I think that
It needs a spec. So we're writing
a spec about it and the spec right now
introduces a couple of new operators
to enrich what edges can say about
one another and things like that. Sam, I
saw your hand go up.
Oh, Phil.
Yeah, two questions. This is one I think
is an obvious yes, but can a dossier
point to another dossier?
Yeah, for sure.
And then I thought the use of an OOBI in
the SIP header was an elegant way to
AID itself. Have we considered doing
that in edges either in the dossier or
in the ACDC's?
I have not thought about that.
but as soon as you said it, I was
But as soon as you said it, I was
like, wow, why didn't I think of that?
That's a really great idea. I love that.
What was your idea first?
Edges are actually a block. You can
add as many properties in an edge as you
want. So it's just a matter of saying
you're going to add an UI to an edge.
Okay.
Cool.
This is an example of the kind of thing
that the dossier spec needs to say is
here's a really useful way to, you know,
make this more powerful. Yeah.
since your voice is quiet, why don't you
use the
Anyway,
no, but he's only recording his
thing.
Yeah, for the camera.
The gent speaking to his name.
Yeah, I got
I got to talk. I'll be No, don't pick up
my sound.
Okay, pick me up.
It wasn't that I said verifiable data
it wasn't that I said verifiable data
graph
20 years ago or 20 2020 or whatever it
was just came out of nowhere. It is
comes out of the theory of automated
reasoning. Automated reasoning you build
verifiable data graphs with aggregation
operators. The only difference is
that you're trying to do often live
control of something where you're saying
I've got 50 sensors, I've got, you know,
data process, I got database, I got a
map, I got all of this stuff and I have
to make a live decision with the best
available data to me at the time that I
do it. And all the data is aggregated
differently. So you have a whole family
of aggregation operators and you just
have connections between all of your
sensors and you know sensors
aggregate to aggregate and
then and it just looks like this big
complex graph and all I had to do was
say well you know if I want to make a
trust decision that's no different than
any other automated reasoning. So we
should be able to map ACDC's directly to
how you actually do the processing.
You shouldn't be building some
artificial thing that is not that is
divorced from the actual way you make
you make decisions. And so ACTC's
model how you actually make
automated decisions.
And that resonates for me because of
that, you know, earlier slide that I was
showing about how to make a decision for
a mortgage. You're you're actually this
is the real way that the real world
works, right? You're assembling a bunch
of evidence and evaluating it and Yeah.
Go ahead. So very different approach to
all of this. But from the legal
standpoint, we're now starting to move
to modeling where the fair
information practices are actually going
to be mandated. Your original
definitions
solved a number of problems because the
the data collected is the minimal
data necessary to fulfill the purpose.
it is a specific purpose that even
though the information may be kept in
the dossier, it isn't ending up in some
giant data lake that then can be used
for other purposes later on. And I
think the other piece of this
that's really elegant is that if you
have let's say in government social
programs that require three or four
agencies to interact right now they
claim they need a data lake.
So th this allows you to decentralize
that none of them is in effect the
steward. they are just the steward of
the particular piece of it that they
need to integrate for the programmatic
utilization.
I love it. And this actually segus
directly to what I was going to say
next. Traditional verifiable
credentials and in fact most ACDC use
cases that we think about assume a
single issuer,
right? But one of the things we're
introducing in the dossier spec is the
idea of joint issuance.
And the idea here is not that you
have joint issuers all using a single
multi-IG even. You just have joint
issuers. They're all individual parties
representing themselves with different
AIDs.
But in the ACDC, in the dossier,
you can say this dossier takes effect as
soon as I have five of the following 18
people who've signed.
And it's just a completely asynchronous
thing. And I put a picture of the
signing of the Declaration of
Independence up here because you had a
bunch of people in a room. But actually,
in some ways, that picture is bad
because it suggests everybody got
together right at the same time. In
fact, what we're suggesting here is you
don't have to do that.
Right. You can have one party sign and
then a week later in a different place
under different circumstances you can
have another party sign and another
party and so forth. Sam,
I just want to clarify you're using sign
as a euphemism for actually anchoring in
or anchoring into the registry that is
of stuff like that but it's the same
thing. you're you're anchoring the same
thing with the different AID, but it but
everything else is the same. And so it's
a joint issue because everybody issued
the same facts, but
yes.
So in order to verify, we would need
The verifier to do a little bit of
work that it doesn't currently do,
right? It's going to have to go look up
signatures in five different places or
something. Unless this bottom line an
optional finalizer can say, "Look, I've
already done all of that work. Here's a
a thing in my KEL that just lists
everybody that already signed and you
can go verify it." So, that would
be a nice thing. But I really like this
model. I think that joint issuance is
going to create a lot of useful
flexibility for us. You can also have
models, by the way, that aren't M ofN
models. You can just say this is a
petition and as soon as we get a
thousand signatures on it, whatever.
There's no N in it, right? It's just
this is the threshold is M, you know. So
anyway, there's some really neat things
about that and I can see how there's
certain legal behaviors that
this facilitates very nicely.
Now I wanted to say something else.
This is another way that some of the
superpowers of ACDC's come into play
in the telco use case that I had. I had
a case where I wanted parties all along
a chain to be able to verify but the
amount of data that they needed to see
varied.
Okay. A regulator needs to see more
and an intermediary on a transmission
chain needs to see less.
And the beauty of it is I can have a
dossier that is sparse for one
audience and full for another and it's
the same dossier and they can both refer
to it the same way
which means you have the option of
assembling this dossier but having many
different variations on the verifiable
data graph that expose lots or little
amounts of what's needed.
So in telco when you have the rule
about lawful intercept for example law
enforcement agencies require that
they be able to see certain things about
Your communications. Anywhere
where there's a jurisdiction like that I
can solve that problem with a nice rich
dossier view and anywhere where I can
show less I will do it.
So are you using selective disclosure to
mean the category of controlled
disclosure or just the specifically
selective disclosure as opposed to any
of the other variations of disclosure?
Well, the original title of this slide
When I wrote it a month ago, it said
graduated disclosure.
And then I thought, oh, I could play
around with this. Oh, I could stick it,
you know, I could take contractually
protected disclosure. There's all these
variations on it. I don't know which
is the exact frame that you want to
use in a particular context. The point
though is that I can suppress data or I
can show data using variations
that all have the same root hash and
I don't know what you would call that
control this thing is called partial
disclosure but essentially it is
creating a nonbinary Merkle tree of the
data so that the fully compact is
essentially the root and then he's just
he's just tracing it out, but the hashes
along the way are generated. So, so you
can do a proof of conclusion the same
way you would a mer tree just by just by
walking down and then expanding it
at that point saying, "Oh, here's what
it is." So, so it's a non-binary
hash graph that you can do some sort of
booster.
So, if I had to use a different
word, I'd call it contextual display.
Okay.
That's a good one.
Okay. I'm basically done with my
presentation at this point. This is
this is where you can get more
information. The spec is currently at
version 0.6.
We'd love to have people contribute or
if you don't feel like contributing
because you're way too busy like me.
I get it. But at least keep track of it.
I'd love to have some people just
show up and fix a typo so that I can at
least put more names on the spec besides
me.