Daniel, you will introduce yourself?
– Sure.
So I'm Daniel Hardman and I'm the
CTO of company called Provenant.
You've heard a couple of
references to work that we're doing in
telco. And I'm here to explain a little
bit more about that.
all of us have been impacted by scamming
in telco. Usually a day doesn't go
by that I don't get some kind of a
message. This morning it was
somebody running for Congress in some
state that I've never lived in telling
me how important it was that I donate $3
to his campaign. But all of us get these
kinds of things. And many of us who
work in cyber security sensitive areas
are pretty well aware of how scammy
and fraudulent a lot of it is.
Even people who don't know anything
about tech know that this is scammy and
and full of fraud to the point where
this is the answer they're coming up
with. Just don't answer your phone,
right? Or just stop sending texts.
That's actually a pretty bad indictment
of a technical infrastructure when
the best advice we can give is just stop
using it.
But that's kind of the state of affairs
right now. And that constitutes an
existential threat for an entire
market vertical.
There are billion-dollar companies
that make their money off of phone
calls
or make their money off of texting.
And so if you have entire influential
voices, segments in an industry that are
saying just stop using that tech
entirely, there's panic going on.
Microsoft is an interesting example
of this and so I'm going to use them
because I know some details about their
world. One of the common scams is
maybe you've had a grandparent who says,
"Oh, I got a call from Microsoft tech
support."
The reason that scam is
dangerous is because Microsoft does have
a tech support staff and they do
sometimes call people. They don't
spontaneously call people, which is the
way the scam usually works. But if a
person calls Microsoft tech support and
they get disconnected,
Or if they call and they have the
end of the current conversation, but
there needs to be follow-up, Microsoft
does call people.
The problem is people don't want to
answer.
And that's a serious pain point for
Microsoft.
And regulators are getting involved
in this now because Microsoft has
another characteristic that's kind of
complicated that would be true of
anybody who's a giant global
conglomerate, which is they put their
people in the most strategic places they
can for cost reasons and so forth. So
particular case in point in the UK
Microsoft has plenty of customers
that they interact with but Microsoft
doesn't put their call center staff in
the UK. They put their call center staff
in Bulgaria or some other lowcost
center that can you know make a cheap
call into the UK. But Offcom, which is
the equivalent of the FCC in the UK
has some problems with that because they
don't want a phone call to be
claiming that it's coming from the UK
and from Microsoft when it's coming
from Bulgaria.
And so they have said, you may not
attribute this phone call to a UK
number unless you can prove it.
You have to prove that it's really
coming from Microsoft
and this is creating a lot of pain for
Microsoft.
So what Microsoft wants is a
transformation of the customer
experience from the phone on the left to
the phone on the right. They'd like it
to be the case that when the phone
rings, it shows the Microsoft logo. It
shows the Microsoft name
and it shows why they're calling. Oh,
they're calling because they're customer
support representative and they want to
be able to prove it.
It's not hard to make a phone show
logos.
What's hard is to be able to prove why
you're showing the logo.
And this is the requirement that
Microsoft has.
So,
So, what I'm here to talk about
what I'm here to talk about
is I'm just going to let this narrator
take over for a minute and we'll watch
this demo. This was presented at
Mobile World Congress about a month
ago,
a three person consultancy who wish to
make outbound calls to their customers.
We then move to a larger organization
Microsoft. Their outbound contact
centers need to be able to make calls to
customers, but increasingly find that
their calls are impacted by incountry
regulation, get spamm or simply not
answered because customers do not know
it's Microsoft calling.
What you will see looks like a branded
call. However, it is a little bit
different. With OBC, the information
displayed on the handset is based on a
set of credentials which prove certain
things about the origin of the call.
They prove that Microsoft has the right
to the telephone number that is being
displayed, that it is Microsoft
Corporation that is calling you, linked
back to the Axel legal entity
responsible for the call using a
globally unique legal identifier, and
that they have the right to use the
brand that is being displayed to you.
These credentials have all been issued
to Microsoft and are in their control.
Microsoft could use these three
credentials to originate calls
themselves, but there is a fourth
credential which allows Microsoft to
delegate the right to sign on their
behalf to another platform. For the
project, we've worked with Info Bit,
Twilio, and Vonnage as platforms that
could be used to sign traffic on behalf
of an enterprise and they do not wish to
make their own calls.
The call you see will leave the platform
onto a network where it will be verified
by a transit operator before it has
arrived. handset and the outcome of the
verification is displayed. Let's go and
make a call. For this example, we're
going to make a call from Info BIP.
We are logged in as Microsoft and we'll
send a call from this US telephone
number which has been allocated to them.
We will call this Spanish number which
is a prepaid SIM we bought in Spain for
the demonstration and is in the handset
which is mirrored to the right. Let's go
ahead and make a call.
You can see here the name, telephone
number and brand along with a verified
tick are displayed.
These are displayed based on a
successful verification of the evidence
provided in the communication.
What we'll do next is have a look at the
governance model that underpins this
evidence.
One of the biggest challenges with
global verifiable communications is
ensuring there is thorough and
consistent vetting of original parties
that can work in many different
circumstances.
OBC has rich governance model and
provable chain of evidence to support
this. It starts with a local governance
authority that sets the vetting
standards for OBC.
We next have policy administrators who
appointed by the government's authority
to apply these vetting standards in a
given jurisdiction. It's important as
there are many differences of
regulations and vetting processes in
different countries. They're responsible
for certifying vetting agents to be able
to vet in these jurisdictions for
different communications channels.
Once credentials been issued to betting
agents, they're able to bet enterprises
in specific regions and for specific
communications channels. In the trial,
we've had brand numerical and easing
enterprises.
The vetting agents verify enterprises to
prove rights to telephone numbers, that
they are the legal entity they say they
are, and that they have the rights to
use the brand, and then issue the
enterprises with appropriate
credentials. This process can support
support both small businesses and large
corporations.
It's important to note that these
credentials are chained all the way back
to the governance authority providing a
provable chain of trust. It is also
means that it's possible for credentials
to be revoked at any point in the chain.
So if for example a vtor does not follow
the rules and bets bad actors, it's
possible for a policy administrator to
revoke their credential and have a
cascade impact on the credential set
issue.
The credentials are held in wallets by
enterprises to whom they have been
issued. While the focus of the
demonstration has been on voice, these
credentials can also prove other
communication channels such as RCS, SMS
or APIs. The final credential which can
be created if needed is a delegated sign
credential which we discussed earlier.
What we'll look at now is how the
evidence looks for a real call.
First, we're going to make another call,
but this time from another one. One of
the credentials has been removed by
Microsoft.
As you can see, in this instance, the
call fails. This is because the transit
operator verifying the network attempted
to verify the call and found that one of
the credentials had been revoked and
therefore rejected the call.
We will now go and look at the evidence
detail for this call.
We can see the call here. Evidence
detail records refer back to the
evidence and provide a permanent record
of the evidence accompanying the call.
We can see the three credentials here.
The identity credential, the TN
credential, and the brand credential.
And we can see here that the TN
credential has been revoked.
We can also look into the evidence in
more detail and see who has vetted
Microsoft. In this case, it was Eegis
and even how they gained their authority
to be a veter. We can also then see the
policy administrator and the
government's authority for the trial.
These were just placeholders.
We'll now move on to look at the actual
call flow for the call that you've
seen.
We started with a set of credentials
that have been issued to the enterprise
and delegated to an originator so they
can make calls on their behalf.
When the call is made, the originator
calls out to a signing service from
Provenant, the technology provider for
this project. The service returns a
compact passport, a stir passport and
also replicates this passport from out
of bank hash. The passport is not a
shaken passport but a verifiable voice
protocol passport.
Once signed, the originating party sends
the phone onto the PSTN.
Here it is received by transit oper
operator Wrestle
and uses a verification service to
verify the pool. Verification can happen
anywhere in the call flow. The RB
scenario verification takes place in the
terminating network. In the case of the
good call, wave press will pass this
call to the terminating operator. And in
the case of a bad call, Wress rejected
the call.
When the call arrives on the handset, it
does a look up to an out ofbound
passport cache. If a passport is found,
a verification again takes place and if
successful, the result is returned to
the handset. The outcome of the
verification is then displayed as the
phone rings.
In our trial, we relied on verification
on the handset using a modified version
of the standard Android dialer provided
by Google for this project and a lookup
was to a public outbound service. In an
ideal scenario, the verification would
take place in the terminating operator's
network with the cryptographic evidence
being passed directly to the handset or
to the antibb service to be deployed in
the operator's network.
This concludes the demonstration.
This project has been supported by the
GSMA Foundry and has had participation
from the following companies. If you
would like to find out more, please
follow the QR code.
Okay. So there was a lot of detail
in that and I'm going to try to pull out
of what you saw a few points here.
The first one in the view that you
saw that was like this anybody who
has seen that telephone call transit
their network has the ability to prove
certain things about it. This will
satisfy a regulator.
It will satisfy an IT team that's
worried about regulatory compliance.
It will satisfy an end user and all of
those stakeholders matter. just
making the end user comfortable isn't
the only goal here. We had to make
Offcom comfortable.
And so be being able to drill in and
say for this call, what are the
credentials that were available and what
can I know about the party that made the
call at that time and I need to be able
to have real time reaction to
revocation.
if Microsoft is doing something funny
and a regulator says don't let that kind
of call through be anymore and we
revoke one of the credentials the
system has to react in real time to
that. So that's one of the things I
wanted to call out.
Oh did I just oh I guess I pushed a turn
oh did I just oh I guess I pushed a turn
off the button. Okay. Being able to
drill in deeper so it's not just a
badge but you can you drill into the
individual pieces of evidence and look
at their status and you can do this
historically too. So at the time the
call is made you can look at it but you
can also go back a week or a year
later on a particular call and say what
was the state of the credentials at this
time? what was a justified conclusion
based on what the evidence looked like
then.
Now Sam's talked about tipping point.
I really hope that the telco thing is a
tipping point. You know it's it ain't
over till it's over but we have made a
lot of progress here. So I want to just
highlight a few of the things that were
kind of touched on briefly. VVP is an
acronym. It stands for verifiable voice
protocol. That's an IETF draft spec
right now. For those of you who
don't work in telco, I've gone through
this learning curve recently. Stir
is a technology that is used in VoIP.
Voice over IP
and basically a stir passport is a
JWT.
So many of you know what a JWT is
and how it works. So a JWT carries a
small amount of information and the
world's VOIPE systems already know how
to KERI these JWTs.
What VVP does is it says we're going to
put a little bit of extra information in
that JWT. And I'm going to show you how
little I really mean when I say a little
bit. It's actually remarkable how rich
we can make this with a very tiny
addition. And because the world systems
already know how to KERI this
information, we don't have to modify the
infrastructure. In the narrator in that
video mentioned just in passing that we
were calling a Spanish SIM card that
we had bought off the street, literally
we flew into Spain for this conference,
which was a month ago in Barcelona. We
flew in, we walked into a shop on the
street, a random one, and we bought a
SIM card and stuck it in, and we got a
call to work. And that's important
because we're not talking about
proposing to the world that they go
deploy a whole bunch of new
infrastructure.
The networks that carried this call
with this information had no notice that
we were doing this. We just did it and
it worked. So, that's really important
to the adoption story.
This is the events that are
listed here are kind of in
chronological order.
The GSMA is the world's basically
the arbiter of mobile technology in the
world. And so this is important that
they convened this project
and those names that are listed there
are all big names. They all
participated in one degree or another.
Google was the handset manufacturer
who got their dialer modified fastest
and that's why we used the Google
handset to do the demos. But Apple
We had good conversations with them.
Samsung was there, Cisco was there.
All of these companies participating
all of these companies participating
together and Microsoft is going to
production in right now as we speak
in various parts of the world. It's
not a single big bang. It's a series of
going to production things in different
jurisdictions
and with different kinds of evidence. In
the UK, they don't need the branded
calling right now. They just need the
name Microsoft to appear. So, they don't
care about the logos. They're going
live in the UK first because they have
to satisfy offcom in the UK. Then
they're going to other places. So
anyway, there's some real live in
production stuff by companies that you
know that are doing this and the GSMA
completed this OBVC project in March,
just a month ago. So now they've
announced that they're going to have
some follow-on projects. One of them
is going to focus on governance.
And this gets to the whole LEI and
vLEI topic.
During the proof of concept
stuff that we did, we were using an LEI
to identify the companies and everybody
agreed that was vital.
And so now they're looking to extend
that and fit into the vLEI family.
That's part of the follow-on governance
work.
The other thing is that they explicitly
want to make this technology usable in
multiple channels. So the channel
that we focused on in this ex first
experience was voice calls. But they
Care very much since their mobile
the world's mobile technology
providers. They care about texting
just as much as they care about phone
calls. They care about rich chat and how
iMessage works and bunch of things like
that. And so when I say multi-channel,
that's what I'm talking about. Now, I
never explained the acronym OVC. So, let
me just spend a minute. OBVC originally
meant open verifiable calling.
But during this foundry project, people
said, "Well, wait a minute. There's no
reason why we couldn't take this
evidence that we've built into these
other channels." Right? So OBC has now
become in the minds and in the
communications that go on in GSMA
channels like their mailing list and the
meetings that they have. They've started
calling it open verifiable communication
and that's what OBVC now means with
this check mark. They're they're
explicitly pursuing communication as a
general goal, not just calling. So I
have a little bit more information about
that in a second.
This you know Sam made a point in his
presentation that we don't want to
have a single vendor solution.
Provenant was kind of the enabler of
this whole thing. And of course
proven is a for-profit company and we
hope we can sell lots of people on what
we've built. But it's important for it
to be open and we believe in that. And
So here's some kind of proof
points about how open verifiable
calling and the verifiable voice posture
Ver verifiable voice protocol work
and thank you to this is a shout out
to the Trust over IP folks who've let us
Build a dossier specification at
trustover IP and I'm going to talk about
what a dossier is in just a minute. It's
it's important to this whole concept and
Also to the folks over at IETF that
we're working with.
Okay. Let me talk a little bit since
this is a more geeky audience. It's not
just pure business people. I want to
talk about what's going on underneath
here.
When we looked at what we had to
build, these are the kinds of
requirements that we felt we were
getting from the business side
and the regulatory side. And I'm not
going to read all of them out loud, but
I hope when you look at that you say,
"Well, that's a pretty ambitious list
because it felt kind of overwhelming to
us." building half of those would be
pretty easy, but when you start having
to build all of those things in or
address all those requirements, as Sam
said, you get into a very hard trade
space where you're making trade-offs and
some of them are hard. And we didn't
want to trade away any of these
requirements. And because we're here at
a KERI conference, I will just say I
don't believe we could have built this
with any other technology. there were a
number of reasons why you end up at a
dead end if you try to solve it any
other way.
So
without belaboring that, let me say also
it was important to identify some things
we did not have to do. And this is
important because there are calling
solutions that deliver significant
value
that have some of these requirements and
we were not asked to address some of
these. The most interesting one I'll
just mention the bottom one here.
Somebody said, "Oh, well, this is all
well and good, but how do I know that an
AI is not, you know, sending me words
and pretending that it's coming from
another person?" And the answer is we're
not trying to solve that problem.
The reason we're not trying to solve
that problem is because for us, the
issue is about accountability.
If Microsoft connects to you, then
it's on Microsoft if they once they're
connected with you and you know you're
really dealing with Microsoft who made
the call. If Microsoft then sticks an AI
on the call, that's their problem and
your problem, but it's not the problem
of the technology that connected you and
proved that Microsoft was accountable in
the first place. So, it's about
accountability
Not about whether it's human or not.
However, however, we could certainly
prove that the party who dialed you was
an actual human being versus an AI if we
needed to. And I'll I'll show you where
that fits if that became
interesting.
So, these are some of the things that
were the places where maybe the
trade-offs manifest and it would be
hard to address some of these
requirements.
The top one is the maybe the biggest.
Okay, how do you do all of this? but you
do it with a commodity SIM card over
networks that haven't been modified. If
you can do that, that's a big deal.
Anyway, there another one, the third one
there, I just want to mention, it's
possible to prove things between a
caller and a colleague using classic
The classic u trust triangle that
we've talked about for years using
verifiable credentials.
However,
In that kind of a model, the parties
have to know who they're talking to
in a sense before you can prove
because you have to
yeah basically you have to have a
connection with the other party in
some kind of an outofband way before you
can then prove with your credentials.
And the specific characteristic we
needed for this solution
was that a stranger could call you. You
haven't had any prior knowledge about
who these parties might be that are
reaching out to you.
Okay.
What does this look like? If I gave you
what does this look like? If I gave you a
really high-level architecture diagram, it
a really high-level architecture diagram,
it might look like this. You have a party
might look like this. You have a party
like Acme Corporation that wants to make
a call. sometime near when the call
originates like right at the same time
or within milliseconds afterwards if
they're putting traffic on a network and
they're were you using like a
cloud provider or whatever as the call
originates a signing event occurs the
signing that we're talking about is a
signing of the JWT
and the JWT is this thing that's called
a passport That term passport is a term
of art in the IETF specification
for these JWTs.
So this passport contains
and the blue with the underscore
here is supposed to suggest this to you.
It contains a hyperlink
to what we're calling a dossier.
The dossier is the collection of rich
evidence.
So all we're adding to this passport
that it didn't have before is a field
that has a hyperlink in it.
the relationship between the signer of
the passport and the and the passport
itself is crucial and we could talk
about that offline. I probably won't go
into it in my talk that much. Suffice it
to say that you have to prove that the
party signing has some relationship of
delegated authority with the party that
is originating the call. It could be the
one in the same party, but it doesn't
have to be. And that's important because
you have to support things like call
centers
That are other businesses. The call
center is not Microsoft and a regulator
needs to be able to tell those two
parties apart. But you have to be able
to prove that the call center is acting
on Microsoft's behalf. they can't just
assert it.
There's a whole story about how
evidence is built and I'm not going to
go into it in detail, but essentially
you start out with a cryptographic
identifier for the company
identifier for the company and
and
and a control mechanism. Those two
things go to go together. And once you
have those two, then you build an
identity credential. And for those of
you who know how VLES work, this is
straight out of
straight out of Carla's thinking.
It's exactly how VLES are built.
it's exactly how VLES are built.
Basically steps one through four are
basically steps one through four are
the journey of getting a vLEI.
And then you add to that a bunch of
other credentials.
Importantly, the credentials are issued
by different parties.
So you have a collection of issuers.
They all have their own revocation
criteria and their own revocation
SLAs's. So we can't put all of this in a
single credential.
And then you bundle all the
credentials together in a dossier. And
the dossier includes a last thing which
has to be a credential issued by the
actual company that we're talking about
declaring their intentions to make this
kind of traffic flow.
And then you can use it in ongoing
use. Now some of you may be wondering
here we are at a KERI conference can
this technique be used without
ACDCs without KERI no it can't you
can't build this whole solution but you
can interoperate with other kinds of
credentials quite nicely. So if a
company has a credential and the format
of this credential is a format that's
required by the EU to prove something
about the company and they want to use
that to prove one of the logical
propositions in the dossier, you can do
that. You could accept a credential that
is a W3C verifiable credential. You can
accept an SD jot. can accept a signed
PDF if you want as evidence, but you
have to wrap it somehow because unless
you can put it in a verifiable data
graph and you can reason about it
in a particular way, the solution falls
apart. You can't end up generating that
view that I was showing you in the
evidence that has the badges and stuff
like that. So, there's two basic ways
that you can deal with that. You can
either use wrapped mode, which is where
I take a foreign piece of evidence and
put an ACDC around it, and literally
the ACDC has the content of the
other piece of evidence right inside it.
And it's a reissuance essentially.
So, you have an issuer of an ACDC
that's saying, "I looked at this other
piece of evidence and I used its native
technology, whatever it is W3C
verifiable credential stack or
something, and I verified it on date X."
And so now I'm issuing an ACDC that
says on date X, this credential was
verified and it was true. That's wrapped
mode.
And you can see that wrapped mode
has some good things about it. and some
bad things about it. The good things are
that a party on the other end doesn't
have to know about any other stacks
or technology types. It only has to
verify
verify ACDCs.
ACDCs.
But you have a revocation issue. Does
the party who's doing the reissuance
sign up to also track the
revocation?
To be determined, right? The other
one is you can have embedded mode and in
that mode the party that's creating
the ACDC doesn't take a lot of
responsibility. They basically say
here's an ACDC envelope
around data but what it means is up to
you to determine and so you have to have
a stack that can look and understand
this other evidence format and decide
whether it agrees with the guarantees
that it provides. I don't think that
embedded mode is a good idea because it
fragments the verification space.
But anyway, enough about that. I won't
but anyway, enough about that. I won't
go into great detail on this diagram. I
could talk about it for a very long
time, but I'll simply say this. The way
that passports in stir were conceived of
is that a passport was supposed to
include an X5U field that was a
hyperlink to the certificate of the
signer of the passport.
Okay. And when you went and looked up
that signer certificate, you would see
That the certificate included
proof of a cryptographic identity. that
would be their public key and it
included information about the
attributes of this party. So that'd be
like the common name of the company and
their organizational unit or you know
all that other stuff. What we've done is
we've split that apart and said
information about identity and
information about attributes need to be
handled differently because identity can
be permanent.
There's no reason on this model. How
often do you have to replace this
all the stinking time? I don't know
exactly what number you're going to come
up with, but I guarantee it's a number I
don't like. Right? If it's once a month
or once every three months or once a
week,
Shaken in the United States mandated
by the FCC calls for three-month
rotations in their guidance. I think
they enforce a higher number than that,
but okay. Anyway they're only
doing it right now. The certificates
that shake and use are only for big
companies like Twilio and whatever.
They're not for the millions of little
companies around the world. So, they
said, "Well, let's go to let's take this
thing and we'll start using certificates
on all the little companies around the
world." Can you imagine if every little
company around the world has to replace
Proof of who they are? Let's say
there's 30 million businesses in the
United States alone. And so you're
going to be maintaining a fabric of 30
million certificates that rotate once a
month.
It's completely impractical. And so
here, how often do we rotate this?
Zero times. I really love that answer.
You can rotate the keys as often as you
want, but I don't have to replace the
identifier ever.
And I can't tell you how profound the
difference in cost is and the difference
in infrastructure lift when you don't
have to replace anything. It's huge.
Now, we do have to change attributes,
but we only have to change them as often
as the attributes change,
right? If your company doesn't rename
itself, you don't need a new proof of
what its name is. And if it doesn't lose
the ability to use a logo in a
particular jurisdiction, you don't need
to replace that either. So again, the
maintenance is dramatically different.
This is how we it actually looks on the
wire today. On the left is a standard
shaken passport. This is what
actually flows over the wire right now.
And the reason that we could deploy this
with no changes in infrastructure is
because this is how different it looks
over here.
None of the infrastructure cares.
The only real in that I'll highlight
these two lines. So this is the
hyperlink in a traditional shaken
passport that says here's how I can find
the certificate of the party that
signed this.
And here we have a link. This is an OOBI
to a KEL.
Okay. And down here we have an
unsupported assertion from somebody
saying, I think that this is an A-level
call. I believe in this call. Here we
have hyperlink to evidence.
It's really simple.
let's see.
I'm not going to I'm about out of time.
So, I'll just say that Dossias can
prove lots and lots of logical
propositions, not just one.
And the list of things that you can
prove under the previous model had one
bullet on it. You can prove the opinion
of the company that signed the J JWT
about whether it was a good call.
That's not a very long list.
I mentioned this that OVC is coming
to mean something different. There are
active there's active work now going on
on a variation of this for SMS, a
variation of it for rich chat. So
proving who sends you an iMessage or
the equivalent in the message app on
Android and web meetings. Wouldn't you
like it if when you showed up to a Zoom
meeting you actually had proof of who
you were and everybody else did too? And
there are some other transports that I
won't announce today, but there's cool
stuff going on with those two.
So if you want more information, the
spec for the verifiable voice
protocol is at this one and the demo
that I showed you is at that QR code.
You can watch it again. Any questions?
We got time for two questions.
Yeah. You mentioned that you were using
the Google dialer. So, was that
deployed?
So, Google's dialer is it was actually
signed by Google and so forth, but it
it's not in the mainstream distribution.
Google is still debating whether
they want to put it in.
Another question
about the security of the URL that goes
to the dossier. So obviously if it's
wrapped and signed then the URL is safe.
The URL itself is safe but at the
target there that's where something can
change and be malleable. So how are
what's what are you doing to secure the
endpoint where the URL goes?
Well, the URL is an OOBI. So it's it's
not a generic URL, meaning that when
you go there, you must see a signed
sequence of events that proves the
its evolution from its origin
moment, its inception moment. So you
could have somebody who
tries to replace the content at that
location, but if they did, they would
have to come up with content that still
evolved from scratch and was still
related to the identifier in
question, and that would be detected
then by the watcher network and so
forth. So, KERI prevents a bunch of
monkeying with that. And interestingly
enough, this is one of the debates that
I've been having in the stir working
group at IETF because people said, "Oh,
this is a great idea. We'll put a
hyperlink in there. We'll just accept
any hyperlink."
And I said, "No, that's not quite a good
idea." For the very concern that
you're talking about, we'll see if I can
convince them. They might just modify
the spec and say any hyperlink will do.
In which case there
that immediately becomes the
sensitive attack surface.
Exactly.
One more question.
Could you grab the mic?
In your architecture, you showed a
couple of phone home paths. What
are the implications of privacy on that?
So the phone home path is not
a phone home to another party. It's a
phone home to the originating party. So,
Basically the party that made the
call might have somebody call them back,
Or it call their watchers and
witnesses back. But these are
entities that they control and have
chosen. So it's not calling home or
phoning home to a central registry. it's
phoning home to it would be the
equivalent of on the web calling the
name server for Microsoft.com that
Microsoft chose. So you're tracing data
back to a server Microsoft set up and
empowered.
So it doesn't have to be provenant in
every case.
Oh no, no, no, no. Provenant
implemented this system. But the spec
is open and anybody could implement the
system. Yeah, there's no lock in
about that.
Okay, thank you very much once again.