Evan Asawaka ｜ Mobile Wallet ｜ KERI Conference 2026
So we have been developing a web
wallet for KERI essentially just as
you know more wallets more platforms
better.
All right. So initially Sam set out
these goals where we wanted to create a
fully web native wallet because
currently the Locksmith application is a
desktop application.
and so let's see. Core wallet, we wanted
it to run entirely in the browser
with no like server or anything running
KERIpy on the back end. Which,
proved to be a challenge in fact.
So again, we wanted everything to
happen in the browser so you can have
all of your keys locally created and
stored on your device. Don't have to
worry about them being stored on some
server. Then we could just send you
this application and you would get
your in-browser wallet
and we also wanted it to be
persistent because that would be a
little bit useless if it wasn't.
So some challenges running Python in a
WebAssembly was the first big hurdle.
because currently
Python is run on CPython which is a
you know C written interpreter.
The cryptography had to work in the
browser and this basically meant that
KERIpy couldn't drag LMDB into the
web path because LMDB relies on MMAP
which is not supported in
WebAssembly.
And, again, we want this to be
not a one tab, one reload type of
wallet. We want it to actually be like a
production grade wallet that we can
deploy where you can just take the
files, serve them yourself, even if you
wanted to, and be able to have your own
identifiers that you can manage from a
browser and not have to download an
application on specific
architectures. So getting Python into
the browser was a interesting
challenge. We found Piodide which is
essentially the Python interpreter
compiled to WebAssembly which allows it
to run in the browser which
means that you can then run any Python
native packages
and for all the non-Python native
packages that was a medium challenge
And then we have PyScript as like
the browser bridge so you can launch off
web workers in the browser and it
interfaces with like the browser
database so you can have again that
persistent storage
which is exactly what I put on my
slides.
So to do this we had to again go through
the dependencies of KERIpy get them
to work in the browser which started
with pysodium which is
a python wrapper for Libsodium which is
a C library. So I had to take Libsodium
compile it to target WebAssembly and
then I changed some of the code in
Pysodium so that it loaded the packaged
Libsodium that I created, called it pychloride
because it's like you know
sodiumchloride… that was Sam's idea.
I'll give credit where credit due.
Blake3 is written in Rust. I had to compile this
WebAssembly and also in an
attempt to get ready for future proofing
we took this pyoqs which is an open
quantum secure safety library for
key creation and
made it WebAssembly compatible. So that
will be coming in the future hopefully
before quantum computers.
So in KERIpy itself we had to make it
WebAssembly safe which meant creating a
second database backing which used
indexedDB which runs in the browser. We
created webdber instead of lmdber
which means we're no longer relying on
the MMAP LMDB
And we also had to make it so that the
imports don't randomly import lmdb so
that it works in the browser. And again,
this webdber allowed us to create like a
persistent storage in the browser that
can survive when you press reload on
accident and then you lose all your keys
because that would suck. – Can
I ask you can I ask you a question?
So is that
from a technical perspective? Is
there an abstract class for that or is
that not implemented with an
abstract?
– Yeah, we created a base spacer
Or wait not for basers. No,
for the database we made a second
class, just for this one.
– Okay. So it's like what is it
called, duck typing or something?
– Yeah, we duck typed it all the same
functions just with indexedDB.
– I mean maybe we can come back to this
but do you mind if I ask a question?
– Go ahead.
– I'm not familiar with KERIpy so I
understand none of the words on
– Oh, okay.
– Except for like just from like a
more of a web centric mentality like
how is it storing data?
– We're using PyScript's API,
actually which is one of the reasons why
we chose to use it. They have a storage
API that exposes basically a couple
useful functions that we can then use to
store our data persistently.
– What is WebDBer?
– WebDBer is the ducktyped
class
for LMDB and KERIpy. KERIpy is the
core KERI repository
that implements
the protocol.
– We can talk more after.
– This is like basically the
nitty-gritty of…
– This is some of the KERIpy
internals
of the library itself. – WebDBer is a
KERIpy concept.
– So is HIO.
– HIO is a separate library. It's an
asynchronous library that [inaudible]
– And Sam had to extend HIO actually
for this to be possible because the
browser and JavaScript uses
asynchronous calls and HIO did not
before and so Sam had to add an
asynchronous interface into HIO we can
then use to persist our database.
– So are all these changes now
today committed into
KERIpy?
– It's on a branch but yeah.
So this is how it
works. We have the UI. It's just like a
very basic JavaScript shell which
launches our PyScript web workers that
then call into KERIpy and HIO which
allow us to run Python in the browser
and those call out to indexedDB which
stores it persistently.
Keys are created in browser… survives.
No server side key management. Don't
worry guys, here comes the demo.
– Before you get the demo guys…
– Shoot.
– So, what you guys do about Keeper? How
are you encrypting keys?
– Made a web keeper
that interfaces with…
[inaudible] the encryption before putting it
in indexedDB.
– Yeah, I think so.
I could look at the code. I can tell you
what I did. I don't know. I did a lot
of this like a couple months ago.
– So if I wanted to make my own
database implementation, I would make a
ducktyped class for another data store.
– Correct. And then you'd have to
create like a baser for that class and a
keeper for that class.
– Really?
– Probably. Yeah.
Anyway,
here's it running in the web.
So, I just copied Locksmith's UI
because that felt intuitive.
Again, this is just being hosted
locally. Eventually, I think we're going
to want to deploy like a the KERI
Foundation will want to deploy like a,
you know, basic rate limited version for
the features that require witness and
watcher access. So, I have some vaults.
See, I was testing some vaults out.
All right, let's create a vault.
Open the vault.
We can create local identifiers. I'll
make one for Evan. Oh, those are emojis.
[inaudible]
And I was trying to get this working
last night. Those might work. I created
the plug-in page.
So let's see if it actually works.
It's spelled incorrectly. That's okay.
The KERI Foundation plugin. So in
Locksmith which Phil demoed yesterday
which they then donated to open source.
The idea is that because it's open
source anyone who wants to provide
witness and watcher infrastructure can
create like a plugin
and then you can connect to these
different providers plugins and get oh
it worked nice – so it works
you can get witnesses in the browser.
– So that plugin is pointed to some
external infrastructure or…
– It's pointed to the witness and watcher
service that healthKERI also so
graciously donated that is running
locally on my machine right now.
– The same thing he demoed yesterday.
– Yeah, he demoed this yesterday just
spinning up your own local infrastructure.
The KERI Foundation is going
to provide I think like a basic API
which will allow you to interface with
our plug-in and then you can grab our
deployed witnesses and watchers on our
service. That sound right?
– Close enough.
KERI Foundation will have a
plugin. Other providers will have
plugins as well that they can provide.
– So we're going to host all of
our services or we have hosted our
services on Digital Ocean.
I'm doing this all running locally
because it was faster for testing
essentially. Yeah, and so
it's working in the browser. The next
thing I have a lot to show guys.
I've also been working on trying to
get Locksmith
able to
have multiple plugins so that we can
show that, you know, in this open source
ecosystem, anyone can come in and
provide their own
witnesses and watchers as a service. So,
Here's the KERI
Foundation.
– This one's desktop?
– This is desktop app.
I'll add my Evan identifier. That's not my name.
With an emoji. No. What? No emojis here,
guys. I'm sorry.
So, this is Locksmith, the open sourced
version.
Okay. On the desktop.
On desktop. This is the desktop app.
– So, we just doing this for comparison
with the web one.
– Yeah, the web one is not as far along. I
have plugins working on the desktop
one to demonstrate that you can have
multiple providers giving you witnesses
and watchers. So, we have our KERI
Foundation plugin.
So we create like our account
identifier. I think Ryan showed this
yesterday, but
it's basically just talking to…
– It works a lot faster when it's local.
– Does work a lot faster when it's local.
And then I have a second plugin here.
Well, actually, that wasn't anything
impressive. So, I can add one of my
local identifiers in the KERI
Foundation plugin.
And then I can grab witnesses from the
KERI Foundation infrastructure which is
running locally.
And I have to provision and register
them.
It's like kind of similar to
healthKERI because they left some shared
components. So I used a lot of them.
And then I can grab this. Rotate them in.
All right. Selected to rotate in the witnesses.
Okay. So now my local identifier has one
witness from KERI Foundation
infrastructure, ideally once it's
deployed. And then say you as an
individual or corporation want to also
provide witness infrastructure. You
would create a plugin for Locksmith.
I copied and pasted the folders so they
look very suspiciously similar.
– Can I ask a question here?
– Yep.
– So this
creating a plugin.
Do I have control over the UI?
– Yeah.
– And so if I want to have
some enterprise
whatever specific thing or any
service I want I can integrate
that as a plugin.
– Totally. And you probably want to
again because this is fully open source
to get it like contributed to the… you
could either contribute it like upstream
to like the one in the KERI
Foundation repo or you could just clone
it and deploy it as your own
application.
– Okay. And so just as an
example, when we first did the plug-in
concept, we were thinking just SaaS
providers would put a plug in here so
that you'd get watchers and witnesses
from anyone. But then we found use case
for the enterprise credential
issuance platform that we're building.
The user interface is a plug into
Locksmith and it just made sense because
if you're building any kind of user
interface that could use KERI, it's a
great place to put it.
As long as you're like writing Python and
PythonScript.
Or writing Claude [laughter]
– As long as you can. I don't like it.
– All right. So, I'm creating my test
infrastructure account. I'm not going to
scan this one. And then I can go to my
identifiers. I can grab the same local
Evan identifier. You can see and it has
the witnesses. It doesn't have all the
the fancy schmancy tooling that
healthKERI showed quite yet.
So now I have four witness servers
running for this one. So I can add four
witnesses here.
Okay. And then I can rotate in these
witnesses. I can also rotate
the other witness, but I'm not going to
do that.
My authenticator has two seconds left.
I'm using Google authenticator on my
phone, so no onePassword copying like
Phil was showing yesterday for me.
I missed a digit.
All right, there you go. They're in. So
now I have again it took it sequence
number is two because I rotated in two
sets of witnesses from two different
providers and there are five total
witnesses witnessing my local
identifier. So, it works. [applause]
Sweet. And then,
I've been trying to make it easy
for anybody who wants to create a plugin,
to create their own plugin. I was
thinking, I've had many different
approaches as to how I best thought
this possible. So, my newest approach
was to create just like a templating
folder basically that would kind of
just give you like a one UI page that
you could use as a template so that it
would Claude could actually be smart
when he does it. Yeah.
– So Sam introduced the concept of
what was it called? Observer registrar. I
still need to figure out what all
that is. But so similarly here the
plugin you could I suppose manage
those kinds of things as well?
– Eventually, yes. I think the observer
and the registrar stuff.
– Are they just extensions of witnesses
and watchers? I guess I don't know…
– They monitor a different thing.
– Those monitor your
credentials. – So, but if I wanted to make
a plugin for that, I could mention…
– Probably.
– Yeah, I don't we haven't gone down that
road yet. So…
– Wait, sorry, what was the question?
If the plugin could be used for
helping implement the registrars and
observers.
– Yeah, absolutely. I mean, it would
just be the user interface into
those. So if you stand up a SaaS platform
that has APIs to allow you to stand up
registrars and observers that absolutely
you could add it to your interface here
in your plugin to reserve those for you.
– Which is similar to the witness and watchers
you have to services out there. – Exactly.
– It's just UI to connect manage
the relationship.
– That's exactly right.
– Yep. Sweet.
– Okay that was most of the things I
wanted to show. I mean this is cool
because it shows the how we are, KERI
Foundation. We're open source accepting
multiple providers if possible.
– So then what's the status of the
mobile because we did web and desktop…
– The mobile is, Jay do you want to take
this one?
– I'm sorry?
– How's the status of
the mobile? Jay has been working on
mobile
– It will be deployed sometime in the near future
as soon as it gets the account info
from Sam for the iOS and Android stores.
– It's the same code though that runs the
web wallet.
– It's the same code.
– So it's just being deployed.
– It the iOS and Android code are just in
wrappers that run almost like a pseudo
browser and we just deploy pretty much
the same code onto it.
– So it's the web essentially version.
– And, it's pretty much
it's just the web app.
– So it's doing all the same stuff you said,
the Wasm and all the WebDBers
mobile.
– Yes.
– Is there a mailbox as part of this?
– No, not yet.
Probably.
– So on either the phone, you know, or
or a browser page, right? Let's
say I'm an issuer,
issue you a credential offer or
friend.
And your phone is off or your browser
is not on at the moment.
Will there be a mailbox in
between to pick it up?
– I would assume it would go
to your witnesses or something.
– So that's a common misconception.
So when we originally deployed
witnesses, we did make mailboxes a part
of the witness deployment simply because
we were moving very fast and had nowhere
else to hang them. Okay,
we didn't want to create a whole new
service at the time. So, we have since
moved away from that. healthKERI does
provide mailboxes as a bespoke thing you
can reserve and I was going to demo that
yesterday but ran out of time and then
and then you just launch a Locksmith
turn it on say activate this mailbox and
now you can get messages on it and if
you miss any messages they're stored
forward so they sit here.
– Are those on your platform like you're
storing?
– Those are platform. So then …
– It's a very simple small service. It's
it's basically if you were to look at
the code inside of KERIpy you just pull out
the mailbox stuff. – Yeah, because there
is mailbox up in the right
– That could be hosted anywhere.
– Absolutely. It's just like any other
resource.
– Yep.
– Again, we got this code
recently from healthKERI. So,
– Awesome work.
– There's a long
list of features we're we're aiming to
add. So,
just hit the ones that were priorities
for the conference first.
I mean, again, you can you can always go
into the open source repos, create
issues for features you want to see, and
we can address those as they come in
as well.
– Or fork and build.
– Yeah,
absolutely.
– So did I understand you correctly
that you had you said five witnesses
were monitoring? Well, five witnesses
were associated with your identifier.
Okay. That's the same amount of
witnesses that GLEIF maintains in the
infrastructure and the same that we
require from QVIs to contribute to with
only a small overlap for shared
resources in effect. Should we be
also perhaps providing guidance to
wallet holders? Credential holders?
Guidance as to how many witnesses
they should be addressing?
– True. Well. If there's
particular requirements for it, then
yeah, absolutely.
– Sam's recommendation was
– Was five?
– It was either one or four
cuz he says when you
have three or four as your signing
threshold for witnesses you can't be
eclipsed and then if you have one well
it's less secure because one could
be compromised.
– I think a mission of the KERI
Foundation is going to also be to
provide
documentation with recommendations and I
would guess it will grow to span
ecosystems so like if you
going to become a QVI
here's what you will need to consider
here are the recommend recommendations
you're going to have to follow if you're
going to be doing this in healthcare,
or use other things. I suspect that
KERI Foundation will be a central
location for that stuff.
– Well, I've already got those kinds of
requirements in the ecosystem governance
framework for QVIs.
Because obviously we issue credentials
to the QVIs.
But I could put in the credential
frameworks for the legal entity one, the
[inaudible] A recommendation of
how many witnesses should be
associated with.
That would be the right place to put.
Okay.
All right. Thank you.
– Anybody have other questions, things you
want to say, comments, concerns? Yeah.
– I just have a general question. I'm
not very familiar with KERIpy and I'm
I'm doing my own like very lightweight
kind of educational JavaScript
implementation and as soon as
you try something like that you
notice how extensive the spec is. So
it's like one step five.
So you're doing this in the web
but you're not reimplementing with
JavaScript you're wrapping KERIpy. So
you basically get all the… like how
much of the spec does KERIpy
implement
like pretty much all of it or?
– So KERIpy as it stands right now in…
there's three branches 1.2x and 1.3x
those implement full KERI of KERI and
ACDC of 1.0
and KERI has since evolved
significantly into 2.0. What these guys
are… well so one of their missions
besides just put out these tools is to
take KERIpy and completely upgrade it
to 2.0. That is still work in progress
and it is the current main branch on
KERIpy represents that work.
So it will of course eventually
implement certainly the entire KERI
spec and I would guess the first
milestone is as much of the ACD specs…
ACDC spec as is needed to satisfy SEDI.
So I'm suspecting that's probably Sam's
big goal for getting KERIpy to where
it needs to be.
– But it seems like with this strategy
whatever the feature completeness is of
KERIpy you kind of get that for free.
You get that from this
except
is there a distinct UI in the
browser like do you have like could you
have a situation where the desktop is
ahead of the browser because the browser
hasn't written the HTML templates to…
– Yes. – Okay.
– Yep. Those are
separate UI implementations.
That could come slightly opposite,
and I would suspect they'll eventually
grow to be somewhat separate simply
because of the paradigm of running
something in the web and mobile versus a
desktop app.
Just like if you look at one password
looks similar but there's quite a bit of
difference functionality between their
plugin and the desktop app.
– So the Locksmith desktop app is that
also Python everything?
– Yes. – And what's the
PySide6?
– PySide6.
Yeah, it's pretty good to work with.
– And that works cross platform.
So, Mac and everything.
– Yeah.
– Mac, Windows and Linux [inaudible].
[applause]