So yeah, my name is Fergal. I'm the
identity solutions lead architect at the
Cardano Foundation. I've been there for
the last four years building out our
open source identity solution known as
Veridian. Some of you may have seen
that this morning in Thomas's
presentation on the 5WS.
Over a year ago, we launched the
Veridian wallet to the public app
stores. This is the first KERI ACDC
mobile wallet in production. It's
based on KERI and Signify. We
invested a lot of time and effort into
Bringing a nice user experience to
the user. You know abstracting away
the details of low-level KERI and
giving something that's actually usable
to the end user. So in doing that we
had to actually contribute a lot of
things back to Korean Signify.
Yesterday I spoke about the security
yesterday I spoke about the security
architecture of Korean Signify. But
today I'll talk about the path to
production. I think there are some
maturity gaps in the implementation of
Korean Signify that should be addressed
for adoption of the KERI suite. It's
starting to lag behind the maturity of
KERIpy. We'll kind of step through
that today.
so
I mean yesterday's talk gave kind of an
in-depth explanation of how it works in
practice. But kind of the tagline
that I had was agent in the cloud
controller at the edge. So KERI
allows you to deploy cloud agents
which essentially handle all of the
verification of KERI ACDC up in the
cloud and allow you to use an edge
client library known as Signify at
the edge to just assign key
events essentially or ACDCs this
keeps the edge layer very thin. Okay. So
for example, Veridian wallet on our mobile
just uses a Signify TS just to sign
things essentially and all of the
complex validation logic is pushed to
the cloud kind of like a black box
essentially. So in many ways it
becomes kind of a more easy to use
API that's kind of at a higher level
which you know is desirable for adoption
So it gives something that's a bit
more tangible for people to develop on
And very quickly this is taken from
my deck yesterday but doesn't look so
good on the four screens there but if
KERI is this kind of block in the
middle is the multi- aent service it's
based on pie Okay. So it's a Python
service. It allows you to spin up
various agents in the cloud that are
fully isolated. So they have separate
databases. And for every agent in
the cloud, you have exactly one
signified client at the edge. So this
these could be various applications from
various people sharing the same cloud
agent. This could be say on a mobile
device for example. And there's a
secure communication between each client
and agent. Which I delved into
yesterday. I won't do that today.
And the agent is also responsible for
and the agent is also responsible for
interfacing with everything else on the
network. Such as witnesses and
watchers and issuers and verifiers and
so forth. So Signify only ever talks
to the cloud agent.
Quick question if I may. So why
must there only be one Signify client
per agent? So for example, let's say I
had a Veridian wallet and I had a
browser wallet. Why couldn't I both
connect to the same agent? What would be
the problems with that?
Do the Signify clients have different
do the Signify clients have different
key material?
No, same pass password passcode.
Well, for me that's moving around the
passcode a bit too much.
Well, it's the same user though, right?
I have my phone and I have another two
phones or two devices. What's the
problem with that?
There wouldn't actually be a problem
with that if it's effectively the same
client. If you're using the same
passcode, it is effectively the same
client, just a different instance of it.
So it'll it'll derive the same key
material and authenticate in the same
way.
But if your applications keep local
but if your applications keep local
state, you might it might cause
inconsistencies essentially. So
Okay. Okay. But it might work.
No, it would work. Yeah. Yeah.
Although it might then you know how
it actually stores data on KERI needs
to be the same. You've seen this when
you've tried to connect your
wallet to what was our wallet. Yeah, it
works but you see some fuzzy stuff
that's related to our wallet only.
But yeah, this is generally the setup.
but yeah, this is generally the setup.
And today I've kind of split into
three different sections of what I will
cover on how we can mature Korean
Signify. First is focused on the
developer experience. The second on
the operational resilience and third on
scalability. I think the first two
are the most important to do in the
short term. To really you know
increase the usability of the stack.
Scalability is more relevant in the long
scalability is more relevant in the long
term. A lot of people think about this
now but these first two points are more
relevant in my opinion and scalability
will be very relevant for SEDI though you
know if we're launching KERI
instances they want to serve thousands
and thousands and thousands of people
with wallets and scalability becomes a
big concern. And just to preface as
well, I mean this is going to be a talk
probably explaining all the bad points
of KERI and Signify, but it does work.
It is in production. It's just maybe
a bit nuanced to work with. It's very
unless you understand it, it can be hard
to work with because there's a lack of
feedback in places. But all of that is
really just traditional software
development points that are missing.
Just some extra maturity. It's not like
it's not anything related to the
protocols as such or the security.
And in places where I say that, oh,
and in places where I say that, oh,
there's not enough API hardening in
place, the reality of that is just
something happened. The KERI crashes.
It's not a security bug. For as so much
as I can see, it's more about a
resilience thing. Okay.
So, on the developer experience the
first point I'm going to on this slide
refer to at the edge. So everything in
Signify essentially
We've been working quite hard over the
we've been working quite hard over the
last at least 6 months I think to
strongly type the edge libraries so I
mean if you're using sign typescript
you should be using types essentially
but when Signify was originally written
It didn't have any types in it
this is problematic if you're
refactoring code and so forth things
start to break. So we've put a lot
of time and effort to strongly type
Signify. It's not fully there yet,
but it pretty much almost is. And
instead of adding types directly into
Signify, we've actually taken a kind of
A different approach because as I
mentioned yesterday, Signify essentially
is kind of like an API wrapper around
KERIA. It can do extra things like
generate key events and sign them, but
it's otherwise an API wrapper. And
since you have an API on KERIA, you can
let KERIA decide what it wants and what
it will respond with through its open
API documentation. Okay, so it will say
at this endpoint, it will give a
response in this format if it's a HTTP
200 or whatever. So
and this is common practice to take open
API documentation and autogenerate types
in languages. Okay, so that's what we've
done. We've updated all of the open API
docs on KERIA and generated types in
Signify TS and Signify Java because they
propagate to various languages now as
a single source of truth and if you
wanted to add in another Signify like a
Rust library you could just
automatically generate them. Now you
might have to do some reworking in
places.
Java for example is
not as expressive in its type system as
TypeScript is. It didn't play nice
with a lot of the semantics of CESR.
But we've kind of got it working now.
So it took some changes there but
it's quite useful and also we're not
hand rolling the open API docs. We're
actually taking
the data structures in KERIpy that
Sam's written saying okay here are the
top level fields of an ACDC we've
converted those into Python data classes
automatically generated so they can be
reused in KERI and those data classes
are converted to the open API docs and
you what that gives you is if there's an
update you know downstream it propagates
upstream and the open API docs don't go
out of sync so this has been a huge
lift to make it more usable.
Internally, I think Signify still needs
some work.
Probably we can get away with not doing
probably we can get away with not doing
that for a bit. There's maybe some other
points that are more relevant to that
point. I would say we'd maybe tackle
this when we're upgrading to CESR 2,
which would be quite a bit of work as
well.
So, quick question if I may. So
some of the Web of Trust developers
refer to Signify meaning Is it what
Signify TS has in it? I always thought
of it as like the protocol that KERI
exposes. So is Signify a component or is
it a protocol or is it all things or I
don't. So how would you define what
Signify is? So sorry it's a simple
question but it's a language question
mostly
an edge client that you can that
any edge client of KERI.
Yeah.
Okay. So it's got it.
Yeah. Yeah. So there's a KERI
protocol essentially,
right? It's defined as a protocol, but
it could be Signify JS or Signify Java
or
Yeah. Yeah.
whatever other language.
How does it look like? Is it is it
UX stuff or is it command line stuff or
library?
Library. So when you're using Signifi
TS,
you essentially it's kind of like having
a compiler error if you type in the
wrong formats essentially. So if you try
to create an ACDC or something, it will
know what the structure should look like
and you can reference it directly.
Whereas before you're kind of blind
essentially, you know you would if
you're maybe you receive an ACDC back
from KERI and you were going to present
that in the UI and you would say I want
to get the top level I field as the
issuer.
If you were to reference some field that
doesn't ex exist like T before it
wouldn't complain and you just get a
blank space in the UI whereas now
TypeScript would say there is no top
level T field in an ACDC. So
I'm a strong you know believer in
strongly typed languages.
The payoff is very high in terms of
the payoff is very high in terms of
keeping the book count low and
especially when you refactor.
to your to your question. It's a library
you need to be able to build that you
want on top of
sort of
a hole in the wall where you give the
food like you give to the other
the delivery desk or whatever.
Yeah,
you have the back office which is
career
and then you have this and then you can
deliver it out to the UX
serving window or something.
Yeah.
Okay. And with this you know what's
going to come out, what shape it will
be, what comes through the serving
window whereas before it's like you're
blindfolded. So
No I'm good. Another one which is
no I'm good. Another one which is
a bit technical. Currently with in
all of the Signify implementations
When you want to do something like
issue a credential
in one command on Signify
it will construct the credential
Try to create the interaction event
to anchor it in your Key Event Log. It
will pick the sequence number for you
and submit it to the API all in one go.
Absolutely.
Which automates workflows of several
steps. Yeah.
Yeah. Which is not a good thing because
if you lose the HTTP response
u you've not lost data. Okay. It's okay
when you use Signify completely
stateless in smaller applications but
when you want to build enterprise
applications where you need you know
mission critical reliability you need
things to go through. So if you want
outbox patterns, you need to be able to
decouple those things. So you can create
and sign at the edge and then submit.
And the API should be ident.
Yeah.
Yes.
On that particular note, I want to
make I want to hear more what you have
to say on outbox patterns. That's
actually something I was looking into.
It seems like that while we're
considering this,
we should consider the API, the
fundamental design of the API between
Signify and car because the One of the
reasons why we have so many different
HTTP payloads instead of just CESR
streams which if we were to just had
streams the outbox it would be very
straightforward
is because we didn't have a fully a
complete parser and cryptographic
primitives implementation in TypeScript
when Signify CS was being first created
and so we ended up doing a bit of what
you would say is a bulkier
API from Signify CS to KERI because
really we should just be passing CESR
strings around and instead we have these
and embeds that we put in HTTP messages.
And so I it's it's sort of a something
that I've wondered about as part of
maturing the Signify and KERI out. But
even before we even get there, I do
think we should architect everything the
way that you're saying about boxes
save everything locally. That makes a
lot of sense. So
but I'm just sort of saying if we're
going to do that anyway, maybe we should
reconsider what we even send per
end.
Yeah, that's a big refactor as well or
change rather. Yeah,
but you could put helper functions,
you know, also in Signify ts, sorry,
that
that either give the structure or raw C.
Okay, going
I'll finish because I have like 10 sides
of this. This is on our fork. We've
done this already with identifier
creation. So, we create the identifier
locally and then submit it and it allows
us to get reliability in our wallet,
which we couldn't get before. But we
probably need to apply this everywhere.
Can you say that again? You create the
can you say that again? You create the
identifier and then submit it. Yeah. So
the post call is decoupled. So we
can put it into an outbox locally and
push it up. We've gone to a lot of
lengths for reliability in our wallet,
but you need to do things like that for
it. And you also get better control
in the sequence number for anchoring. So
if you're trying to assign multiple
things at once, especially in a group
multi context, having better control
will be better.
So how is this how is that just
different from simply right now? Is that
what the 10 slides are? Well, for
example, right now in Signify, you IPEX
is decoupled. You create the IPEX
message and you submit it.
It's two calls. Everything else isn't,
but it should all be like IPEX.
I see.
Yeah.
Wants to go through.
Maybe I should leave the room.
All right.
Okay. It's just an example of the
TypeScript generated,
a snippet of it. It's a very long file.
And in Java there's like hundreds of
classes generated but this is what
we're contributing. The other
developer experience issue, and this is
actually probably even a bigger issue,
And you see this all the time on
Discord for new developers is
silent failures
where, you know, you submit something to
KERIA
and nothing's happening essentially.
Now with KERI when you submit things
now with KERI when you submit things
that take time you get an operation back
and you can track the operation
completion such as if it's waiting for
witness receipts and so forth. But
it's so common to have operations that
are stuck in pending forever and you
have no idea why and you can't trace it
down and it's because you had a
different set in this place of this and
you there's very little feedback to why
that happened. So
you want to put more weight on it.
Yeah, you just need more you just need
better feedback patterns essentially.
It's probably a case by case basis
to do that. This is at kind of the
API layer. It needs it needs work.
But there could be like a result T kind
of pattern applied to the call so
that if there's a failure in any call,
it's handled in a consistent way.
Yeah. But this is not the call. the call
is like it accepts it and it puts it
onto a parser
and then the result of parsing that
doesn't result in a fully signed
something because something was wrong
and you have no idea why and you're
tracing through the logs and there's a
million logs.
I don't have a I mean this is case by
case basis so you'd have to step through
the code and find the biggest issues but
even if you historically look at the
GitHub issues or Discord you'll see what
pops up most. This one
I think we fixed this one and actually
caused a different issue or
not sure.
Yeah, we made a change. Yeah, cuz it
wasn't
anyway. Yeah, but in general it just
needs work. I would say it's a
barrier to entry. Yeah, I've seen
this too often where the operation just
times out and you have no idea why.
I would think they're probably the two
biggest things you could do for the
developer experience. So, it's actually
easy to build on, you know because
if you get stuck wondering why this
isn't working for hours and hours and
hours, it's
If you finally convince someone to try
if you finally convince someone to try
car
Yeah.
and they start developing and this is
experience.
Yeah. But this these are easy things to
fix. It just takes a little bit time to
go through certain edge cases. The
harder one to fix is the typing which
we've almost done. So, that's the good
news. The second so that was
developer experience. The second kind
of section is operational resilience
kind of you know after you deploy it
what that looks like. Some of these
might bleed back into developer
experience though but related to the
last one is API hardening. They're
kind of overlapping. But additionally
not just
you know KERI getting stuck in the
state where things are pending. It's
also a bit crash prone from certain bad
inputs.
What happens if it crashes?
what happens if it crashes?
Well, if it's in the Docker setup, it
just comes back up. That's fine. But
like you know we even see like in our
developer KERI deployment that we use
at Veridian and you'll have some random
person in the community trying to do the
previous slide sending the wrong input
and they crash our instance and all of
our wallets are flashing to offline mode
because KERI has gone down and up you
know so it needs a bit more
resilience. At that point it's not
on the parser. It's actually just on
things like the granter and things like
that. All the dexter and the agent in
file.
It's the development, not the
production.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
He says our wallets are going up and
down. That's
the development environment.
Yeah. Yeah.
They don't have access to our
production. That's not Yeah.
yeah. And of course, KERI is multi-
aent. Okay. So yeah, like I just said,
you're now denying service to other
people just because you're submitting
the wrong thing. And it bloats the
logs with lots of errors. That could be
nice,
you know, information back to the user.
You submitted the wrong thing.
Yeah, I believe this was the I believe
yeah, I believe this was the I believe
this was the one we fixed recently.
So it doesn't crash anymore if you
point your
Admit to the wrong instead of
pointing it back to the grant, you point
it to a different string. It caused a
crash. Now it causes is now it causes
a an operation that's pending forever.
So you just pushed it down one layer,
but
Another one is application layer
reliability.
So
I think there's kind of a misconception
that the escros in KERIpy are
meant to provide application layer
reliability, but they're not. They're
more they're they're more so to
handle out of order processing. Okay. So
in reality, if you want full reliability
at the application layer between say
two wallets, their agents will need to
continuously resend information
Until they get a acknowledgements
back. Okay. So like for example
currently if I send an IPEX grant and my
KERI sends it to the port of another
KERI instance and it's accepted 202
all that's done is put it onto the
parser.
Okay. It's not going to give you any
feedback if it crashes. The parser is in
memory right? So if their KERI instance
goes down at that point in time when you
just got the 202 back, you have no idea
that they didn't parse it at all.
They've never seen it essentially. So
for application reliability, we need
retries on that.
So when you're talking about they you
so when you're talking about they you
mean the other controllers agent
maybe not even related to your agent
other than it's on the same KERI. So,
I was experiencing the need for
retries that I didn't understand because
I have a good network. But it
could just so as a defensive program
when you get the 202 or other certain
other areas, you need to retry. It's not
necessarily a network error.
Yeah.
Is that what you're saying? It's the
KERI is busy or dropped it.
Yeah. I mean, so on the 392 port, the
CESR endpoint of KERIA, it will just
take in the CESR stream and put it
onto the queue of the parser and give
you a 202 back and then parse it. But if
it gives you the 202 back and
immediately crashes, you've now lost
that data.
They have no idea that they need to
parse something. They can't parse it.
It's lost in memory. But the 3902 port
isn't used by Signify TS, right? It's
I'm not talking about Signify TS here.
I'm talking about entire KERI here,
but agent to agent communication. Yeah.
But also from Signify clients.
but also from Signify clients.
Can use it if they want.
can use it if they want.
392 is open.
Yeah. But Signify TS doesn't do anything
with it out of the box, right?
No, it doesn't out of the box. No.
But also Yeah. If your agent accepts,
but also Yeah. If your agent accepts,
you know, an IPEX message, it should
send it, right?
Especially for groups. So, for example,
especially for groups. So, for example,
If you have a group set up
based on KERI and Signify
Let's say the one person proposes an
IPX message, sends it to the others, it
starts collecting signatures. before it
collects enough signatures, it goes
down, comes back up, receives the other
signatures, nothing happens. It doesn't
send it to the other person because the
granter deck is in memory, the queue.
So, it's lost it. And the lead of the
group currently is the one that sends.
So, a lot of the in-memory decks that we
use for cues in KERI need to be made
durable. So
we is there an issue? If there's not an
issue with that, I'm going to make that
one right now. That's
Yeah, that's that's that's bad. That one
that one's bad, actually. That needs to
be fixed soon. But you don't see
these in your normal setups like
because it's just happy paths.
Everything just works. Everyone clicks
at the same time.
It's all good.
Yeah.
And it'd be nice to have some more
feedback on the async stuff because
everything in KERI is async. So,
if we have better ways of receiving
results that are more rich on what's
happening, that would be useful. But
that's a bit open-ended.
I mean, if you already have a plan to
put these into issues, I don't want to
duplicate it. But is this like is
there's a plan to currently make an
issue on that because if there's not,
I'll capture it immediately.
I have a joint discussion but I don't
know if it has everything from this. It
was written a while ago. It's either
in Signify TS or KERIA. Okay.
That's some information from Sam on
that's some information from Sam on
application layer reliability.
If you want to read it, it's him saying
that KERI Pie is not going to provide
this essentially.
What is him saying again?
About achieving application layer
reliability end to end.
Okay, cool. and the need for retries and
identy so forth.
Cool.
Finally, well, not finally.
so
especially when you're using group
multisig if you're doing something
wrong, it can be quite hard to
understand what you're doing wrong
because it's a multi- aent setup. All
your logs are intertwined. There's no
way to filter on the logs. And even if
there was a way to filter on the logs
per agent there's still too many
logs. There's no way to filter on the
action you were trying to do. And
data again, everything's based on HEO.
Everything's async, everything's moving
various ways with little
observability. It's again fine in happy
pad once you've developed it's fine
but sometimes it can be very
difficult to add new features to KERI
and try and figure out where the data is
actually moving and what's actually
wrong and why this isn't completing and
so forth.
Should the KERI requests have a
request ID added to them?
Probably. Yeah. Yeah. But it'll need
some work with KERIpy as well
because most of the complex logic of
KERI is KERIpy. It's it's a direct
dependency. it gets pushed onto KERI
pie. So I need to do some work
there. So yeah, some instrumentation
would be useful at that. And this is
just I mean yeah, you see you go to the
logs and you're just trying to figure
out what's going on because you've put
the wrong ID somewhere and it's yeah,
you can see Kent added some you added
some stuff here. But we probably need
to go a bit further so we can actually
filter on ids of like agents and so
forth.
A structured log.
Yeah.
Request ID or client ID.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'll do this one quite quickly.
Yeah, probably KERI and Signify should
yeah, probably KERI and Signify should
have some semantic versioning because
it's an API. And I think you raised
issues on this. There should be compet
compatibility enforcements between them.
I don't think this is big issue now,
but in as you move towards, you know,
being a more mature ecosystem and
getting more developers in, it'll become
more relevant. Also versioning
Right now you have to version on the
KI per agent and iterate over them. So
there needs to be a migration framework
in place. We've been avoiding this
for ages because there hasn't been
migrations essentially but when there is
yeah in production it would be
problematic. Okay so that's
resilience
and again this is just I think these are
more like traditional software problems
you know just put some resources into it
and it'll make it a more mature app
it's not a protocol thing so these are
all very achievable
But finally on scalability
And this one is also a kind of
developer experience
So
I mentioned earlier that because a lot
of the things are async, you need to
submit like create an identifier, create
a registry, issue a credential and you
get an operation back.
And then you need to pull on that
status of the operation until it's done
while it's waiting to collect signatures
and so forth. That's kind of a pain.
Typ modern systems are usually
event driven. Where you would get
some notification that it has completed
rather than constantly checking.
The same goes for notifications. You
the same goes for notifications. You
have to constantly check if there's new
new notifications.
You know in any general application like
you know in any general application like
a wallet, it's going to have to
constantly check because it doesn't know
when to expect that you're receiving a
credential.
Single threaded environment, it could
completely
block the rest of the application.
Yeah. And I mean like
this we've made event driven in our
wallet in every application we've built
because we've just put it in a corner in
the box and made it event driven from
the perspective of the rest of our
application. But it's kind of annoying
to have to build that every single time.
But
this is very doable in if we were to
take the KERI reply
it approach of just using the even just
the WSGI response stream we could open
up the server events connection per
agent. Yep.
To Signify and do this today.
I might try that over the weekend.
Huh?
No.
Tell me about it.
Before I get to that. Yeah. So, the
reason I put this in scalability is
because right now you have 10,000
wallets using one KERI instance and
they have 25 pending operations that
they're pulling, pulling, pulling. These
are all full HTTP requests. It's way too
much traffic hitting KERI. It yeah
it won't work. So moving to something
like service events
is much better from a developer
experience, but it's also much better
from a load experience. And
it isn't, well, I haven't I've never
implemented them, so I don't know what
it's like, but for notifications, it
wouldn't be too difficult because it's
just the next notification coming out on
the event. It's more problematic for
operations. I explain that in a moment.
I also service end events are true
HTTP, so they're compatible load
balancers. So if you if you start to do
horizontal scaling and so forth, they're
compatible, which is why Sam likes them
over or would prefer that over
websockets because that isn't pure HTTP.
yeah. Now the problem for integrating
with operations is currently
when you perform an action that requires
a long run operation to track that
status of the operation.
It just stores the related sets and
it just stores the related sets and
metadata that refer to that operation.
It doesn't have a status of pending or
failed or anything like that.
And when you use Signify to check that
status of pending or failed, it's not
stored in the database. That's what I
mean. It doesn't flip in the database
from pending to complete
actually if you look at longridden.py
in KERI, it takes all of those sets
and compares it against the database of
the agent to see if it's effectively
complete. Okay, so it's not checking is
this operation complete in the database.
check in based on this operations
metadata are all the signatures in place
for this to be considered complete for
example you can see here for the
delegations using the swancomplete
every time you check
yeah basically like a diff on the
database
yeah so this has been quite a mental
challenge for me for like two years with
KERI is the notion that the concept of
state and state modeling is missing
and that's intentional
I think from Sam for what is
let's let's IPEX for example right is
you know I tried to get a state
machine diagram of all the possible
state transitions and IPEX of spurn
grant you know accept and all that and
had very had a challenge getting to the
precision but this is similar is you're
wanting to KERI the state of an
operation and it has to be derived and
has to be requeried to compute the state
is what I think I heard you say.
Yeah.
Of an operation, right? So it'd be like
it'd be nice just to get the state back
from curious like oh it's in pending.
Yeah. So basically while it's currently
like this we can't do event driven with
ser events
to date
because it's you're checking against the
database state. Okay. So instead of
checking the database state or the diff
when this completes for the first time
inside KERIpy, it needs to emit an
event that gets sent on server the
server sent event
thread.
Okay. Because I'm thinking what we could
do for each operation type is that there
could be let's say there's already a
server event connection from the agent
to the Signify client. It would
essentially just be a channel to
communicate. I'm thinking on completion
it would just send a completion.
Yeah. But there is no completion of an
operation in KERIA. It's a state check.
It tells you it's effectively complete.
There's no point where it's the
database. So
it's inferred
if you Yeah, it's inferred. So if you
never ever connect it again,
nothing changes on the database to say
it's complete. It's just you coming back
later and saying this is the status.
Okay. So because there's no point at
which that happens
things that's this is a problem all the
time right
so essentially
we need to store the completed state not
just derive it
yeah so and also but all of this happens
in KERIpy so KERIpy needs to tell us
because this is a KERI thing
operations aren't in KERIpy
locally in KERI per agent so because
once we derive it once even though we're
reading it
yeah but what triggers to derive it
otherw then you're going to move the
polling inside internally
what triggers What
what triggers check and it's complete
in KERI out.
So this is where I think what we should
do when we have an operation
There should be a doer for each
operation
once it completes at the end before that
doer finishes it should write the
complete state.
Yeah. But then you're now you've just
moved all of the polling internal toia
and you'd have so many doers for 10,000
signified clients you know. So it would
be a lot better if internally in KERI
Pi it could just let us know when it's
effectively completed
because there's already something inside
KERIpy tracking this I would say. So
then it can admit that event or whatever
and we can capture it and update our
operation in the database and send the
event back and service events.
Yeah, I think we're slightly talking
past each other but I think I get what
you're saying. I think fundamentally
when an important event happens in KERI
five, it should be admitted saying this
is happened.
Yeah. Yeah.
Rather than having new doers that are
also tracking it again, you know,
cool just one more slide. So it's
actually good.
No, actually one so not too bad.
Yeah, and horizontal scaling. I mean
yeah, and horizontal scaling. I mean
people have asked about this before
I would put this on the lowest priority
because other things just need to be
fixed first to get adoption. But for
SEDI it would be important.
Okay right now you could do something
like sticky sessions. It would be a very
naive approach. Where you know you
deploy 10 different KERIs and you
have a load balancer and once a once a
client connects and gets rooted to a
KERI instance they always have to go
there forever. that's like a sticky
session. It would work now, but it
wouldn't be great.
To do true horizontal scale, I think K's
to do true horizontal scale, I think K's
actually already quite suited to it.
Because all the databases of agents are
because all the databases of agents are
fully isolated and no agents are shared.
They're just a bunch of LMDB files.
Okay. So if you had to like
the easiest thing you could do is have a
shared volume in your cloud deployment
that all of the instances can access and
they would just go to the specific LMDB
files that were that they're currently
serving. And if it's done correctly
they won't try to access the same LMDB
file of someone else and you could have
the agency coordinate that. If you
wanted more isolation, I guess you could
separate the volumes, but I think that
would be
a little bit complex, not necessary.
yeah, you'd be moving data across
volumes. I don't like that for now. At
least I don't think it's necessary.
Unless there's a
legal constraint on data or something. I
don't know.
And yeah, the agency can become the
load balancer like it kind of currently
is basically for the message router in
KERI. But instead it would
actually be outside
KERI and root into kind of a more
lightweight KERI. So you kind of
decouple it a bit be different services
But yeah I think that's more down the
but yeah I think that's more down the
line. So that's why developer experience
and operational resilience are highest
priority I think. Yeah. Done.
What's this up?
That's the file system. So,
yeah.
Okay. So, the agency database is an LMDB
database. You can see that there was two
new
Agents booted. There are the config
files that get copied in the JSON config
files with the OOBIs.
And for each
Agent they have a subdirectory in all
of these directories. Like there's the
key store for example.
Probably it would be better if you
probably it would be better if you
restructure it so that the agent is at
the top level and it has its databases
internally so you can more easily take
it. But if it was a shared volume
across many instances it wouldn't
matter.