So hello everyone and welcome. My
name is Ferggo Connor. I'm the identity
solutions lead architect at the Cardano
Foundation. I've been there for the last
four years now helping out build out
our open-source identity solution known
as Veridian.
Last year we launched the first
mobile wallet in the KERI ACDC
ecosystem to production. This is a
production grade mobile identity
wallet. It's gone through security
auditing and pent testing. And in
general we put a lot of effort into the
user experience of this wallet and how
we could bring KERI and ACDC to the
masses and make it more accessible.
Okay. The wallet itself is based on
KERI and Signifi TS. And throughout
the years, you know, we've put a lot of
effort into contributing to KERI and
Signifi TS in the open source community.
Particularly because we were trying
to bring in this extra user experience.
There was kind of gaps in the existing
software that was required to deliver
that user experience he wanted. And
also some kind of security edge cases
kind of operationally that we had to add
in to align with our pen testing.
So today I'm going to be going over
kind of the security architecture of
KERI and Signifi TS. This is in the
advanced track so we'll be quite
technical. I think it's generally
okay if you have kind of a background in
into KERI but some parts might be
a bit low level.
now the first kind of tagline I want to
start with is so KERI is a cloud agent
In the KERI ecosystem.
And I kind of in line with everything
that say Sam was speaking about this
morning I kind of put the tagline
here of agent in the cloud controller at
the edge. Okay. So just because you're
using a cloud agent doesn't mean that
you give up control of your keys. Okay.
So if you have a mobile wallet which is
using a cloud agent based on KERI
your keys will always do the signing at
the edge on your phone. Okay. And I
also took this snippet from the
directly from the KERI specification.
So Samo defined that a controller
application needs to do five functions.
This is key pair generation and
storage, key event generation and
signing and key event validation. Of
course this is at the lowest level of
KERI. It doesn't talk about higher
level protocols such as ACDC's or UBS or
IPEX and so forth. But if you have
that controller application with those
five functionalities you can you can
if you wish split it across two kind
of software deployments of a controller
application on the left and a controller
agent on the right. So KERI is your
controller agent. The split here is
that your controller application say
your mobile wallet will have to do
the key pair generation key event
generation and signing. And then your
controller agent in the cloud can do
keeper storage and key validation. Now
the keeper storage of course has to be
encrypted because your agent cannot
access those keys because that would
break everything. And I think also
with this diagram you could put the
keeper storage in either side that works
in the setup of the deployment.
But critically the key event validation
but critically the key event validation
Is pushed to the agent in the cloud.
Okay. So particularly when you start
adding in other protocols such as
ACDC's and so forth, you're pushing all
of this complex validation logic that
must be spec compliant and so forth
to the cloud and abstracting away the
details in a way that your controller
applications can be a bit more
lightweight at the edge. All you have to
do is sign some events essentially and
not do all of the complex validation.
Okay. So today we're going to cover
kind of three areas.
First and foremost the kind of
service architecture of Korean Signify
How it works in general. Then
we'll delve a bit deeper into the trust
relationship between the cloud and
edge. What keys live where you know
what must be signed to establish this
trust relationship and so forth. And
then finally to wrap it all off we'll
we'll see and explore how to use KERI
to interact with the rest of the world
once you set this up.
Okay.
So on the service architecture
As an overview before we get into the
diagrams
KERI is of course a KERI agent in the
cloud. It's based on KERIpy directly.
So is the Python service that uses
KERIpy as a direct dependency. Most
of the complex validation is from KERI
core. It's essentially an orchestration
unit wrapped around it. It's a multi-
aent service. So it allows you to
provision many agents for many
controllers
and kind of to summarize it's a set of
HTTP endpoints essentially for
controlling these agents. So
provisioning them utilizing them and
to interact with the rest of the world.
Signify on the other hand is your edge
client library. This is what your
controller application would use.
Again the main idea here is to sign at
again the main idea here is to sign at
the edge. I believe in the early days
people were going to call Signify Kate
keys at the edge. They stuck with
Signify however. But it's essentially
just
basically like an API wrapper around
KERI. Except they can do this key
event generation and signing as well.
So it understands bits of C's and so
so it understands bits of C's and so
forth. The relationship is for every
Edge client there is one cloud agent
a direct onetoone mapping. And it's
available in multiple languages. So
within the Web of Trust the two complete
implementations are Signify ts in
typescript and Signify Py. I don't
believe Signify Py is used in production
but Signify ts is used by most people in
this ecosystem to be honest that aren't
building directly on KERIpy. In the
kan foundation we've also built a full
java implementation of Signify. It's
fully feature complete. That's
actually been used internally at the Kon
at the Corona Foundation and a number
of other projects that we're working on
Which have actually gone to
production.
And in general one nice thing about
Signify is that right now it gives
you a higher level API that is more
accessible to actually utilize KERI.
So if you were to build directly on
so if you were to build directly on
KERIpy you need there's a steep
learning curve to understand how it
works internally. And it would be
very easy to go wrong. Whereas with
Signify the API is a bit more like you
know create this identifier create this
ACDC registry issue this credential.
I think having that higher level API
also brings much more accessibility to a
wider audience for adoption and
because it's available in multiple
languages that also makes things
easier. It's you know I'm not going
to say it's super simple to add new
languages for Signify but it's much
more trivial than ports and KERIpy to
various languages.
So if we to look at the kind of this
overview diagram if KERI is here in the
center as I mentioned it's a multi-
aent service. So we have agents A B and
C.
Each agent has its own fully isolated
database. These databases are mostly
provisioned by KYI. They're a set of
LMDB databases u but they're fully
separated
and for each agent you have exactly one
signified client and they have a secure
API between them. Okay. So client C
cannot talk to agent B.
All of your state will be held in the
cloud. Signify is completely stateless
except for the key material that you
give to generate and derive the keys.
All signing happens at the edge. So
all signing happens at the edge. So
Signify will push signed events up into
KERI and your agent will you know do
whatever with that. It'll make propagate
it to witnesses send an exchange
message to a verifier or so forth.
And all interactions with the rest of
and all interactions with the rest of
the KERI network. So agents,
witnesses, watchers, controllers and so
forth all happen via KERI. And
these will all be direct CESR inbound
and outbound streams. So the Signify
clients will never talk directly to the
other agents, witnesses and watchers.
It's always through your agent directly.
And if I take that diagram and maybe
zoom in a little bit on KERI
again we have the three clients and
three agents. Each agent has its
isolated database
and KERI itself as I said it's a set
of HTTP endpoints. So there are three
endpoints 391 32 393.
The last one 393 is used to provision
new agents. Okay. So if you come along
if say Signify client D installs a
wallet on their phone which uses Signify
and they go through the onboarding
process they'll be able to provision
a new agent through this endpoint
which will set up all the database and
so forth. And that endpoint uses the
the agency it's called internally and
the agency has its own database to track
you know which client relates to which
agent which identifier that was
created by a client relates to which
agent.
It's pretty small to be
honest. This port 303 in production
shouldn't be left open because
otherwise you could just write a loop
and keep provision new agents with more
databases. So in Veridian we completely
Block that port from public access
and we have one-time boot URLs that
are sent by emails to protect the
infrastructure.
Once the client is onboarded in and
they have their agent up and running
within KERI in the service they can
then use the 391 port on the top left
which is the admin API. This is just
a set of rest endpoints you know create
identifier issue ACDC and so forth.
It's completely
it's completely
authenticated. So of course only one
client can talk to one agent. We'll
see more on that in the coming slides.
And then your agent, you know, it
might be talking to other nodes in
the KERI network to say propagate
events for witness receipts and so forth
or send an EXM message. Like
everything in the KERI implementation,
everything's async. So the response will
often come back in on a different port.
When it comes in it'll come on to the
message router. And the message
router will based on the headers
it'll look up in the agency okay someone
external is trying to talk to this AID
which agent should I route to and it'll
route to the correct agent and they'll
parse the incoming CESR stream
using that database specifically.
Okay. So that's kind of generally
operationally how it works and again
just to recap there are three different
ports. The boot port is used to
provision new agents. The admin port to
Serves all the rest endpoints for the
clients and the external 302 port is the
CESR endpoint for inbound
interactions. Okay. So
if we to delve a bit deeper into the
trust relationship between KERI and
Signify. So okay you've onboarded
into the system but how do you actually
authenticate on that API
I created this sequence diagram here
it's probably going to be the most
technical part of the talk but on the
left we have the signified client and
here we have the two ports that the
client uses the boot port and the admin
port I don't know how clear it is to see
there but there's a blue box there in
the top left which is the boot
sequence to provision a new agent
So,
Signify itself is completely stateless
except for a passcode that you must give
it. Okay, this passcode is used to
derive key material. It's a 21
character salt essentially in the
CESR B 64 URL variant.
Signify has an API to generate these
passcodes or they can be generated
externally. It doesn't matter. Yeah, you
just pass it to Signify when you're
connecting, booting or connecting to the
API. This 21 character passcode
which is assault then gets stretched
in a hierarchy deterministic way using a
path and the argon 2 ID function.
Okay, so this allows you to drive
keys ED25509 keys specifically.
So at index zero you get your first
signing key. Index one you get your
rotation key. These two keys
together you can use to generate an
inception event for your client AID
which I've called CA ID here. So this
client AID will be used by Signify to
communicate with KERI and to
authenticate on the endpoints. Okay it's
KERI direct mode. There are no
witnesses because this is directly
between client and agent. This client
AID is not used to interact with the
outside world. is only used to
authenticate on that endpoint in
KERI. Okay. So once you've generated
the inception event for the client AID
you of course sign it with your signing
key and then you send the signed
inception event on the boot port.
Once KERI receives this if it's a valid
inception event it will provision a new
agent. So it'll set up all of the
databases. It'll generate a salt for
that agent in the cloud because the
agent itself also needs its own AID.
And this AID which is a AID here agent
AID is actually a delegated identifier.
Okay. So it's delegated back to the
client AID. So there's this kind of
tight connection between the two AIDs.
And it'll send that back in the
response and because it's delegated and
KERI uses cooperative delegation. The
signified client will need to approve of
the delegation and send that back the
approval event which is just an
interaction event essentially which
contains the delegation seal. The
main reason you would do delegation here
is because Signify is completely
stateless. You know it can't remember on
its own what agent the ID was talking to
that it set up with initially. But if
KERI can give you back all of your
Key Event Logs and it can verify it. it
has proof within its own Key Event Log
that it the agent AID was the one it
would created the this kind of trust
relationship with. I don't think Signify
does that yet, but it could.
Yeah. One thing I've conceptually been
confused about is that and you probably
just explained it, but I needed to hear
it again. Is what who's who's
delegating to whom and what is being
delegated? You probably just said it,
but I need to hear it again. And is for
just that event or is there delegation
used later beyond?
Well, when you create a delegated
identifier in KERI, it essentially
means this identifier is not valid until
the other identifier approves it. So
they put essentially the AID of the
delegator inside their KEL in a seal in
a new interaction event. And now every
time the agent ID would want to do a
rotation event, the rotation event is
not valid until the Signify client
approves it. Okay, so it's like a
two-step approval. GLEIF use this with
QVIS for example. So if a QVI rotates
its keys, GLEIF has to approve it for that
rotation event to be valid. So
cooperative delegation and KERI is just
another security mechanism essentially.
But once that delegation is done,
then the agent can sign for the
controller for something. No, no,
no, no. It's not a delegation of
authority. That would be more like
issuing ACDC to someone.
Cooperative delegation is a security
mechanism essentially for rotation
events.
Okay.
It also for supersedes recovery where
you can like step back in the KEL and
fork like recovery. It there's the
mechanisms in which that's allowed are
much stronger, much more powerful in
delegated identifiers. So delegated
identifiers are for security
essentially. Yeah, it's cooperate
delegation. But in this case, it also
has the nicity of the Signify client
knows it should be talking to this agent
AID. It has proof that's who it
should be talking to. So at this
point you essentially have your agent
fully provisioned and fully ready in the
cloud. And you have your stateless
client which just has your 21 character
pass
passcode which in the code is also
called a brand but yeah, there's
different naming everywhere. At this
point okay this is only needs to be done
once you can now use the other
endpoint to do whatever you want to do
create identif issue ACD and so forth.
Okay now the first thing you need to do
because of stateless is to fetch the
state of the kels for direct mode. So
it fetches both the kels of each of them
And the sequence number of the
derivation path that way it knows how
to derive the keys again for its current
signing key. So on your client AID if
it did a number of rotations once it
starts up again it needs to initialize
itself with the state and this is an
unauthenticated endpoint because it
doesn't know what key to generate yet.
Once it's done that and derived its
current keys it can create HTTP requests
on the rest endpoints
And fully sign them with the client
AID and the responses will be fully
signed by the agent AID. Okay. So you
we're not using bearer tokens here. The
HTTP requests are signed back and forth.
Okay.
Does that make sense? Any questions?
I won't explain this cuz I might run out
of time, but the passcode that you use
to boot you can rotate that full
passcode. So you can switch to a new
salt essentially. This functionality
exists in KERI and Signify already.
The reason you might want to do that is
the reason you might want to do that is
because you might think your passcode's
exposed. Now, if it's fully exposed,
you're already gone. But let's say
you have a time window to recover from
that. You can actually rotate the
passcode. How that's done, I won't
explain right now. I'll do it at the end
if I have time. This QR code, suppose
you might be able to see that well
is a link to the markdown file from Phil
in the repository.
Which explains everything I just
explained this and everything I'm about
to explain quite clearly. If you want
to look at it after
finally one other thing that I want to
mention is
so I just said that the HTTP requests
between the client and agent are fully
signed. They use an RFC 9421.
Okay, so this is an existing standard
outside of KERI.
It's just been slightly adapted to
KERI, which just means the key that you
should be using for signatures is the
latest key state of the KEL essentially.
This is the in vanilla Signify TS
and KERI. This is how you how you do
it.
I have an open PR for ESSR support. I
think Phil mentioned ESSR in the last
talk.
On our fork of Veridian. We've been using
on our fork of Veridian. We've been using
ESSR for yeah I don't know the last like
14 months or something. The problem with
the signed header approach is that you
have your authenticity because
everything's signed by the AIDs but you
don't have your confidentiality. You
have to lean on TLS. So if the TLS
connection was compromised you lose
confidentiality. Whereas with ESSR
it's
basically your best way of combining
authenticity and confidentiality. So
sign combining encryption and digital
signatures.
It's what is used by spack and the
trust banning protocol. So Phil
implemented it in KERIpy. We've
extended it down to the API between
Signify and KERI. It looks
something like this. It's a bit I won't
spend too long on this, but it's kind of
like Winter is designed with SAM. It's
like a HTTP request tunneling kind of
thing. So the green at the top left is
the original request
Which we would send say
HTP request for put identifiers with the
body and the headers and so forth.
We serialize it into a HTTP string
and then we in we do a cryptobox seal
with lip sodium to encrypt it to the
agent AID. So only the agent can decrypt
it. Okay. Cryptobox seal is a form of
hybrid public key encryption. So for
those of you
who are aware, asymmetric keys are
incredibly inefficient at encrypting
data. it's just not really feasible.
Symmetric keys are much quicker.
symmetric keys are much quicker.
The crypto box seal from the sodium
is a form of hybrid public key
encryption which uses your asymmetric
key to derive a symmetric key
essentially. I don't know the internals
of it but it's what spack uses.
This sealed box then can become the body
this sealed box then can become the body
of a new request which we send to this
post slashinpoint.
So when we do this, every request that's
sent from Signify client, nobody knows
where it came from. They don't know what
we're even trying to do. They don't know
that we're trying to update an
identifier because it's going to post.
Only the agent will be able to decrypt
it. And in the headers, we put a
signature over this essentially. Now,
the signature needs to be over the
digest of the body, a timestamp for
replay attack protection, and the sender
and receiver AIDs. Okay.
And additionally in encrypt sender sign
rece you also have to encrypt the
sender. That's why the sender is also
a header of the original request which
was encrypted. Okay. Only then are
you fully secure from all the attacks
that Sab mentions in his spack paper.
Okay. So
yeah we've gone over the general
architecture and also gone through
the trust relationship. Now, finally,
the last kind of piece to tie it up will
be how you use KERI to interact with
the rest of the world. So up until
this point, you've basically installed a
wallet and onboarded onto your cloud
agent and done nothing else.
So,
the first thing you probably do
is create an identifier, maybe resolve a
newbie, but probably create an
identifier. In the codebase these are
known as managed AIDs because the client
AID we created earlier is only used
indirect mode to talk to your agent.
Okay, it's only for that communication.
It's not used to receive credentials,
issue credential credentials or anything
else. Okay, so
we can use the / identifiers endpoint on
KIA to create managed AIDs. Okay. And
these are
well they may be private or public but
these are AIDs you would use to interact
with the rest of the world or use in
your use case they're more userf facing.
Okay. But once again the keys remain
at the edge. Okay. Now this is a bit
technical but for those of you for those
of you who know KERIpy in KERIpy you
have a hab which represents an AID and
you can incept a hab and you can sign
with a hab and so forth. You can have
group habs. Also within KERI pie
there are Signify habs and Signify group
habs. It's just so the code knows that
the keys are not readily available. The
keys exist somewhere else at the edge.
So if you see that in the code that's
why it's that's why it exists. Now
you might be asking where did the keys
come from.
Maybe a naive approach would be to use
the passcode that we used to create the
client AID and derive more keys.
That would be problematic because of
that would be problematic because of
passcode rotation and it also would go
against what Sam said this morning of
being able to use just your KEL to
derive exactly which sequence number
on the derivation paths is required.
So actually for
so actually for
for each new AID you create you actually
create a new salt. Okay so they're fully
separated.
It's of course randomly generated by
Signify at the edge. And it's stored
encrypted on KERI. This is the default
mode in Signify.
It's of course encrypted with the client
it's of course encrypted with the client
AID. And you have a salty keeper
which tracks
you know, for this AID, what encrypted
salt does it have, what derivation pad
is it currently on, how many rotation
events is done, and so forth.
The main reason you would want to split
the main reason you would want to split
these is if you did a passcode rotation
and your one passcode had all your keys
for all of your identifiers when you
want to rotate that passcode for
whatever reason, you would have to issue
a rotation event for every single AID.
And that would get very cumbersome as
well if you also had group AIDs. You had
to coordinate that. So this way there's
a kind of a clean separation kept from
them.
You can also I think Phil had this in
his last his last presentation as
well but you can also use Randy which
means just instead of a salt which is
used to be stretched with argon 2 ID
to generate keys you can just randomly
generate keys directly and store them
encrypted in KERI. Same idea. So
this is kind of goes back to that first
slide I had where from the spec that
your key pair storage can be done
by your agent.
Now in case you don't want to sign with
now in case you don't want to sign with
Signify it.
Oh
okay. In case you don't want to sign
with Signify or expose your salt
over the internet like that, you can
also use an external source for
signing such as a HSM. This, I
believe there's a current open
PR in the community to fix that on
KERI. But you can use HSM and
directly sign all of your key events
externally.
Now once you've created an identifier so
now once you've created an identifier so
you would you know generate that
inception event generate the salt
whatever post that to KERI out
to communicate with the rest of the
world you would need to generate an
OOBI. So each managed ID can now set up
their OOBI. This is probably going to
get a bit technical now but
if you know how OOBIs work this will
make sense. If you don't, this is
probably too much information, but in
KERI nodes or whatever can have
various roles in the system such as
witness, watcher, agent, controller.
If you were to build a wallet with just
if you were to build a wallet with just
just KERIpy and not have the split of
controller, agent, your OOBI would look
something like, you know, slash OOBI,
your AID/controller.
Okay, you have the controller role by
default over your AID. But there are
other roles in the kind of ecosystem.
One is agent of course. So you may
As the controller of your managed AID
authorize your agent in KERI to
act on your behalf in the agent role
essentially. So this indicates to
everyone else in the world if you want
to talk to me direct all traffic to
the agent. the agent will handle that
essentially and this is called an
endroll authorization.
again this is a bit low level but the
agent itself needs to say where its
endpoint is which is the two 392 port.
it needs to create a signature over that
to commit to say I'm at this URL Veridian
id
whatever that's called a location
scheme in the in the code
And additionally
another thing that came out of our
pentest was actually securing the
communication not just between the
signifi client and the agent but
agent to agent. Okay.
What we've implemented on our fork is
we've added full ESSR support that's
also in line with spack and the trust
banning protocol. So all of the CESR
streams inbound and outbound
essentially wrapped in the most basic
form of the trust banning protocol.
The work for that in KERIpy I merged a
the work for that in KERIpy I merged a
while ago with Phil that's done the
KERI work I still need to open a PR
for but we'll be contributing that
back soon. And finally, this is
probably the most technical part, but
this is only if you understand OOBIs. If
you don't, then it's probably too
much, but just to kind of show the
relationship between all of the AIDs
that we mentioned today. There's
kind of six slots here. Okay, the top
one is a managed ID I created using the
admin endpoint. This is its key
event log. So this it ends in 2 zed
that's its AID. It has the three demo
witnesses from KERIpy. These are
the signatures and the witness receipts.
If you look at the very bottom I give
the end roll authorization
from
my controllerAID that ends in two set
to this endpoint AID that ends in XA. I
gave it the role of agent. Okay.
So this over here see the cursor. Yeah.
This is my managed AID. This is my
cloud agent XA.
I can also see that my cloud agent here.
It signed a location scheme to say you
can find me at this URL and no other
URL. That's how OOBIs work. It's very
very particular.
and if you look at the
one up
here, this is the Key Event Log of the
agent. You can see it's a delegated AID.
It's delegated to this AID here, which
is my client AID from the initial
sequence diagram. The second one is my
client AID KEL. And here's the
interaction event that approved the
delegation. So you can actually look in
the KEL and see the full kind of
sequence of what I mentioned end to end
essentially. But yeah that's
all I had. I think I have
seven more minutes.
So I will very quickly go back to this.
Okay. So
when we created the client AID, it had
a signing key and a rotation key
on sequence number zero.
If you were to drive more keys and do
a rotation event on that same passcode,
it would just look like a normal
rotation event where the next key
becomes the current key and there
would be a new next key that's blinded
for postquantum security. But if you
want to switch from an old passcode to a
new passcode, okay, in such a way that
you don't need to remember the old
passcode when you're done and you don't
want to because someone's going to
compromise it,
then you need to generate your new
signing key and new rotation key on the
new passcode. All right, so here's the
rotation key hashed from the new
passcode. Here's the one
from the new passcode as well. And
here's the unblinded one from the old
passcode. So if you issue a rotation
event, you have to unblind a threshold
amount of next keys from the previous
event. So this one from the old passcode
has to be here. Otherwise, it's not a
valid inception event. And this or a
rotation event, sorry. And this rotation
event has to be signed by both of these
keys. Okay? Because each new event
has to be signed by a threshold number
of new signing keys. And it also
needs to be signed by a threshold amount
of previous rotation keys. Okay, so
that's why it needs to be signed with
both of these. And the trick here
is if you look at the threshold, the
threshold is splitting away one and
zero. So the old passcode even though
the key is inside the rotation event, it
has no authority from this point on. It
has a weight of zero. It can do nothing
essentially. But it just fits the
validation logic of rotation events but
completely gets rid of the old passcode.
Okay. So it's kind of a it's a partial
rotation essentially for a single sigfer
which is kind of unique.
Yeah that's it. Any questions?
Have you have you mentioned anything
about retiring an AID? Could you discuss
that if that's okay?
Yeah, I mean it's not really
specific to KERI and Signify but
if you want to
abandon an AID as Sam calls it
You have to do a rotation event which
just sets all the thresholds to zero I
believe. So at that point there's no
more signing authority of also of the
the signing keys and the rotation
keys essentially. So it's just dead. It
can't do anything. It's called
abandoned at that point. But I don't
believe anyone's done abandoned the ids.
It's probably in KERI core and KERIpy
but it's not exposed in Signify.
So I have some questions that may
be tough for you to answer and
because I've struggled with these over a
long period of time looking for an
answer. So the one might be simple
the first one might be simple is what
could work offline in a wallet without
the agent being online.
You know can you can you sign things?
Can you issue credentials
in the current model? No. You could sign
them and cue them up, but they wouldn't
actually be effective on the network.
They need to be on the cow or tell or
witnesses, etc.
Yeah.
So, you need some infrastructure.
But you might be able to prove
you might be able to sign something, but
it couldn't be couldn't be logged
anywhere. Could you sign
something, right?
You could sign something. Yeah.
Okay. And if you're using direct mode
KERI where there's no witnesses and
watchers, then you don't need the
infrastructure level. So you
you could sign something and send it.
Yeah.
Okay. So one of one of my concerns with
KERI a in general is that to my
knowledge it doesn't support high
availability and disaster recovery kind
of modes
today. Right. So if the hard disk
crashes or sorry solid state disc drive
crashes
you're out of luck kind of on your car
server. Is that correct? And
what is what's the roadmap if any to
make it high available or you know
disaster recovery of KERI a
I have a whole talk about that tomorrow
about the
road map. Oh awesome. Okay that's a
tough question. Yeah, but it's a it's an
important one I think.
And then there's a similar question is
and then there's a similar question is
Sort of with vendor lock in. So you
you know host your own KERI or use
another one from one of the you know
QBIS or providers. What and you
have some vendor lock in at that point.
What can you do to move to another KERI
a hosted by someone else? Has that been
discussed?
Again, that's something that's more on
the road map.
Like
like
you can do that. You have control of all
the keys. More of a problem would be
the data. So, you would have to have,
you know, the previous provider would
need to be okay with moving that unless
you're going to sync down to Signify,
but it's not only it's not all available
on the KERI interfaces, right?
Yeah. But you could make it available,
right? So, that doesn't exist yet. Yeah.
what you're exact asking for it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah. But it is it is something that
we've been thinking about. It's just
again on the road map. One problem I
have with the
if it's
with this
Is if you lose your KERI instance,
you lose all of your ids. You know your
the passcode that you have that
you're entering only gives you access to
KERI essentially. So if you lose
your encrypted salts, you've lost your
AD.
I didn't realize that was
everything was that those things were
salty. I thought those were the
encryption key was also derived from the
passcode, but no, it's
the encryption key is, but having the
actual cipher text to decrypt, you know,
it's stored on KERI. So you do use
your client AID. Oh, you use using
asymmetric encryption or symmetric
encryption.
Asymmetric.
Oh,
it doesn't need to be fast. Okay. It's
just salts,
I believe. Anyhow, but these are
stored encrypted on KERI. So, if your
KERI provider went disappeared,
you've lost all your eids unless you
have backups to these.
Yeah.
the combination of you know without
redundancy of data ac you know
ideally across regions and so forth and
without this recovery it's it really
makes KERI vulnerable in production
today.
Yeah. Yeah. Well yeah there's the path
to production is kind of long
it's not really production ready at
scale or at any trust level in my
opinion and is that is that a fair
statement?
It depends. I mean we've done
mitigations on that. I mean for example
these encrypted salts are also in our
wallet
and we have our own backups of those
because
I mean okay the data is one thing like
if you lose all your ACDCs you can go
back to the issuer. Okay.
Right.
The main thing you need to keep is your
keys. You know,
it would be annoying to have to do that
and build it all back up, but
And of course our deployments have
like backups every few minutes.
And I know I know you're in on the same
channel, but just for everyone's ears,
it be nice to see road maps, you know,
from Web of Trust to say, "Yeah, we're
intending on doing these things this
quarter or whatever."
I know. Yeah. The same.
Thank you.
three minutes.
Any more questions?
Maybe one thing to mention as well is
what we are working on with regards to
migration for the road map
discussion is how the brilliant wallet
can request the cloud agent to provide a
backup file. So then you can migrate to
your own career or a different career
provider. So you can actually trigger
that
exactly
export and then as long as a career
provider is able to accept that import.
I mean this is also an element of the
GLEIF ecosystem right you can move from
QBI to QBI. So there are ways to
migrate but it does require there to be
it's also not trivial because you have
to update all the OOBIs and everything
like that and so forth. there's there's
some work to be done
but yeah it's definitely something to
think about.
Cool. But this is why we put a lot of
A lot of cost and resources into
actually how we back up the career data.
So we assume that there will be a catch
failure and we pay a lot of money to
have high availability of that data. So
for the production services that we use
in our own organization foundation and
for any clients a lot of cost goes into
high available to data center
disaster
but that is an implementation choice and
how you deploy. Are you describing
How your cloud provider and your
EC2 kind of things are set up from a
data
storage how we're making sure KERI does
get wiped
frequent snapshots
like
yes
but that isn't really a protocol based
thing
right
yeah there's no protocol issues with
KERI really it's more of an operational
thing you know that's where the gap is
immaturity you know.
But yeah, snap snapshotting is not
necessarily the most elegant way to
provide that high availability
redundancy,
especially.
No, but that's disaster recovery.
That's not for high availability.
Yeah.
Yeah. So like horizontal scaling is a
different Yeah. Tough.