So, while we let Chris find a
chair, I'm going to go ahead and start
so we can stay on time. So, one of the
things I want to ask the panel
and each one of you will get an
opportunity to answer this question.
What I want to know is if you in 2
minutes or less, could you tell us a
little about your background and
what was the specific lightbulb moment
that drove your passion in trying to fix
digital identity?
So
I don't think this is on
I turned it on, but it didn't connect
anything.
This, however, does. So
So, my
So, my background is actually kind of a
bizarre I started again with take about
an hour, so we're not going to do that.
but I think my healthcare IT
background began actually at the very
beginning of the of the exercise
we're all involved in, right? So, my
first health my first job actually
was in 1986,
which is when the 8088 was the
processor du jour. And fast forward
processor de ju re. And fast forward
processor de jure. And fast forward
about 10 years from that point when I
went through a couple of life cycles of
career, I ended up being transferred
back and ended up in the healthcare IT
space. Actually got the
My first healthcare IT job was
actually the bass player in my band got
me that job, so but actually my
original notion of why I identity is
important is really far back. It is
really actually back to the notion of my
first implementation of an EMPI, if you
know what that is. So, this is the
notion of a an enterprise master patient
index. So, the idea that you would know
who you were talking to reliably at that
point was a question of probabilism with
very little very little assuredly
about who those people were in any way.
So, pretty early on I realized that the
quality of the data that was being
collected to establish this was
poor. That their ability that actually
the organization I was working with at
the time was Kaiser Permanente Northern
California. They had a about a 30%
duplication rate in their system. And
so, your ability to actually resolve
identity was the first thing that was my
light bulb moment. My next big
opportunity then was like, I don't know,
20 some years later when I was
responsible for a national network
deployment that was the Commonwealth
Health Alliance. And again, when that
first launched, its focus was not on
healthcare information exchange, but on
identity first. Because the expectation
was this was the problem you had to
solve. You had to figure out who you
were talking about at this point and
that point. What I quickly learned is
that we were still talking probabilism
and we were still talking 20%
duplication some 20 years later. I mean,
this stuff had not gotten even a little
bit better.
So, the notion that identifiers would be
important, I think for me really began
to click when we couldn't resolve
identity.
So, getting to identity assurance
wasn't something I was thinking about. I
was thinking about the fact you just
couldn't match people or records with
people. And so, the my light bulb moment
really was around identity resolution
and that's really my was my raison
d'être. But then, now in this setting,
what we're trying to figure out is how
to make it possible for us to be sure
that people are who they say they are
when they're contracted over the
internet. This is very different problem
than identity resolution, but it has the
same core problem, which is that people
go through processes to do this
exercise, this initial exercise. The
initial exercise is the first
transaction. The first transaction is
the failure transaction. That is the
fact. So, if you can't get the first
transaction right, all other
transactions beyond that will fail.
So, this was my big aha moment. I've
been saying the first transaction for
about a decade. I think it's the most
important transaction of all. And if you
can't get the right stuff in the door
the first time, then you're trying to
match to it,
all bets are off. Not going to work.
So, that to me was my light bulb moment.
It's maybe, I don't know, 1993.
It's a good time to have it. We're just
going to do this like a slow stadium
wave. We'll just keep rolling on down.
Okay, well, I'll give it a try. I
suppose that light bulb moment for me
probably came back in
2015. I'd started with CMS. We were
working out how we were going to make
data available to
Patients, to beneficiaries. And it
was going to be done via third-party
applications, health applications that
we're seeing
pretty typically these days.
And I just asked this the
really the simple question is there a
way
that we could automate the registration?
But if we're going to do that, I really
need to be able to have some confidence
that the organization that is
presenting themselves
is who they say they are.
And so
I started this the way I seem to do
quite often. I wrote a blog.
It happened to be for HHS, and it simply
asked that question. And
that led to conversations. And I think,
Scott, we even had conversations
with the DirectTrust around is there a
way I could call an API and check with
you guys whether you know this
organization. And so that really evolved
from there
it more directly around
healthKERI areas. I
Back in back last year
again I wrote an article because I'm
thinking how do we operationalize these
APIs that
a thousand health plans are going to
have to implement and tens of thousands
of provider organizations
and I don't want these to do all this
work on
defining what these
APIs are
and have them sit there and do nothing
because that doesn't benefit the patient
whatsoever.
So how can you operationalize that?
And realizing that the manual methods we
used for patient access API
which takes
days, weeks to go through
is totally non-scalable.
And so
I asked the question
how can we have an organizational
identity that we can check?
And that sort of led me down the path to
to KERI.
And I've said.
Okay. Well, coming at it from a
completely different
Is it working now?
All right.
Thank you.
Coming at it from a completely different
[laughter]
angle.
My background is in financial services,
particularly in transaction services,
which at the time that I started
wasn't a very common or
what would I say attractive part of
financial services to go
into.
But I've spent most of my career around
identifiers
and identification.
Which is quite different than identity.
Although a good foundation and a good
basis for the way that my career at GLEIF
and my involvement in this community has
has led to.
So
come the financial crisis as I explained
before,
my background in standards led me to be
involved in the development of the LEI,
of course, another identifier.
And then it was its usage,
especially guided by
the its initial usage in order to solve
an initial problem. We want to know who
these organizations are who are
responsible for a particular function in
a particular context, just to generalize
it, basically.
And then as we started to
to operate for a few years,
in our strategic discussions at GLEIF,
we started to talk about we have a high
assurance
identifier that's global in nature, that
can identify
a very broad list of
entity legal forms or legal entities in
effect.
Because of the effort that we put into
or our partners put into validating this
identifier and the effort that
GLEIF puts in managing the global LEI
system and the quality of that system
and its operations,
why don't we look forward in order to be
able to see how we could make this
relevant in the digital world, which is
the way that the world is going?
And so this is when we first started to
get involved with the identity community
and I'll call it the identity industry,
which of course I had no idea up until
this particular point even was a thing.
And so luckily we were able to
get connected with and
be welcomed into the community by many
of the experts that we see here today,
who introduced us to the importance of
identity and not only identification but
verification, which of course led us
To wanting to be able to develop
the vLEI and then use the vLEI.
I have to say that it was an eye-opener
for me. My aha moment was actually not
as I was
day-to-day trying to be able to figure
out delivering on the strategy that my
CEO had given me in order to be able to
say, "Okay, let's make a verifiable
credential containing the LEI and
let's make it a success."
It was how clueless I was to how I was
exposing my own identity every day in
in the everyday things that I did
just as a natural person and a citizen
and how I naturally accepted anything
that people told me was secure
And was protecting my identity. I
took it just as face value.
So, Scott, you said your lightbulb
moment came in 1993.
I think I think mine came at the
exact same time. I was two.
At and I'm a little bit
tongue-in-cheek, but the truth of
the matter is that for my generation
we were born into… Now, I do remember
when we had dial-up installed in the
house. I'm not that young. But in
a real sense, I grew up in the digital
world. Like we had digital identity
before we had a term for a digital
identity. And we just accepted, you
know, in the in the halcyon days of
yore, you know, MySpace was the hot snot
and there was none of the concerns that
we had around it. But for my
generation, there's never really been a
demarcation between my identity in the
real sense in the real world and my
identity in the digital world. And so
for me it was I don't know that I ever
had a lightbulb moment. It was a
lifetime of experiences where you
know, XYZ got hacked, your credit card
gets stolen, your you know, all of these
things and it wasn't until I started
to understand some of the things that
were possible with digital identity that
I went back to this whole life that I'd
lived and said,
there has to be a better way. We
have to do something different than
what's being done now. And you know,
I mentioned this earlier, but the I
guess the coup de gras on that
system was when I just realized the
fragility of the system we've built off
of
poor identity structure and how that
could impact me as a patient.
I feel like a baby compared to this
entire group.
[laughter]
I'm a I'm a newcomer here.
I think I had three things that have
got me to this current this current
point that have I guess made me a part
of the identity movement. When I
first got into my role as chief privacy
officer, it was one of the it was the
first time the state had one. And I got
calls all the time from people that I
would sit on the phone for I think the
longest one was probably two or three
hours where I felt like I was like a
psychiatrist of they're just saying,
I've had this horrible thing happen and
I have no control.
And I've had cases where
women would call and say, my
psychiatrist literally like gave my data
to my ex-husband and now it's being
used against me in court or my data's
been breached and XYZ has happened. And
that made me realize one, people had
absolutely no control and they had
nowhere to go. Their data's been lost
and nobody was listening to them.
The next thing that built upon that
was George and I had offices close
together for years and between George
and the rest of the team, we knew
government had a big problem. If you
don't know the problems in government
right now,
there is really no data governance and
with what's happening with technology
and the transition the last 30 years,
what used to be due process rights and
ensuring you had processes that were not
arbitrary, that were not capricious,
that eliminated bias,
that is not what you have now with
technology. And so it became very clear
that if we truly believe that the basis
of government came from the individual,
and then they're the ones authorizing
government to do what they do,
but government is now just doing
whatever, you have got to have some
anchor of trust. And that was where my
first constitutional basis came from of
it's it's the individual. And that's why
I hold so strong like that to that in
the SEDI approach. And then lastly has
come of as we work to redesign
government, not just SEDI as a point at
which you engage, but what do all the
other government processes look like for
identity, for organizational identity,
to have end-to-end verifiability, to
have that provenance, and to identify,
you know, where is automated
decision-making going to fit in and
these artifacts government has to create
so you can hold them accountable, you
can't do any of that without identity
to know who are the accountable
accountable parties and who's been
wronged. So all of that together last
5 years has
for me created a essentially an
undeniable truth of we have to fix
identity or we are not going to have a
trusted government in the future.
So as you can see we have a very
passionate, well-qualified group to talk
about the elephant in all of its various
facets. So what I want to do for the
about the next 15 minutes is I want to
talk a little bit about the topic
area. So we're going to start with Chris
for the for the government perspective
and then anyone on the panel jump in to
to add additional perspective. So we can
acknowledge that public and private
partnerships are not new. Historically
their value is questioned and often
debated. We don't know if they deliver
on what they say they're going to
deliver on. So, describe for us, Chris,
how you view SEDI's engagement with the
KERI community and how that's going to
benefit all the parties involved.
Does anybody know how we started the
engagement with the KERI community?
How many actually know that inception
event? Okay. Well, let me tell you this.
It started with,
Sam and Timothy and Mike Lahey,
Sat us down in a room with Alan
Fuller and myself and a couple others
and they were like, "We have the
solution for you."
And we were like, "You are so
full of it."
[laughter]
And, and but just like
I think you'll find the whole Utah team,
we are willing to sit down and listen to
anyone. If you have a good idea, it
doesn't matter who you are, we sit down
and listen to everyone. So, we listened
and we listened and we listened and
before long,
It was a I we think there's
something here. You learn things that
you can't deny.
And so that passion from the
the KERI community and their persistence
in bringing facts to the table, we've
been very fact-driven. That's what's
impressed me is you come to the table,
you bring facts, you've educated us cuz
we weren't experts, we verify and
validate on our end, but then we've
created this reciprocal of relationship
of what are the facts, let's have an
honest discussion. I can assure you
every time we meet with any of you, we
bring in skeptics as well to challenge
it and we've had meetings where we have
Sam, we had Phil Windley and we had
Steve McConnell all in a room, you know,
kind of battling out in a way to get to
first principle truths and we've gotten
to the point now where I feel very
comfortable in just having honest
conversations and we've said everyone
else, bring mDoc, bring W3C, let's have
that conversation of how it fits
together and to me that's resulted
in how we have engaged with the KERI
community and then the basis of how
we're we're engaging going forward of
just what are the problems, what are the
facts.
And then because of that trust built,
I feel loyalty because it's was
partly created in Utah to help that
community thrive cuz there's not many
like it. And if we can scale that and
that type of engagement and truth
finding, you can do really amazing
things when you have passionate people.
Anyone else want to jump in? So
So, DirectTrust as an organization was
born out of a groundswell of
basically volunteer effort initially if
just in fact, I don't know if you
were involved in the in the Direct
Project initially or not, but
watching closely. So, the Direct Project
was like 150 different, you know,
organizations and individuals who were
involved in this exercise. It was
The idea was we need to be able to do
secure identity assured communication in
healthcare. That was the goal, right?
That was the goal. This is 2012. This is
This is coming out of
this is coming out of the HITECH Act,
which is basically legislation that
says all of the electronic health record
companies are going to get a big boon as
all of the doctors can basically get
paid to implement healthcare
systems for their for their for to move
from paper,
you know, to actual electronic systems.
And that all just really happened very
quickly. So, the Direct Project was born
kind of in that crucible, but it was a
public private partnership. So,
the first thing that we did was they
they actually were stood up within the
ONC as the as a part of the national
coordinator's work. And then the
national coordinator gave
a couple of years of support economic
support to actually stand up the
organization. And so, since
2014, DirectTrust has had no economic
support from the federal government. But
that
short period of time where we had
federal relationships, actually the
relationships have continued, but the
economic relationship has not continued.
So, we do have one aspect today,
interestingly, we've talked about this
UDAP exercise. We're talking about the
Root of Trust that's associated with
that
is a cryptographic Root of Trust that is
an X.509
based PKI framework.
And let me tell you the challenge that
we have with it. It is not
extraterritorial.
It's bound to TEFCA. It is in It is
invented and used intended only
be used in the TEFCA area. So, the
opportunity with this eLEI exercise for
us is to take something that is good
anywhere it's, you know, presented for
the same benefit of identity assurance
that a PKI framework can be used for.
So, we're intensely interested in this
exercise and very excited about
An ongoing relationship with GLEIF
and also hopefully with SEDI.
Sorry. Yeah you had Ryan Hamilton
here yesterday and he was one of the
very early organizers, along with people
like Aneesh Chopra,
Around the CARIN Alliance. Well, that
has now also evolved into It's an
accelerator within HL7. And I think HL7
itself, they those accelerators are
great example of
public-private partnership. So, really
what happens I'm retained by HL7 to
help write some of those standards for
the DaVinci project, for the
accelerator. So, we're focused around
payer-to-provider. So, I've written
payer data exchange. Well, what you see
happening there is CMS is watching. In
fact, CMS is
has a contract out there where there's a
whole bunch of contractors
that they have embedded into HL7 to help
write implementation guides to help
develop testing protocols, to help
develop the educational materials,
because the secret is you know, Congress
will go and set legislation, they'll
write a law.
The agencies then have to regulate.
Well, you can't regulate what you can't
point at. So, they really need to come
to organizations like HL7 and say
let's help you get those standards
written so we can point to them to then
get people to implement. And so, this
it's been a really
it's almost an early warning signal as
to what are they going to regulate on
next because you see where the pressure
is on to get something published.
So, I just wanted to add that GLEIF is an
ongoing part public-private partnership.
We are under regulatory oversight and
continue to be throughout our entire
existence.
And
the engagement with the public sector
being a private sector individual and
myself
started long before that actually in my
my standards role
at the international level.
And I think that being involved in
public-private partnerships and making
them work
that it's important in order to be able
to realize that bringing
viewpoints and sensitivities
and important points together
from the private sector and the public
sector
actually produces better conversation,
better discussion, better debate, and
hopefully in the end better solutions
than if it was a completely, you know,
one-sided discussion.
Also, it's sensitized me over the years
that I need to believe in, you know,
exactly what I'm putting forward and I
need to speak facts and I need to
understand
what I'm what I'm talking about and it
really sold us at life
in order to be able to decide to develop
the vLEI
when the people who
approached us and said that there's a
better way than the traditional way of
being able to do this were actually the
people who had built the previous
solution and were ready to move on.
I would maybe just add a quick
thought here which is that with regards
to public private partnership and I
think we'll get into this
from a healthKERI perspective. I've
seen what happens when the public part
of that partnership goes awry and they
just run at something on their own and
they don't you know enact
a partnership with the private market. I
think we've also seen the
alternative to that where the private
market starts to dictate terms
and I think in both cases
it is better if you get all of those
parties aligned. I think that's one of
the powerful things around
doing things like Care you that is so
you know open source open standard. It
invites the collaboration and invites
the participation and it actually
defends both sides from being able to
just run amok.
Thank you for all those answers. One of
the things that I've noticed with this
public private partnership approach that
we're taking is there's not a person we
don't talk to who realizes they're
ultimately going to be the beneficiary
of some of this technology. So we really
appreciate the fact that everyone's
putting forward the effort to say well
wait a minute.
Ultimately this is going to impact me.
How do we do it the best way and
that open discussion and that dialogue
has been super helpful for us. Well we
are at Care you con so let's take this
directly to a Care you question and this
one I'm really interested to see where
everyone goes on it. Regarding the
healthKERI industry
what is the biggest problem you see Care
you solving in the time horizon of the
next 5 years.
Anyone jump in.
Yeah, wouldn't I go first? I
we have to solve organizational identity
and the key the thing I see around
digital identity particularly for
individuals is it's all about context.
Right? So, you've got to be able to tie
those threads together.
And that's where I see how we can
implement the VLBI, the ACDCs, these
here. All of the this technology to
basically say
I'm part of this organization. I'm
allowed to do these things. This is the
type of transaction I want to be able to
to take on. You know,
I think some people already said that.
We exist in many different facets.
You know, after say I'm in
Utah in the winter, I'm a ski
instructor. So, I have a you know, I
have a an employee badge for that
and I also have one for my day job.
They're totally different, right? And
give me different permissions
based on the context of am I working
there or not. So, we have to get this
problem of being able to clearly
identify and prove and be able to root
out bad actors at the organizational
level
and relate it to individual identity as
well.
Can I Can I interject just really
quickly? 73% of all cyber attacks
that happen in the US healthcare
ecosystem come from third parties first.
The bad actors one, we're the most
targeted industry. Two, they know
exactly how to get in and that's through
the insecurity of the identities
established between parties in those
connections. I think if there is
anything that carries going to do in the
next 5 years, it's going to take that
73%
and plummet it to the ground. I think
we'll be able to solve the largest
problems in that connectivity. And
something like 60% of providers that are
hit by a ransomware attack go out of
business. Yeah, so I can tell you also
just from So, we also accredit
healthcare organizations for their
cybersecurity capabilities. And
as we review the activities of
folks in post-breach world, what happens
what you find out is most of the
breaches are caused by the use of an
actual a credential that is actually a
valid credential. So, you're talking
about people who are using someone
else's credential
for nefarious purposes. And once they
get in that initial door, they're able
to then use
AI, for example, to get
to traverse the entire network
once they're inside. So, from my
perspective, being able to move the
entire healthcare ecosystem from weak
credentials
to a model that is actually
password-free would be the biggest thing
we could do for the workforce in
healthcare. I think that's up That would
be the best outcome.
I also think that in general that
the world needs a veracity engine
and we don't have one.
[laughter]
So, there needs to be a veracity
engine. So, when I appear online, when I
appear online in any context, like when
I'm talking to you over Zoom, you should
be able to see who I am, that I am who I
say I am, reliably. And that should be I
think and that's if I want my
I need to be shared. And like these
things I think are so important to
establish. I think the policy focus is
really important though. If the policy
doesn't happen right, I think this is
what Utah has done so well. You know,
first principles, policy first. I think
that has a huge impact.
I'm going to give a slightly different
answer here. It's going to be
controversial.
This is from the policy perspective
of what needs to be done in 5 years to
actually get lots of money put into the
ecosystem and to align interest with
policy makers to get them to run
legislation and actually get the market
going cuz we've had breaches and
security and lack of trusted identity
and provenance for decades and it hasn't
fixed the issue. What is the one topic
everybody's talking about now and
pumping money into and it's AI? And so
if you want to solve all of these
problems, you've got to tie it to some
AI use case which is where all the money
is going. And so Utah did something
really unique and this is just for
everyone to think about as you're
working on the problems.
They have been in national news
because they did the first automated
prescription issuance from AI
Coming out of our regulatory sandbox.
So Utah's created some really unique
things to allow new
AI to be used. We know in this room what
KERI and ACDC is going to bring to the
AI ecosystem in terms of provenance
and then associated to data or to AI
agents having being delegated with
authority to act on somebody's behalf.
And so I think it's critical to tie
in some of these unique capabilities to
AI and not show that we're reducing
fraud or losses but to show some
efficiency gains or things that directly
impact individuals. So if you can start
saying because we have we proven,
you know, verifiable delegation for this
agent acting on another doctor's behalf
to start streamlining prescription
issuance and lowering cost, that's going
to get people excited. And if we can
prove the use of this technology over
the next I don't think it's 5 years, I
think it's the next 3 years,
that is going to start turbocharging the
the digital identity and verifiability
approach.
Okay, who in the room just registered
KERI.ai? Did that Did that just happen?
Okay. Jared, go ahead.
[laughter]
I mean, yeah. I agree with what
Chris is saying and really my
thought there is that
this is a problem that can't wait
and this is a problem that people should
be thinking about and working on
already. And what I guess what I what
what I'll say is while we haven't moved
some of the work we're doing at Health
Caery around AI into open source, I
mean, we probably won't in the near
term. We definitely want to entertain
conversations with folks that look at
that and see it as a problem the same
way Chris does.
And I will say to do what I just said,
you already have to do everything you
just said. It's just what's the story
you're going to tell and that's an
amazing story to tell that will get
people to put more money into it.
So Carl, I'm going to lean on your
organizational experience that you've
had.
Given what you've seen in creating
verifiable organizational identity, what
do you anticipate is going to be the
practical friction or challenges that
healthcare organizations are going to
encounter going through this process?
And then, panel, listen up. My question
to you would be is how do we help
mitigate those issues?
Well,
to begin with,
I think that
the first thing is that
people are used to doing things or not
doing anything at all or doing things a
different way. So, there's going to need
to be a change in behavior.
And the reason why the change in
behavior is going to need to be
explained to them.
And that's a challenge for us.
Not to get into the technical details.
To focus on the user experience and
what the benefits are in order to be
able to target whether it's doctors,
whether it's patients, whether it's
payers and the plans. As we've we've
been speaking with Health Caery and
we've been speaking with DirectTrust.
I'm learning more and more about the
healthcare industry and the fact that
there are
data inconsistencies,
efficiencies that need to be
exploited
and identity and verifiable identity is
at the core of all of these things.
And for us to be able to leverage what
we've already
created and
to see this applied in this way, to be
able to take a problem
and say, we can look at our process that
we have here
and we can explain to our members that
they're going to want to see their
credentials registered in the provider
registry so that it reflects the real
situation in the world,
I think is an improvement. In order to
be able to
to
also apply the
the credentials to the plans.
And so you know who is associated with
what plan and also to just disambiguate
the providers themselves. I go back
to the example that Scott gives to say
which St. Mary's is it.
And
you know, we had
I guess the answer kind of like sitting
there in the LEI repository
and we are glad in order to be able to
know that there is another industry and
another domain that can benefit from the
same kinds of principles that we
wanted to promote in the first place.
I did want to just say,
if you
you asked the question about barriers,
like so what's going to keep us from
being successful? I think
I'm new to KERI. I think KERI is
incredibly interesting and exciting, and
I'm a kind of a
propeller head, but not
not my propeller is kind of just drawn
in crayon. But so but I what I've got
to tell you is that
that KERI's going to have the same
challenge that the X.509 community has,
which is y'all speak Eldish.
And so
you're going to have to translate this
into English, and really quickly,
because if you're going to try and bring
this to market,
we're going to have to start using words
that people understand. And we're
going to have to de-acronymify
because in this day and age,
I can tell you, we merged with an
organization called ENACT, and when we
did, we went and we de-acronymified
everything, cuz all their programs were
four-letter acronyms. I'm telling you,
this is really not a
2026 kind of a thing. This is a That's a
1995 thing, right? So, acronyms are big
in technical space, because you can't do
these things without them, because you
can't You can't describe something
technical in short words. Germans, of
course, just put words together. But
I'm telling you that this is, I think,
our biggest barrier.
What I heard some people explain here,
actually, I think it was a legislator,
it's hard to explain.
And I think that's that's probably our
biggest barrier is that we have to be
able to describe it very succinctly, and
with value proposition in mind, and with
words that people understand. That's If
there's a barrier here, that's the
biggest one.
Yeah, and so I agree. I
think clarity in
language is the biggest hurdle. If we
can get to clarity of language, we solve
a lot of problems. I think the second
biggest hurdle,
And then the solution, honestly, is
money. And I wish that wasn't the case.
I wish we could talk about healthKERI
being this folderol, and everybody
wants to be, you know, for the patient.
The reality is this industry is not
going to move unless there's money
attached to it. And that comes in two
forms. One is if companies like
Healthcare can come and improve out a
model that carried drives dollars for
companies like us, then a lot of
different ecosystem players are going to
come in. It's going to be new startups
competing with us on our level. It's
going to be people that are established
in the space that want to come in and
start doing what we're doing. But if we
can show money, we can move the market.
The other side of this is for the
customers the groups that will be paying
for these new services, they need to see
money as well. For them likely, they
will see that in two forms. It's going
to be a reduction of cost or an increase
in business. If they can prove that
they're more trustworthy, they can
capture more customers. If they can do
this automatically, they will save on
COGS. So, I think it's it's both the
biggest barrier and if we can solve it,
we'll be the biggest activator because
people will forgive your language
if there's a big pile of money behind
your acronyms.
So, one industry that does not get rid
of their acronyms is the legal industry
and those terms and conditions don't get
any smaller and I do think we can move
the industry and I said this at the
steady summit
is what's the regulatory framework to
incentivize all these experts,
technologists, and the legal
departments to move this way and so
some of our tools would be like the
reciprocal verifiability. You want
organizational identity, we're going to
require them to do reciprocal
verifiability. Who is the org? Who is
the individual? That sounds like well,
it's a cost. Who's going to do this
then? But then we say, well, if you do
this, here's the limitations now on
liability. Here's the safe harbor to
function and we give them the incentives
to move toward reciprocal verifiability
and to use tools that have the
capabilities KERI provides and that
should take away enough liability or
provide enough incentive for them
to at least start in their
transformation to move this direction.
And especially when we start tying that
to AI, I think this is a perfect
example. We say, "Your AI agent must
have, you know, some verifiable form to
say that they're acting on behalf of the
entity and who provided that
delegation." And if you do this, then
you can be in the sandbox in Utah. Those
are the incentives that I think
regulators can help with to move
things.
I want to pull a few threads together
here. The yes, we need to speak in very
plain language to folks as to what
they what we're trying to do. The
problem is yes, legal and government
love their acronyms. So, we've got to
also meet them there.
What we need to do is really think about
don't make it too complicated.
And also try and tie it back to things
they understand.
Jokingly tell a story about how I
actually got blue button built at CMS
and got it out through ATO, their
authorization to operate, so that it
went out and into the into the
marketplace.
And I say, "I basically designed the
project so nobody had to make a
decision,
right? So, that you always could point
to precedent so that they could say,
'You've already done that.'"
And if you look at if you were listening
to what we were saying this morning,
a lot of what we've done there is to
say, "This is just a small change on top
of what you're doing already. It's the
same type of technology. It's just a
different cryptographic key, right?" So,
that you able to make help them make
the intellectual jump.
One other thing to consider is what is
the use case you're building for? We've
had many verifiable credential companies
come in from KERI and every space
and they're selling a product for a use
case which is not the low-hanging fruit
that's needed. And so there are many
entities with really smart people if you
simplify what you're doing enough but
hit that right use case and there's some
out there. This isn't the healthKERI
industry but we had we had Maverick in
here on the first two days of the steady
summit and they actually said, "Hey, if
you one, we've already made steady
legal for purchase of alcohol and
tobacco." And they said, "Well, if you
have the implementation guide, we could
have this implemented in 6 months and
we'll start accepting steady." And
that's cuz there is a product market fit
there that perfectly aligned with the
protocol we're looking at for steady. So
what are the right healthKERI use cases
as well when and we don't need the whole
platform. I think it's what's that to
get you in the door to show value and if
you do that, then you can build from
there. Yeah.
Fant- fantastic point and you're
right. This is all tying together. I
love when a when a panel just leads
towards that natural conclusion. For me,
it's let's talk about the ultimate
stakeholder in the healthKERI industry
and that's the patient. We know that the
trust is broken in terms of the personal
data and the protections around it. We
say HIPAA a lot but that doesn't mean
anything when you're lying in the
hospital bed and
we do have some representation on here
from people who are in government or
who've done some pretty remarkable
things with government regulation trying
to help the industry move forward. So if
you can give me your closing remarks
individually and if you had the magic
wand that you could change one
regulation or add something at a state
level or a federal level that could
really kickstart everything in the right
direction, what would that be?
Well, I'll tell you know, CMS is the
is the organization that has the biggest
hammer. They're I mean their hammer is
actually
is it a spoon with sugar in it or is it
hammer? I don't know which, but it's
very, very, very authoritative and
powerful. So, they their two their two
opportunities are reimbursement
and
Regulation. So, when they regulate,
Regulation. So, when they regulate
they
you know, if for instance, they were to
require
provider organizations to all have FEAL
eyes in order to get into the national
directory,
it would be an instant driver.
And this is a national directory
they're trying to build that is
failing on the subject of organizational
identity.
So, this would be a huge opportunity for
them. There's they haven't
learned to say GLEIF yet. They call it
GLEEF. They are confused. So, I
I'm trying to bring them forward and say
once they can pronounce it, I'm hoping
that they can also support it.
It's a tough one. I
I think I've moved beyond this, but back
when I was with CMS sort of 2017,
2018, there was a lot of talk about
Medicare for all.
And I was saying, "No, no, let's Why
don't we just start with Medicare
registration for all? So, that you got a
standard ID that you could take." And I
I've sort of moved beyond that to say
what I would love to see is probably
regulation that says,
"If I as a patient
present an identifier or an identity to
a practitioner, to an organization in
healthKERI,
you should damn well put that into my
record
so that
Yeah, so that it then starts as you as
they start sharing data and you go to
more and more places, you can actually
patient match. I had a colleague
in the ideal lab at CMS who was there to
do patient matching.
You'll know who he is if he ever sees
the video. Yeah, and
I would always every time I went to see
him
see him I'd say, you know, patient
matching is so much easier when you
involve the patient.
So I haven't become a healthKERI expert
overnight. So
I'm going to take a little bit of a
different tack here.
I would like to be able to see any law
going forward that
involves identity
in order to be able to come at it from
what are you trying to accomplish? What
benefits are you trying
to gain? So what features then do you
need in order to be able to have in a
solution?
Or to have the law be principle-based.
If you have need for
to be able to protect for example
children or elderly parents, do you
need delegation?
Are you trying to be able to
instantiate or give credentials in order
to be able to know the real situation of
authority within a company in the area
of organizational identity
then you're going to need a feature in
your in your identity solution that
gives you that. What level of assurance
to know that it's really the person who
is supposed to be able to be
authorized to get that credential? Do
they have that role? What level of
security am I comfortable with?
Do I need automated verification? Those
types of things. And when you answer
those questions the law then gives you a
guideline or a road map
in order to be able to pick
a good solution. And for me, I think
that changing the dynamic of
being able to come at the law in
that way would be an advantage.
So I've been looking around the room and
I'm pretty certain that our friends from
Libertas are no longer here.
So I think I'm safe to say this without
getting a water bottle checked to my
head.
I would
at this point if I could wave a magic
wand
I would get rid of section 510 from the
HHS
labor bill. That section of that law
made it essentially
illegal for the federal government to
issue a national patient identifier.
And I agreed with all of the reasons
that law was in place in terms of
privacy and the concerns for patients up
until very recently with some of the
work that's been happening with SEDI and
other initiatives. And so now today
knowing that I that we have
a way to do that national patient
identifier that is privacy preserving,
that manages to keep the patient in
charge of themselves digitally,
I think that should be repealed
immediately. And again, if Connor or
Jason from
Libertas see this, we can talk later
about the implications.
This is an unfair question for me.
[laughter]
What would you like to do?
Cuz
there's this bad thing that happens when
I say what we want to do in regulation
then I have to make recommendations.
It ends up happening.
Now some of this I've said
big picture we know privacy and security
is broken in the country. The amount
of correlation happening with your data
and how that profiling and the
scoring and predictive analytics is
occurring in every sector, private
sector, public sector, healthKERI,
social services, education. You would be
amazed in this room and we have seen me
and George have seen these systems. And
so I'm coming at it from a different
perspective of what is coming from the
private sector industry and how that
would be used to exploit for
monetary or the public sector side to
try to influence you to make
different decisions.
I had seven years of experience in
privacy and security with human
services in Utah and I know HIPAA does
not work and the levels of
non-compliance for both privacy and
security. There's maximum use of data,
but these other things are viewed as
just hindrances or there's not the
expertise to do.
So my
And I think this was alluded to
on the legislative panel on the
steady summit. What I am working
toward is
I think there needs to be a total
rewrite of the approach. And so our
goal is that you know, starting with
identity
end-to-end verifiability and zero trust.
Move toward the duty of loyalty
model where anybody with your data
should be acting in your best interest
and this cross all industry. This
crosses healthKERI, this crosses
financial. And if you're aligned with
that end-to-end verifiability, we
modernize the laws for provenance
requirements, we figure out, you know,
how to track these terms,
Then we will be creating also some
extreme safe harbors for entities to act
To work within knowing mistakes are
going to happen, but I think that will
create a more balanced free market and
set us up for coming in the age of
of AI and automation, but anything
absent a total overhaul
for both public and the consumer
side,
it's going to be a very fragmented
disparate market and the public is going
to be confused and businesses are going
to struggle to maintain our economic
dominance that we have here in the US.
So, since Chris pulled me in by saying
I'd seen some of this stuff, too, I'm
just going to say, yes, that's true. I
mean, it's there have been many times
when we've effectively done our
architecture reviews and opened up a
system just to find that it has a
digital hamster wheel still spinning and
we have needed to change and some of
that's going to be in behavior, as we've
talked about, and the incentives need to
be there to help us with the change.
So, as we started this day out, Sam had
made a bold statement that this is the
potentially the year of KERI. I think
from what we've heard from this panel,
that's been corroborated. So, Sam, put
one more in the win column. Can we have
a round of applause FOR OUR PANEL?
[applause]
THANK YOU.