So everyone, I'm George McEwan. I'm the
privacy architect for the state of Utah.
So there's a lot of synchronicity that
happens when you go to these various
events. And amazingly enough, I'm going
to talk a little bit about healthcare in
the rural healthc care setting and why
we look at it the way we do. So one of
the things I'm going to make very clear
is that the state is going to declare
some boundaries in what it does in the
KERI infrastructure and what the
expectations are for the community
because one of the things we learned as
I was the IT director during the COVID
era at the department of health there
was definitely some resistance to where
government had offered the technologies
or applications or worked with platform
providers to provide things like
exposure notification and the backlash
was very intense. That's
probably the best word I can use. And so
we realize that where government can
help and we can set regulations and we
can set frameworks in play, there's
definitely a spot where the government
has an edge and we say this is private
sector and for the individual to handle.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
run you through a little bit of a
presentation that we do with we'll
call them non- nerds, normal people.
Because we can talk in shorthand in the
because we can talk in shorthand in the
SEDI community and in the KERI
community and cyber security. We have
words they don't understand. So, what
we've did is we put together kind of a
generic presentation that we add slides
to depending on who we're talking to.
So, realistically, we hit them on these
points. Digital identity is here. It's
coming. It's going to be something. Now,
one of the I would say the beauties of
the SEDI program is Chris Bramwell
said, "Well, we could take this and
put this against what are the
constitutional rights that someone has."
And by doing so, you get past all of the
vendor needs to make money. You get you
get right down to the root of the
problem, which is there needs to be
accountability and that your rights need
to be preserved and that privacy is not
impossible when you are talking about
digitally issued credentials. And of
course then we get into our the stakes.
If the government doesn't choose or
regulate, the market does it itself. And
the goals of a open market are a
little bit different than what a
government needs to be providing the
services that a citizen would want. And
of course, we know that besides
governments, there's also organizations
that put together specifications that
may or may not be rooted in the same
value system that we're trying to
maintain. So we're very adamant that we
want to make sure that whatever we do in
the SEDI environment, it's reflective of
the values, goals, and rights that are
held here in America. Now, it is not
hard for this statement to be believed
by all of you, right? Whoever has the
data has the control. And the model
right now, everything to the left or
sorry, my right everything over there
is how we work today. Your identity is
owned by other individuals. It's granted
back to you with limited rights. And
then if you've ever looked through all
those long user licenses, in effect,
you've given up all control for the
services that you that you have. And
this isn't limited to just, hey, I got
myself an email address for free. Your
financial institutions do this. your
hospitals and your HMOs, your care
organizations, they're holding a lot of
the data that belongs to you. And
because it's set up that way, you are
basically powerless to do anything about
it. And in a lot of cases, you'll find
that incorrect data may be used in
profiling you to create an improper
picture of who you are.
So really what we want to accomplish
inside the study framework is the idea
that you are the individual who controls
that information because whatever the
wherever the information sits it is fair
to say without contradiction that
impacts the financial outcomes. It
impacts your opportunities. There are a
lot of things that get impacted because
you don't control what should
rightfully be yours. And this is not to
say that everyone did it for a nefarious
purpose. I mean, profit-seeking motive.
We're a capitalist society. Yeah, that's
understood. But the problem is we built
everything to be so exploitative of you
that we forgot that you are the
individual who ultimately gets hurt if
something goes wrong. In the state of
Utah, inside government, there's a
there's a very good way that we look at
data. When we make a data error in
government, it's a negative outcome for
a real person. Classic example, oh the
Medicaid eligibility system, which is a
real time system, goes down for a couple
hours. Now, if you're standard IT,
you're like, big deal. Things happen.
We'll get it back up. No big deal. But
then when the Medicaid director marches
in with their flesh hook and rips a
pound off of you and says, "Right now,
somewhere in Utah, there is a single
mother who took two buses two hours out
of their day to go to the pharmacy to
get medication for pain management." and
the pharmacy directors at that
facility said, "We can give you one pill
because we can't confirm your
eligibility. You'll need to come back."
That's the sort of situation we deal
with when we talk about our data errors.
And of course, we try very hard in
government to be good stewards of that
data. But realistically, if the
individual has a lot more control, who's
a better advocate than you? You are
definitely going to be your best
advocate.
Now, when we get into the concepts of
state endorsed digital identity, we
really try to keep this as simple as
possible. And this is this is probably
way too high. And everyone's like,
"Yeah, I get this slide immediately."
But what we try and explain to them is
those core concepts that we put into the
bill of rights that identity is yours.
It's not issued by the state, but the
state has a role to endorse it for
certain legal purposes. And of course,
we get into the concept of what is a
digital identity? how does it get
created a little bit and then we go into
the whole idea of how it becomes your
state endorsed digital identity through
this process of vetting. Now there are
some potentially debatable questions on
here. U we don't get into the politics
of this but we do know that there are
some markers that need to uniquely
identify you to be part of that digital
identity. And this isn't to say that
these are forever attributes. For
example, your address, your biometric of
your face, those are going to change.
And we have existing laws that handle
that. So, for example, if you are
getting a driver's license 16, that's
not valid for more than 5 years because
we know you're going to change by the
time you get to college. And of course,
with the residents here in Utah who have
driver's licenses who are over 18, it's
a 10-year window. So there are
opportunities for those things to be
changed as part of the credential or to
For lack of a better term lose the
endorsement.
Now when we talk about healthcare data
there are a ton of different places
where this applies. Now we had
healthKERI talking about the provider
payer relationship. That's just one of a
myriad of relationships that exist
between you and your healthcare
interactions. Whether that's the
ownership of your individual data, your
desire to participate in some sort of
demographic mapping. Today, today we
don't do that. Today we have systems
that basically at government control
take your data and aggregate it for
research purposes.
And for some people, that's not
shocking. But when you when you go to a
state and you say, "Hey, do you have an
All-Payer Claims Database?" If the
person's in the no, that means that
every encounter you have that's part of
your insurance program in that state
with your physician and the notes
associated with all your ICD10 codes,
everything that happened during that
medical encounter is now in a government
database for the purposes of looking at
healthcare outcomes. Did patient A and
patient B who received different
medications, which one had the better
outcome? So there's a lot of good
intentions in terms of why these data
sets exist. But I will also tell you the
most dangerous thing in government is a
well-meaning bureaucrat. It's not that
they're trying to do something
nefarious, but sometimes they try and
get hold of data and put it together to
create a picture. Well, where you don't
have any interface to this and you don't
have any control over that data, there's
the possibility that inference,
that conclusion may help you, it may
harm you. So this is part of the reason
we want to start looking at how we
switch this model around so that you
have more executive control and how your
digital twin story gets told.
Now when we talk to them about the state
endorsed digital identity, we also like
to help people understand this
concept of perpetual identity. And this
is where we differ with the mobile
driver's license community and they're
saying you can use it for everything.
I'm like, you can use it for everything
that you don't mind having burned down
if you move to a new state. That's
totally fine. But in our particular
instance, we want to be able to say that
there are certain documents that you may
associate with your SEDI and they
could be your medical records, you know,
your digital driver's license. Any of
these items that you have associated
with your SEDI can be created and you
may have information that you are going
to selfassociate like, hey, here's my
claims history. Here's some of my MRI
scans, things that you have in your
possession that you want to get into
your digital records but currently
don't have. And this is where these
functionalities like blue button are
fantastic is you have the ability to say
this is categorically my MRI. I'm going
to send it to you electronically. You
can pull it directly into my into my
record set. That's the level of control
that we want to have. not go to doctor
office A, pay $50 for a doc fee to have
them really, it still cracks me up, fax
information to doctor B, and then
hopefully they didn't lose anything in
translation and the whole packet's
complete, which you generally find out
on your next medical appointment that
it's not somebody dropped pages 8
through 12, and now you got to go
through this whole cycle again. So, we
have these inefficiencies that are in
the system the way we run it today. And
we're telling people, no, if once you're
in control of this, you can start to
aggregate your data as necessary. And of
course, we talk about the concept of
perpetual ownership. If I move from Utah
to Texas, there are certain privileges
that go away. I don't keep a Utah
driver's endorsement anymore. I have to
go get a Texas one. But everything else
that I had associated with my SEDI is
still valid. And in fact, because I have
a SEDI that's authorized by Utah or
endorsed by Utah, Texas can say, "We
know that's Utah. So, we're going to
accept these baseline facts that you've
asserted. We can bring you right into
the system and we can move on." And hey,
guess what? You can go get your Texas
driver's license endorsement without all
the reproofs that we have to do along
the way.
So when we looked at SEDI as a
functional item, we wanted to build into
the framework some very important
principles. And of course you can see
them up here. We break them into some
general categories. Now this is where I
want you as KERI experts to start
ticking off in your mind which one of
these items are solved by KERI, which
one of these ones are actually enhanced
by KERI, and also when we get to the
end, I'm going to give you a little
here's what we're not going to do at the
state level. Okay? So privacy and
autonomy this is pretty straightforward.
We want you to have interactions with
your digital identity that the
government does not monitor has no
capability to and also third parties.
We do not want crossontext correlation.
We want you to have individual
relationships and as such there are
technologies that will do that. Funny I
think there's one in the room here
that might do that. We do want you to
have this capability of selective
disclosure. I was telling Mike a
story where I went to my grandkids,
picked them up for a fun day out and we
went to a trampoline place and the first
thing they did was get grandpa to sign a
liability waiver. And as I was looking
at it, I first thing I thought is, you
do not need my birthday. You just need
to know that I'm old enough to enter
into a release of liability. And I kind
of sparked because not only would that
be a problem, I don't actually have
permission for my daughter to release
liability for her children. So there's
some other things that could get cleaned
up in that situation, but this is part
of the community education. This is the
open sourcing of privacy we hope to have
happen is I'm not going to have every
single interaction where I'm going to be
able to ask why, but we do want to get
people and just across the world saying,
"Do you really need that for this
transaction?" And that's part of where I
say in keeping with what Chris has
said, a 10-year journey. Now, if you
think back in cyber security, how long
did it get people to understand the
Nigerian prince scam before we could go
on to that's a fishing email and then
that became part of the lexicon that
people use? It took a long time. I
call it about a 15-year window just
going back over my history and saying,
"Yeah, it's about when we got people to
understand it." And still we fall for
these things. But this is the same
journey we're going to be on with
selective disclosure. We have to get
people understanding. No, no, no. You're
in the driver's seat. You don't have to
give up this information to be able to
receive services. Now, there's a major
medical provider that I'm not going to
mention them by name, but when you go in
to receive services, they give you this
great set of disclosures. And one of
them is basically a blanket that says
you're seating all your rights for all
your data that we may use in research
purposes including biological samples.
We don't have to notify you. And by the
way, if you don't agree to this, we're
not treating you. That is scary that
they have that capability. But as we get
a community that's becoming more savvy
about these things, not just small
groups like us, but the larger
community, we can affect change and make
those policies flat out illegal. Okay?
And of course, one of the things that I
do want to mention is personas in the
term that we're using it in is basically
helping people understand. You don't
have to stand there at the counter and
pick element A, element B, element.
There are certain transactions you're
going to have that are going to be
standard. You know, if you if you go to
a bar or you might have a pub crawling a
persona that says, "Here's my name,
here's my face, and here's when I want
you to cut me off and call the Uber for
me." That's going to be something that
we would expect the wallets to start
supporting is how do I map these things
very quickly so I can get to through
the interaction as frictionally
frictionless as possible.
So we get the next one going. Okay, I
talked a little bit very fast about
delegation and guardianship the other
day. Probably faster than I should have,
but we'll talk about it some more.
Delegation and guardianship is one of
the most critical relationships that we
see both from a government and a
societal capability. From a government
standpoint, there are multiple programs
that operate based on the relationship
that a parent has to a child a
caregiver to a foster child. You can you
can go down the litany of them and
you'll find there's a lot. In the story
I told yesterday about getting a durable
medical power of attorney for my
father while he was basically passed out
on the bed. He doesn't really remember
that. And there are situations where he
may want to rescind that. How does he do
that? All we've got is a scroll on a
piece of paper that I can guarantee you
is not his signature, but it will hold
up in court because a notary came, took
400 bucks in hash from me and said,
"Yep, he had a positive
acknowledgement of what happened." So,
when we have these situations of where
we have vulnerable individuals who need
assistance or you have an aging adult
who quite frankly need you to help them
with their finances and other
items, it's really cumbersome today.
And I've had to do this for one relative
and I've had to do this for one relative
where we had to bring the court order
down to the bank and then they went
through this whole trust and
verification proc process. They called
the courts. They wanted the make
sure that the all the numbers matched
up on the case and everything. It was
ridiculous. And it and fortunately, they
only had one bank. I was thinking, what
if they had like an investment portfolio
completely separate and that investment
company isn't even in my state? I
got chills on how long that would take
me to help them out. And with the
technologies that KERI is providing,
there's the ability to really do that
quickly through these the these designed
and delegated guardian relationships.
And as I mentioned in that little
vignette yesterday that all my brothers
and sisters were sitting around the
table arguing,
I realized there's six adults here that
could come to some consensus on what is
best for the situation. And it would be
in the interest of my father or my
mother to have us have that sort of
capability. So multi- signature to be
able to authorize these activities.
Totally important. Now we talked a
little bit about agentic AI. It's
coming. I'm playing with a lot of
them. They're still in my little
sandbox, but some of them are getting
more useful. And one of the things that
I would find extremely useful is I was
playing around with Open Claw and I
decided I wanted to
implement Geminis's or Google CLI
and it's like well I usually ask Grock
how to do that but I thought I would ask
Gemini directly and it came up with this
big fat don't do that is a
violation of our policies and terms and
conditions and we will shut you down no
ifs ands or buts you know bad you.
And I realized as I thought through what
would have been the implications of
losing my I call it my burner account,
but I have not dozens, I have hundreds
of logins that are tied to that.
Hundreds of logins. So if that company
decided to take it away from me, I would
break my digital life in more ways than
one. So
here's your product placement idea. If
anyone wants to add this, I would love
that once my SEDI goes live that I have
the capability to go and break all those
relationships automatically and
reassociate them with an identity that I
physically control. That's where I want
to end up because at the end of the day,
if we leave all those accounts and logins
out there, we're seeding our power to
control our own destiny. And of course,
we've talked about the permission and
consent the demo for KERI blocks.
some of you might have seen at IIIW was
fantastic. For those who didn't, and
I'll just give you the two-minute
overview, the goals are the same.
Parents do not want their children in
environments where there are predators.
And we know that there are online
communities that despite their best
efforts, wink the profit
motive is still there. So, they're not
investing in the technologies that will
protect children. And in this particular
example, we had a parent credential,
a SEDI based credential that did a
derivative credential for their child
and said, "This is my child. This they
are 13 and they can be on this system
from 5 to 7:00 p.m. two nights a week
and they can only talk to other children
who have a validated study credential."
And it's fun to watch the chat window
and all the people disappear who are not
able to talk to your child. Now, some
people think that's that's overly
restrictive. You're going to have your
genius child get around it anyway. That
is where we do have that interface
between technology and law. Especially
in Utah, we've talked a lot about the
harms to children through social media
and other ways. I don't think it's it's
going to be too much of a stretch once
the technology is ubiquitous to have
the law catch up to help parents
manage their children's online
environments. Okay. Security and
recovery. One of the things that when I
read Sam's paper for the very first
time, I was like, "Okay, why is it that
we've been doing PKI this way for like
25 years at this point and nobody
figured out this really obvious thing,
which is if you can't tell what the key
state is and where you're going next,
you're back to that whole trust model
and all the things we did to make CA's
work and the intermediate certificate
and by the way, get rid of this one."
And I was like, Sam, it was genius how
simple it was when you looked at it, but
it was like it was one of those things
that until somebody came up with that
answer, we were going to still suffer
from the same problem. So where KERI
has done a lot of things to help us out
and of course like Sam and I have talked
about this over the last three years
about detection of compromise, the KERI
specification continues to get
updated to meet the real world
demands that we have. And one of those
is this whole idea of the mutual
authentication. We've just talked about
that with the phones. We've talked about
that with healthcare providers. And I
will predict something that is going to
be in the future. So we have health
information networks all across the
United States. And they make a lot of
money brokering the transaction or
uplifting it from one EDI format to
another. What a world it would be is if
I'm the provider and I can reach out
directly to a discovered payer
interface. we have this mutual
authentication and I can just move that
significantly changes the overhead that
a provider office has to have. I mean I
I know that my dentist for example he
has
about nine administrative personnel.
He's one dentist with two hygienists but
he does a lot of work in social
services programs and he has to have
that level of people to continue to keep
up with the paperwork. And of course
that's kind of reflected in his pricing.
So every couple years he goes off plan
and I have to pay more to use his
services. But if we could get those
administrative burdens lowered, think of
where we could go.
No credential works unless there's
comprehensive utility. One of the
long-standing jokes about the mobile
driver's license is that it works at the
TSA. Well, it doesn't. Their terminals
are down. They're like, "Well, hey, do
you have your physical license?" And
I've heard this one myself because that
interaction will go a lot faster than
trying to play around with the terminal.
So it doesn't have a lot of usability
and the models were wrong.
One of those models was is we tried to
monetize in the wrong way or at least
vendors did. In our case the
our we're an alcohol control state. So
you have to go to a state liquor store.
But when you are the director of the
state liquor store and a vendor comes to
you and says, "Hey, by the way, I need
you to pay X number of dollars per month
per store to be able to accept this
digital credential." And they're like,
"Wait a minute. Isn't that issued by
public safety?
Why do I pay money to public
safety or to a vendor to accept a
credential that the state issued?" And
of course, their answer was so logical.
Well, I can look at the I can look at
the state ID or I can look at the
driver's license for free. So adoption
is a problem. There are a numbers of
areas where we hope to see functionality
come along like I talked about replacing
username and passwords or taking over
accounts. We want to make sure that this
area which is where the ACDC comes in
great is offline verification. I can't
have my environment completely breaking
because I don't have online access at
all times. Now, Joe Jackson during our
our study panel, he talked about our
offhighway vehicle OV certificate
that we did. And when Joe and I talked
about it, I said, "Joe, this is fine for
X509 technology. Completely fine. It's a
lifetime endorsement. It's never
revocable and you have to supply a
primary credential with it. So, just
because you show the QR code and it has
your information embedded in it, you
have to show a driver's license." So we
said, let's go down the road with this
one because we want to make sure that
there's an appetite for these
credentials and that it would be
extremely low risk. So Joe told you a
little bit about and things we've
learned along the way there. But I'll
tell you what, the funniest thing that
happened is once we release those, the
boating community, everyone who's owns a
boat, I've heard this story like 40
times now. They're like, I own a boat
and you guys have this OHV thing that I
could have on my phone. Why do I have to
have a printed PDF? And they always say
paper on my boat. We're in the water.
Why do I have to have paper? So, we kind
of smile and say things are coming. The
the appetite is there for these
credentials. We have no loss of ideas
and use cases of where we want them to
go. Key to the whole success is the open
standards, no vendor lockin.
We have been very clear to the community
that security by obscurity is never
going to be a solution we're ever going
to be interested. Somebody brings me a
closed source package and says it's
magic, I don't believe them. I want to
see under the hood and in some cases I
lack the time these days, but if I can
get down into the code and look at A
plus B does equal C, I get a lot more
comfortable. And I try to point out to
non-technical people, the reason Apache
is such a successful project and how has
the high level of security it does is
there's lots of people looking at it and
that's where we need to be in identity
systems and identity credentials because
I can tell you across this room and I
know some of you by face, some of you by
name, there is a lot of expertise that
can get into a room and say A and B are
not equaling C and here's why. And as a
state, I don't want to have to broker
broker that and be able to say, "Yeah,
we made that decision on our own. We
want the community to support us because
ultimately the beauty of this is it's
your data." And by golly, you're going
to care about your data. So, I'm going
to get some really good feedback as we
go along in this program, which we have.
And we enjoy the fact that you can do
that. And as Chris has said, if a
standard requires you to pay to be able
to understand your interface between you
and your government or how your identity
works, that's a non-starter for us. We
just we just won't go there.
Now, this part about any app becoming a
wallet, what we mean by that is we do
have some digital credentials in the
state already. For example, if you
download the Department of Natural
Resources app, you can get a QR code for
your fishing license and your hunting
license. That's great. But that's only
inside their little tiny ecosystem. We
want to be able to broaden that out. But
that doesn't mean they have to throw
away their app because they've they've
invested some good money in it. They
also have some poaching features.
So you can take a picture of a carcass
and a GPS and it will send it to you DNR
enforcement officers. So we don't want
to say no you got to you got to go
through the wallet only there but there
are going to be instances where we will
see extension of study credentials
inside existing applications in the
state. The other thing that we are
very aware of is the first mover
advantage for a lot of people is not
going to be going through the platforms.
They're going to be doing their own
trusted apps. To me, there are many
roots of trust that can come into your
relationships. For example, I may trust
my bank and you say, "Hey, we're going
to help you out with your Wells Fargo
wallet and we know about these
pre-key rotations and we provide a
service where you can escrow those keys
with us and using your multisig
capability. Us plus you plus whatever
you know key material you have, we can
unlock your next key for you. That's
fine and that's perfect. And I want to
harp on this just a little bit. The
state's credential is the SEDI. We are
not the wallet. We're not your key
escrow. We're not your key recovery. I
kind of smile and my wife says
this a lot. She's a children's
librarian. She works in a public
library. She has a little counter. It's
almost her personal drinking game where
she says, and I quote, "I'm sorry, I do
not know your Gmail password. I can't
help you with that. Do you have somebody
you can call to help you with that?" And
she has people who argue with her. No,
no, I used this computer yesterday. You
should know my password. And so from the
state, I suspect we're going to get
something like that where people are
going to be like, well, you issued it.
You should know how to recover my keys.
Nope. That and that's part of this whole
idea of, hey, I'm turning it over to
you. Now, with the wallets, one of the
things I do also want to say is that the
state definitely is going to be looking
for third parties who will go and audit
wallets and provide some we'll call
them seals of approval. What I
anticipate happening is when you go to
the state to get your
endorsement for your study is we're
expecting a cryptographic hash and a
signature of the application you're
using. And I can say okay yeah that's
one of the ones we recognize as meeting
the standards of the state. We will go
ahead and finish up this issuance
process and give it to you. But or
Steve McCown Steve McCown's going to
take the source code directly and he's
going to compile his own wallet and make
sure it meets his requirements. So when
Steve comes to the state and says here's
my wallet and in the presentation he
provides us a hash and a signature we
don't know we'll say okay Steve we're
happy to issue to this to you but we
also want you to affirmatively consent
that the state doesn't know anything
about the security of what you're doing.
Yes, you want it. Here you go. Because
we do want that freedom of choice and
the ability for people to operate, but
we also want to have that
guardianship that the state has, which
is the public interest to say, we know
you're not all techies and if you bring
us something that you got your .ru wallet
and it seems like it was the right idea.
We want to make you aware of what that
potential security risk would be. So,
that's something I expect to see coming
in the ecosystem.
Now we at the end of our slide deck
always go back to what is the
key points we want and we want you to be
in charge. We want you to determine who
you share data with, when you share it
with them, and why that matters in the
healthcare environment is we know that
data can be weaponized against you in
the health space. And if you
have no visibility to that and AI models
are starting to be used and I'll say
quite frankly in inappropriate ways to
come to like billing and costing
decisions, you have to be made aware of
that. So you have to have control over
that.
Interoperability. You've heard this if
you've been here the last two days.
What's the interoperability? Well, we
are going to have to be interoperable.
We can't expect that every state is
going to say, you know, we believe
exactly how Utah believes and we think
their technology choices are great and
we are going to go that way.
I don't know if you noticed during the
panel with Joe and our representative
from California, Joe had said we have to
agree that we're solving the same
problem. If we're not, then
interoperability isn't a question. And I
completely agree with where Joe was at
on that. We definitely want to make sure
that we're solving the same issue and
that we're moving forward in something
that is rational for all of us. So
digital reciprocity between states is
something we're going to have to deal
with. We definitely want to make sure
that, hey, if you've ditched all your
your plastic, you jumped on a plane and
you're suddenly in Oregon and you get
pulled over in your rental car, your
digital driver's license has to be
something that can be considered valid
in all jurisdictions. And that's
quite frankly a format war that it's not
my problem right now that I'm trying to
solve. I'm trying to solve the core
identity issues for Utah residents. Now,
of course, we have the
Olympics coming up 2034.
There's probably going to be digital
credentials that come to us from other
jurisdictions even outside the United
States. Well, we are building this
system around the concept of American
values. And what it is no tracking,
no surveillance, no, you know, no
monitoring. So, in those cases, we may
say, "Yeah, that's a valid credential
from where you came from." We might
issue a temporary one while you're here
for the Olympics to allow you to
interface and do the things that you
need to do, but we're certainly not
going to phone home to a foreign server
and participate in state surveillance on
behalf of a of a foreign government. We
just won't do that. So, when it comes to
the healthcare interoperability issues,
we want to make sure that the blast
radius is always one. And this is the
thing that I hate to say it, but we're
finally getting to the point where data
breaches, people are understanding that
your data continues to get lost because
they're in central systems, these huge
honeypots. If we do this right, people
are still going to get social
engineered. But if the blast radius is
one, that's a much better situation for
us to be able to handle than having a
blast radius of, oh, 100 million records
were lost. Would you like some free
credit monitoring and hope things work
out for you? And when we look at the
overall cyber security risk, there's
definitely going to be some things that
we are going to look at from the from
the wallet provider community, key
escrow and how that's done is going to
be super important to us because it's
not your identity if somebody else has
full access to your keys and can perform
rotations without your permission. You
know, I got asked the other day, well,
what happens if I'm
at the border and the law enforcement
agency requires my phone from me and
they copy my whole phone and then
they wander away and now I know they've
got my current keys. Well, Sam, you can
put this on a t-shirt if you want, but I
just said when in doubt, rotate out. You
don't have to stay with that key pair.
When you get your phone back, move on to
your next set. So, I'm going to give you
a situation that happens in rural
healthcare because we talked all about
these things in kind of this really
large buckets, but when I was down
talking to rural healthcare, we had to
have some specific examples of how rural
healthcare is hurt by not having a good
identity system that can provide instant
validation and of assertions of
credentials. So, if you look up there,
50,000 to 100,000 is the and this is
across the nation, not just Utah. this
peer-reviewed studies that they can
bring in a doctor or say a critical care
nurse and getting to the point of having
the original documentation validated.
They're basically sweeping floors or
doing something else or working in a
non-risk position while those
credentials get validated. 50 to 100,000
per provider they bring into the system.
And the tragedy is when you look at
these small healthcare systems in these
rural settings, you may get hospital
privileges for this rural hospital 50
miles down the road where you might want
to work on a weekend or provide
services. You're not accredited. So you
have to go through this whole
credentiing process again. So it's
really hard for people who have made the
commitment as a healthcare provider to
be in a rural community to be able to
service more than one. It becomes a
nightmare and a paper castle. So, we're
looking at SEDI and the subsequent
credentials that get that get in
endorsed by the, you know, medical
organizations and others. We want them
to be able to show up with an ACDC in
the middle of the night and say, "Here
you go. Here's my whole chain of
credentials." And all those boxes get
ticked and that person goes to work
doing the job that they want to do in
that rural community. And of course, one
of the things that we don't want to
Underplay is the fact that these
rural healthcare systems compliance is
a huge issue. You blow up one thing and
you suddenly get all your payments
stopped. In a lot of cases, that can
be detrimental to the organization. I
know for a fact that in the state of
Utah skilled nursing facilities for
long-term hospice care patients, their
hash flow is about 2 and a half to 3
weeks. So, if you get an interruption in
payments, you're calling relatives and
saying, "You need to find somewhere else
because I can't afford to keep my
facility open." So, it's a real risk.
All right, let's talk about us. I
don't know if I'm going to try and get
this as good as phonehome, but I want to
kill the clipboard. I am so sick and
tired of going to an organization that
has my medical records, and every time I
come in, they want all this demographic
data they already have.
It drives me insane and I hope it drives
you insane, too, because it's like,
look, you know who I am. Think if I
attest to things haven't changed since
the last time I saw you, but I'm here
for a sniffle or a broken arm, I don't
need miles of paperwork to tell you the
things that I you already know about me.
And I will say I've been rendered
functionally illiterate by computers. My
handwriting is awful. So half the time
when I'm in these places, they're like,
"Is that an E or is that an A?" I'm
like, " I don't know. I'm in
pain. I'm in a doctor's office. I'm not
really interested in a critique about my
my handwriting. And so what we really
want to do with this kill the clipboard
is reduce these inaccuracies that come
in. And for the love of everything, why
do you have to get a copy a physical
copy of my medical card when I provided
it to you a month ago? And part of this
is not the it's not the fault of the
front-end worker. They have a set of
procedures that are trying to do risk
reduction. And so this is the way that
we operate our systems. And from my
perspective, if I could just go in and
do a tap and say, "Yeah, let me just
punch the items on the iPad of where I
hurt and how bad, that's a much better
experience for me as an individual." And
I also know that the data errors aren't
going to be because you couldn't read my
spelling or you transposed a number on
my medical card. It all came across in a
trustable transaction or series of chain
credentials that we can now move forward
on the situation. So that's the utopia I
look for. Now as I said at the SEDI
summit we look at this in government in
in a lot of different ways but if you
take any process whether it's government
or whether it's business look at the pie
chart of how much of that transaction is
trust verification risk management and
all the other things you actually do
before you get to service delivery. It's
inordinate the amount of time we spend
in making these things work because
we're we're resetting the trust model
every single time. In government, where
this hurts us so much is that we
actually have to staff people who are
part of that front office to injust
this paperwork, make some value
judgments, move things forward, and it's
not something that is sustainable. So
Utah has experienced record growth over
the last decade. We're just growing,
growing. Well, we don't want to grow
government at the same
rate. I can't keep hiring people to
ingest this physical paperwork. I have
to remain in the digital realm, but I
have to be accurate.
So, we are facing this dilemma
everywhere in the United States. As
populations grow, as you know, civil
servants retire, next generation may not
be looking for that sort of work because
generally it doesn't pay really well. In
fact, it doesn't ever pay really well.
But you those are the individuals we
want to be able to have a good
experience with us. But we're not just
going to keep adding and adding and
adding. So we have to get the digital
systems working to our best effect.
So when we look at overall the situation
that SEDI can solve, it's not a situation
of where it solves only one problem. It
solves a number of problems. So when
you're thinking about your specific
marketplace that you work in and how
KERI is going to make things a lot
better, We see it as an underpinning
that breaks a lot of the
traditional models and lets us move on.
I look forward to a world, you know,
endpoints where I can identify and
move things around without an
intermediary. I know Chris and I have
talked about this a lot is that when
this is live and you have these items
available to you in a functional format
with utility, we're going to have a lot
of people who are going, "What's my
purpose in life now?" Because I've had
my job as an intermediary for a long
time. But I'll tell you what, there's
always going to be something new for
people to do. I love history and one
of the things I find funny is when the
automobiles were first allowed in
London, it was a requirement that you
had a signalman walk in front of your
vehicle with a bell and he'd ring the
bell to make sure as you put it away
that the horses were not startled and
they even extended that into the evening
where he would carry a lantern. We don't
have signalmen in front of cars today.
They do something else. And as we
move forward with our new user
centric, you know, sovereign
environment, I think we're going to see
some significant changes in
marketplaces. But it's not just going to
be driven by the state. We can set
governance. We can set law. But as a
larger community, we need to ask those
questions why we do the things the way
we do. And if we are not afraid of those
questions, not only in business, but in
government, we're going to see these
massive improvements along the way.
Okay, we have like three minutes. It's
always hard to be the one who's like
backed up against lunch because the
questions drop off. So, if you don't ask
your question now, that's okay. Find me
at lunch or over the next day
or so. Do we have any questions I can
answer in the next couple of seconds,
minutes, whatever.
Can we get a copy of that?
Absolutely. Absolutely.
That was a simple one. Give me a harder
one.
All right. My question is about on
the delegation slide. You mentioned
several populations where it's super
relevant and one of them is like
unhoused population and migrants and
what how does delegation look in that
case? Who's the delegator?
So in that specific case I'll tell
you what we find with homeless
population specifically in the
healthcare environment. So when we have
an encounter with somebody who's
homeless, the best we can do is put them
on something like emergency Medicaid,
which is super expensive for the state,
and we can provide those critical
services that keep them from
dying, but that's not long-term
maintenance. It's not
prophylactic medications or anything of
that nature. Those don't come until we
have identified that individual. And
given that we might have to query them
like where were you born approximately
when were you born all these items that
we case work it's assigned to them. It
is generally 6 to 8 weeks before we have
documentation in hand that we can now
say we have identified you and we can
now move you off of the emergency
Medicaid and put you on to a different
service. The tragedy is once they
hand them that packet of information
within 30 days the majority of them have
lost their documentation. And it's like
well of course they're unhoused. they're
not going to walk around with
a manilla folder under their arm. So,
how do you solve that problem? Well,
there's a couple ways you can do it. One
of the I was at a conference and I
was just being flip and I said, "Well,
why don't we do a system called Nomad?"
And they were like, "What do you mean by
that?" I said, " National Online
Assisted Documentation, you know, or
management of assist of documentation."
So we are looking at opportunities in it
that could do something like that which
is basically there are some things
you're always going to have with you and
those are going to be some of your
biometrics and if you are willing to
work with the state to get you
identified and put you into a national
data store that's encrypted to your
biometrics then we have means for how we
can get those people on the system.
There are care relationships that exist
inside the state like foster care or we
have battered women who are put in like
safe harbor shelters. So there are some
there are some relationships that we
need to clarify in not only in law but
how that works digitally because there
are certain rights that get communicated
to each group. So as we move along there
will be both a policy side and a
software technology side to work on it.
But the interesting thing is we do
think that the easiest relationship for
us to solve right off the bat is the
parent child relationship. That's pretty
easy to prove. But when we get into some
of these more complicated
situations, so say for example, a
Medicaid household is defined by the
number of people living under the same
roof and what happens if you have an
acrimonious divorce. Party A has a lot
of KYC data to try and infiltrate what
party B is doing. So the state's going
to have to be very careful as we roll
these out to make sure that when we do
endorse something like a parent child
relationship that we do have a glass
break where we can go and turn that off
so that we keep everyone safe.
Okay, I think you is we're at lunch.
So, thank you again. I look forward to
talking to you individually. Reach me
out to me at any time. I'm always
willing to talk about both the tech and
the policy. Thank you very much.
Thanks.