This version of the Locksmith app is
it's it's a open-source stripped down
version of what healthcare has. So, if
you guys want to follow along, I have a
open source repo. It's githubjiot
orLocksmith-demo
and you can follow along. There's some
instructions in the readme.
Locksmith is the desktop wallet for
KERI. This talk is about the
controller side of the system where the
keys stay local. Users manage their
identifiers and control does not
disappear into a single provider stack.
users need a
wallet surface where the keys in
control.
I'm sorry, I'm terrible. The trust
route lives at the edge and non-hosted
services
many
in the in KERI the controller is the
party that actually controls the AID.
That means that it manages the keys in
the key event life cycle. If that user
if that userfacing wallet gets absorbed
into one vertically integrated service
stack, the system may still look open on
paper but it becomes less open in
practice. That's why the wallet boundary
matters is where the control actually
lives.
Many services describe themselves as
open, but in practice, the wallet, the
provider, and the integration path are
all tied to the same stack. When that
happens, builder choice starts to
disappear for KERI to remain genuinely
open. The wallet must remain separate,
and that separation must be real and
verifiable. So, with that in mind,
here's where Locksmith sits in the
stack.
BLocksmith sets the controller side
wallet layer. Witnesses stay outside of
it. The watchers stay outside of it. The
connectors the providers connect to
it but they do not become the wallet.
And by providers I mean the real
external services witness and watcher
operators credential services workflow
services and other KERI adjacent
integrations.
Ashley owns
The first thing that Locksmith proves
is the local state. It is a real local
identity vault. It supports multiple
vaults and local first storage and
controller owned state on disk. That
matters because portability could come
later. The first proof is local control.
So what are you defining as portability
here? You could deploy it to any
any location I suppose.
Okay. Because you say state ownership
for portability polish. I imagine that
means like the key state and everything
necessary for like interacting with the
service provider.
Is that what you mean by state
ownership?
Yeah.
local say that
u and for the identifier
credentials and real user workloads
is where the wallet becomes real for the
user. Locksmith is the desktop surface
where someone can create and manage
identifiers track credential state work
with KERI operations through a usable
interface. That is what the wallet
layers for turning core KERI
behavior into something a person could
actually use.
the this is where the
architecture stays open. Locksmith
has a real plug-in boundary and code
providers sit behind that boundary
rather than replace it. That means that
the wallet can integrate with outside
services without collapsing into
infrastructure. What is real today is
the boundary itself. what is in
progress is the broader ecosystem around
it. More provider side integrations
and the KERI Foundation's work to KERI
that pattern more through more
completely. So the architecture for now
is real now and the full provider
story is currently being built.
This is our architecture flow. The
user signs and stores locally in the
Locksmith vault. From there, the wallet
can communicate with provider side
services via the plug-in boundary.
Separately, events go out to witnesses
and watchers and receipts come back.
Verifiers stay out of that path, which
is the point. Verifiers verification
stays available without turning the
whole system into one provider owned. If
if somebody wants implementation detail,
I could go there. at the at the highest
level that is the overall shape.
What is real now? What is so let
me draw a clean line between what is
real now what is next. What is real
now is the desktop KERI identity
vault local vault and the identifier
workflows a plug-in boundary encode and
repeatable setup reset and launch
evidence. What is next is the broader
foundation plug-in follow through mobile
and web portability and the browser
adjacent work around that this
credibility only for the talk. I wanted
to leave room to I wanted the room to
leave knowing exactly what the demo
proof say and what it's still in
progress.
And then for getting started with the
and then for getting started with the
question on that last one or did you
want us to get to the end and that
question the end? Sure. Let's do it
at the end.
Okay.
And then for getting started with
the code I have a demo repo
that I've forked and I have commands
for Unix. It'll work on for
Unix, it'll work on Mac OS or Linux and
for Windows that the script is it's
just a PowerShell script you could
execute.
Demo bridge.
The locks Locksmith gives KERI a
real control side wallet surface. I
wanted to show the a smallest life path
of this setup can honestly support.
I'm not going to try to turn this into a
full network demo is the
Work that we had to do to remove the
health the healthcare code kind of
made that part a still a work in
progress
So, in order to install this I just
set just run the script where it'll
If it'll detect if something's
ready there. If not, if it is, it'll get
rid of it and then it'll set up the
environment and then I'll deploy it.
Screen
expected.
Sorry.
So I came in like this Locksmith is the
is the wallet KERI.
Yes.
What's the relationship between
Locksmith and KERIpy one that was in
the session description? The KERI
pie one is that this is the KERI
pie one's just my fork or the pie is
The
wait
and the other one's my fork
Sorry. For whatever reason, I selected
the wrong command.
Python scripts demo day. Come on, please
work.
Sorry, my
it takes my
Sorry, this is taking a while.
And then we could initial initialize
a vault and
a lot of this stuff is still work in
progress. The a lot of the functionality
is
not there because it was stripped out
from the from the healthcare wallet.
But this when it we have
when we when we have the full
functionality built out, it'll have
large par with largely at par with the
healthcare wallet
and we could create our own identifiers.
We could set the cryptographic
strength a I don't have a remote
identifier that I could connect to right
now.
Same thing for a group identifier.
issue a credential.
No schemas to
I don't I don't have anything for that
yet.
Add a schema.
And set this. I could change
the settings for the cryptographics
Key strength settings or other stuff
for the cryptography. But this is
The open source version of the code
that you guys can go and explore.
And sorry I'm just I'm not good at
public speaking. So and that's all I've
got. What questions do you guys
have?
Yeah. So essentially is what you've
showed us the KERI Foundation using the
plug-in API with Locksmith to run
against their own infrastructure.
Yes.
In this demo.
That's not in this demo. Okay.
So this is the open- source wallet that
we got originally from healthcare. We've
debranded it. This is available now for
anybody to go and fork this, download
it, use it, build out more if you want
other features if you want. The plugin
itself is not shown here.
You'll see that in my demo, but you and
I are competing with each other. So now
we're not
now we're not gonna now you're not going
to see it ever. Ah,
thanks man. Hey Joseph,
does so does this sorry this is a dumb
question but does this wallet here have
the KEL on in this whatever device is
installing the wallet does is the KEL
also there
you're local
yeah local
yeah locally
so this creates the manages the keys and
the KEL
in that environment
and you publish the KEL to a witness
yes to one or more witnesses right
so you would configure the witness here
Yeah, you'll see that in my demo if you
come to my demo.
When did you demo?
3:15.
It's Yeah, big
sorry. And then and then also the
tell stuff is that
no that's ACDC related. We're not going
to cover that in this
but it would it be on in this on this
local just
that's a good question. I don't know
where theoretically I guess probably
so but I don't I don't know that's a
little bit outside of scope of
dealt with yet.
I know they defined the tell this
morning, but I forgot what it stands
for.
Transaction event log
and that's for the recipient to detect
that's for the holder to detect if their
credentials are being used in the non
Not necessarily tells are
specifically related to a different
construct in AC or in KERI ecosystem
called ACDC which is more about
credential issuing.
Yeah. So the benefit of the tell you're
publishing the transaction event so that
you can
I'm going to get anchored to the key
event log
I can't keep track of the state
I think a good way is the KEL is the
state of your keys and the tell is the
state of your credentials
question like how what the state of
because they can be in multiple
different kind of states depending on
what the credential is
and so
like revocation status state Yeah. Yeah.
I would guess that in Phil's ACDC talk
tomorrow morning, he'll cover this
stuff.
Tells everybody
if he's doing one then. Yeah.
Yeah. He's talking about ACDC tomorrow
morning. So if you have more questions
about that, he might actually have
production use cases that you could
guess.
So about the repos again.
So the Locksmith demo one is this one.
And what's in the Locksmith one? That
just that's the full health KERI
that's the
healthy is proprietary.
Yeah,
we had to strip out all their fun
features when they donated to us. But
we still have like all the core KERI
stuff like identify creationing.
There's support for like witnesses
and watchers but in order to connect to
witnesses and watchers you need to
connect to a provider such as healthcare
through a plugin. So the KERI
Foundation is going to create is
creating our own plugin where you can
connect to our infrastructure to get
witnesses and watchers and then in
theory you could also have in the same
UI you can see KERI Foundations plugin
and like healthcare's plugin or any
other provider who wants to create
witnesses and watchers
provide infrastructure for you to
use basic but what does it want started
with creating a want
encryption storage right Yeah, it's just
a place to store keys.
Yeah, but it is like for per wallet
you have multiple wallets. What is the
reason for it?
Just in case you wanted separation for
some reason.
It's like one password and bit warden.
Most of these password managers have the
similar idea of vaults where you can say
this is my work vault. This is my
personal vault.
Okay.
It's just applying the same belong to a
specific vault.
Yeah.
So you can't move them across.
Yeah. That's I don't know. I don't
think you can move them across yet.
Theoretically, I guess we could
eventually I can understand
I have them.
Yeah.
But here I'm trying to understand
because they're very tightly coupled
with ID, right? The credentials are very
tightly coupled with ID.
And when you have walls,
I mean what would you how would you move
you can't move the credentials across
because different ID
I would guess that you could probably
like if you created two vaults I have so
I don't know. I'm guessing if you
created like a local identifier in one
vault, you could OOBI with it from
another vault as a remote identifier so
you could watch your own vaults. But I
don't know why you want to do that.
The I was looking at the KERI
Foundation GitHub.
There's 16 repositories and it looks
like there's three different wallet
implementations.
There's the Fort Web
the
No, there's the I think those are just
different deployment w targets.
There's one for iOS, there's a web app,
there's one for iOS, there's a web app,
and one for Android. Yeah.
Okay. But there's there's the fort
for Android and fort for iOS and then
there's the key the Locksmith. Are those
how are those related?
The Locksmith is just what we take
and deploy to the different targets.
Locksmith is desktop version.
Okay.
Well, the Fort Web and Locksmith are
they're they're they're both desktop
versions. They're just different
implementations of the desktop version.
Essentially, all of them are a wallet,
right? They're all the same. They're all
wallet. You make identifiers. You can
UI.
So, my question is, why would you pick
one versus the other?
Whatever platform you want to use it on.
Are
you trying to deploy to a desktop or to
an iOS?
But Locksmith is web.
No, lockmith is just desktop.
It's
Oh, this is native desktop.
Yeah, it's a PIDE 6 applic. Okay, that
makes sense. Are they coming from the
same?
It's multiplatform source bundle. It's
it's all it the web or yeah they
they all are getting deploy the same
stuff the same code is getting deployed
to all those all those different
platforms. So for web is just the
web SaaS
app of Fort
also have multiple local identifiers
right in a single one have multiple
local
yes
that's just talking about
issuing credential to many identifiers
some Josh was talking about
Evan be talking more about the web wall
tomorrow
or whatever you want.
Wow.
People have other things they want to
hear about
or whatever suggestions.
Basically, he's just going to stand up
there and let you ask him anything.
Ask me anything session with that.
Cool.
I think that's kind of it.
Do you guys have any other questions or
I guess we're kind of still kind of
pretty early
tomorrow.
Yeah, I guess I mean the question I have
that might be answered tomorrow probably
in your session.
Is there is it is it clear based on what
the what code that's open source what a
provider has to do in order to do their
own plug-in implementation and what they
have to sort of implement on the
infrastructure side
for the plugin kind of. Yeah.
Yeah. Because I want to do I want I'm
going to do a blog about it and sort of
show people how to do it.
I can make my session how to make your
own plug-in demo.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Yeah, it's pretty cool. a good idea
because I will definitely be doing it.
I want to help other people learn too.
I mean it's it's all there in the repo
so you could obviously learn how it's
built but
I don't think we haven't done
anything formally yet to describe how to
build a plugin.
Okay.
So that would be a good thing.
There is yeah healthcare shipped like a
plug-in based flask. So they basically
like define the set of functions
you need to define in order to make your
own plugin.
Awesome. Yeah that's what I wanted
that's what I want to know.
time to go through that sort of thing
tomorrow.
Was interesting.
There are other open source KERI
wallets besides the Fort Locket one,
isn't there?
Yeah. From so I'll talk a little bit
about this in my session, but there's
heavyweight wallets and lightweight
wallets. Lightweight or Signify wallets.
This is a heavyweight wallet. It's the
most complete one in the world by far.
Well, health carries is
Yeah, health carries is I guess
this is sort of a stripped down
slightest. So I guess health carries is
the most complete and then this is
stripped down version of but it's it's
the furthest of all
but that's your session tomorrow not
your session today.
No I have two sessions today. One is
the last one is on the KERI stuff
about lightweight wall. The first one is
going to be on the Root of Trust.
Cool. Wow.
Well thank you. Do you guys have any
other questions?
Who wants to speedrun building a
provider
right now?
Let's do it.
Evan can coach you through it.
All right.
I just copy our
done 40 minutes.
No.
Sorry that this wasn't very long.
Good.
See,
we got a little time. Jay, you can
launch the iOS thing if you want.
Sure.
Just to show it.
Yep. So, this is the iOS app.
Suppose I should
So yeah, it's it's functionally speaking
just it's the same code just it's
deployed to a w the mobile apps
are just wrappers that will run the
bLocksmith code
and yeah it's just this functionally
the same experience on any of the
devices and that's right I have not
fixed this yet.
So, I'm noticing that this looks very
similar to the flat UI. It's And I know
it's Pyite 6.
Mhm.
Yeah. Well, healthcare basically just
translated the flat app into Pyite 6.
Okay. So, the flat app is,
right? I just wondered if it was I guess
did they lift the CSS styling when they
This is CS. Yeah, I just I left it as
close as it to what it was.
Okay.
Good jokes.
Nice work.
Thank you.