Okay, we are getting started.
All right.
This is primarily developer focused.
We're getting down into the nitty-gritty
nuts and bolts.
And I imagine since it's developed
focused, we'll probably have a smaller
audience. I'm going to go through and
get to know each one of you.
Some of you I've never seen before.
Who?
Oh, thanks. Great.
I don't think I've ever met you before.
Will you tell me your name?
This is everybody. This is Joseph
Hunsicker.
Everybody knows Carl McKenna.
One of my bosses at life. And I do have
to remind me your name. Matthew? Yes,
Matthew. Matthew.
Matthew Hillstone.
George McQueen. George McQueen, okay.
Mitchell with the healthcare. Mitchell
with healthcare, okay. I don't think
I've met you before. That's cool.
Mark Scrimshire Onyx.
What was the name of the company? Onyx?
Onyx, okay. And then the name, Matt?
Mark Scrimshire. Mark Scrimshire, okay.
Nice to meet you.
So, what this tutorial is for you
if you're wondering what is KERIA, what
is Signify,
what is this signing at the Edge
architecture that many of the qualified
vLEI issuers in the GLEIF ecosystem
have embraced.
For example, Provenant,
Finema,
I would say there's a
CFCA in China. And we've got a number of
others that are
Trade Go.
Certizen, that's correct. So, the
platform you're seeing today is used in
production by a number of
a number of our qualified vLEI issuers
and other people that sort of there's
the Veridian wallet. They've built on
top of this architecture as well. Now, I
should I should caveat that
the wallet you're seeing today
is a demo wallet. It's not Provenant's
wallet. No QVIs use the wallet. It's a
demo wallet to walk you through the
features.
Now, the goal of today's presentation is
so that you can walk away as a developer
knowing how do I configure and run this
thing? What is this API surface area?
What are the capabilities? What can this
thing do for me?
And it's throughout the we will actually
have a demo. And if you look at this
wallet right here, this is something
yes, I use Codex to help me make this.
I've made
So I actually made one of the first
wallets in the world for DigiCred for
student credentials based on Signify
CS and KERIA. This is way better than
that.
From it's it's more of a developer
wallet, I'll admit it. Their Digicred
wallet was way better user experience
which geared towards students for
non-technical people. This wallet is
geared for you all. So, if you want to
look inside how does this work as a
developer? It's geared towards your
mental model. Cuz quite honestly, for a
customer
for a non-technical person, this is
already way too complicated. This is a
developer user experience. So, it's for
you to categorize and understand what
are the subject matters of API surface
area for me to worry about. Did you have
a question, Matthew? So, this is
basically is it meant to be a web
application? Is it meant to be an
extension or a mobile app or all any of
the above? I'm going to repeat that
question because it's a very good
grounding question for what is this
architecture. He said, is this intended
to be a web app? Is it a mobile app?
What is this intended to be used for?
So, let's actually
Or a browser extension. Or a browser
extension. So, let's actually pause and
jump back to the presentation cuz I
answered that question. Very good
question. I can tell you're thinking.
Okay, so then we ask what is KERIA? When
is it useful?
KERIA, the architecture, let's just jump
straight to the nuts and bolts. It's
this architecture right here and we're
going to answer your question right
away.
So, that web app that you were seeing
is a browser web app.
Most people use it as either a browser
app or like on a cross-platform
application basis, Ionic Capacitor
or React Native.
Anything that uses TypeScript that's
compatible with Libsodium in the
browser, specifically Libsodium wrapper
Sumo,
that can that can work with React
Native, you can run the Signify and
KERIA architecture. Well, why would you
want to do that? Well, let's understand
a little bit more about the what
and the why will become evident.
So, the I'll preface this by saying
there's two broad categorizations of
wallets in the KERI ecosystem. The
terminology that I'm about to use is
mine. I started using this because it's
it's a way for me to categorize how this
how the how the different wallets are.
You can use whatever terminology
makes the most sense to you. I call the
Signify client wallet, Signify and KERIA
architecture, I say lightweight wallet.
And I call what Locksmith is, Philip
Feairheller from healthKERI,
Locksmith is a heavyweight wallet. Why
is that the case? I'm about to describe
why and we're just you're going to
understand it from the very beginning of
the presentation.
Lightweight refers to
what the user has in their hands.
With Signify, all they have is an Edge
signing client. They don't store their
credentials.
Keys only ever exist unencrypted in
memory in whatever browser or web view
instance they have, but that's all
that's ever stored here is just the
unencrypted keys and just enough state
to do whatever your operation you're
doing, whether it's issuing credentials,
doing an interaction event, doing a key
rotation,
doing an OOBI resolution. A bare minimum
of state is kept here, which is why I
call it the lightweight client.
The heavyweight client essentially
takes, you could say this Edge signing
architecture,
and your key store, heavyweight wallets
put all that together locally. You could
think of local first software where all
of your keys So, if you if you a heavy
weight wallet, you'd have everything in
in one app on your phone, and you would
not have a server agent. The lightweight
wallet has a server agent, and you might
say, "Well, is that okay from a security
perspective? What about the keys? Where
are the keys? Do we want to Are we
custodying keys here?"
We're going to get into the nuts and
bolts in the in the later slides. The
answer is that
there are keys key seeds that are stored
here, but they're only ever stored in
the server encrypted.
The way that it works, and we'll get
There's some more slides is the root
master key here in the Signify
lightweight wallet client is an
encryption decryption key.
It's also a KERI AID.
It performs a delegation from the
in-memory
identifier to the agent identifier. If
you're familiar with the concept of a
witness, a witness is a non-transferable
identifier, right?
And but it's it's it's it's a regular
KERI identifier. You can get a key event
log. You can resolve an out-of-band
identifier to get that Key Event Log
with that one event plus some location
scheme records and endpoint rule records
for a witness. Well, an agent is a
little bit like a witness, and there's a
common capability between witnesses and
agents at least in the most commonly
deployed form. healthKERI actually did
witnesses the right way in the sense
that it's only a witness.
But, just because of an artifact of
accident of history, witnesses in the
beginning
of GLEIF's implementation of the
the KERI spec, witnesses and mailboxes
were combined.
Mailbox is a store and forward
mechanism. Cuz what happens if your
phone goes offline and it's a
lightweight client? You still want to be
able to receive messages when that phone
comes back online, right? You don't want
to not be able to receive messages
because your phone's off or it's dead
battery.
So, what you do is there's a mailbox.
A mailbox
runs in a persistent process that has
an IP address,
a way to essentially send it messages,
which is similar to a DIDComm relay.
Now, I see that a couple of people came
in here later. Let me quickly before I
sort of finish off the mailbox topic,
I'm just giving you a warning. I'm going
to come in to ask your names and sort of
introduce you to everyone else cuz
we're all developers here, so we get to
to know each other. All right, so I'm
talking about this concept of a mailbox.
An agent functions as a mailbox. It's a
store and forward mechanism. It's a
persistent internet presence.
The primary responsibilities of an
agent, it's a mailbox, it's a delegation
communication proxy, which we'll get
into later,
and it's the primary data store.
Your ACDCs are stored here,
not here.
Your contacts, your out-of-band
identifiers, your Key Event Log, it's
all stored here. It's all signed here.
Nothing is signed here
on your identifiers.
With a small caveat, remember I said
it's a mailbox, it's a store and forward
mechanism, it's a delegation
communication proxy.
As it performs those functions,
remember, we're in zero trust. It's a
signed everything
architecture, no shared secrets
architecture. When the agent itself,
which is an identifier, it's an actor in
this ecosystem, when the agent is
sending communications, it does have its
local key that it'll sign messages so
that everything coming from the agent
can be signed and verified.
But, the agent does not have any of your
keys. That's the thing.
Go ahead, question. Is this strictly a
delegation model? Strictly delegation.
KERI delegation. Okay.
You can just Okay.
And what's interesting, so how it works
and this is architecture slides are fun
because you can spend a lot of time on
them and then we'll breeze through the
rest of the
the slides.
The way that you provision an agent, so
when you start your controller into you
instantiate it in memory,
the way that you boot an agent there's
it's two-phase process. You do boot and
then connect. When you do your boot up
I need to touch my computer more often,
I guess.
Oh, it's thinking that we're not
paying it enough attention.
Let's give it some attention here.
Change. I love this picture. I got to go
there someday. This is in France. It's
the one of the most beautiful places
I've ever seen in my life.
I'm going to take my wife there.
Okay.
So,
now that we're back up,
so when you when you do the boot
process, you're actually signing a
delegation event. You send it over here.
You request from the agency. So, you
actually send the initial boot to the
agency. It provisions the agent and
starts the delegated inception process
in the agent identifier. It's first
event
in its Key Event Log is a delegated
inception. It accepts the
delegation request and then when it
responds on the connect, it actually
completes the delegation handshake.
So, this is a strict KERI delegation
relationship between your Edge signer
and your agent identifier.
Anyway, so now you and then I have some
other graphics here to show you that the
agent has the responsibility of managing
the essentially the database for
your identifier, any credential
registries, and credentials that you've
got. Now, the keys that are stored here,
remember they're only ever encrypted.
And they're encrypted
with the key that is derived from the
passcode you have at the Edge. This
passcode never moves over here, ever. It
only ever stays at the Edge. That's why
it's called a signing at the Edge
architecture.
Not quite. This together is the
lightweight architecture.
The heavyweight wallet combines both of
these responsibilities into one thing.
What it is this runs on a server.
This runs on a client.
Makes sense?
This is leaking.
[laughter]
That's really weird.
Just got to drink it all.
I didn't I wasn't I wasn't abusive to
this. I don't know why it's leaking all
over there.
[laughter]
Anyway, okay, so now let's move on.
So is there anybody that has sort of any
lingering questions on the architecture
before we move on? The agent on the
right side is the whole thing. It's not
just the one
So this is multi-tenant in the sense
that the agency can have multiple
agents. I expanded out what you're going
to have inside of an agent. So there's
multiple clients.
Well, there can be multiple clients.
Yeah, or yeah. All using the same
agency, but they have a different Yes,
the agents this is the orchestrator for
the multi-tenancy for a given server
process.
So therefore one agent per Signify
client. Correct. Correct. What's That's
a good point. One It's a one-to-one
relationship between Signify controller
and KERIA agency agent. And
all of the components underneath the
agent are what's inside of it.
Yes.
And there's a dedicated LMDB database
for agent. Actually a set a set of
files, but
Okay, so
now that we beat that to death.
So KERIA is a
KERIA means KERIA agent. That's what it
means.
And we talked So it actually originated
something called the simple KERIA web
off protocol and that evolved to Signify
sign at the Edge. Where you have your
link to the original hackMD document. I
remember when this is being first talked
about back in 2021 2022. There's a
current Web of Trust repository with the
original
a simple-KERI-for-web-auth. It's
actually some of the best documentation
of the
different alternatives and ways to think
about it if you want to really sort of
do a
some software archaeology.
But the basic idea
encryption key at the Edge
and the identifier seed salts in the
agent. Now you have the encryption key
at the Edge
and what happens is you will pull those
encrypted salts
from your agent local to the Edge in the
browser and use them to do signing of
events
for any of your managed identifiers.
Okay, so
what's the agent? We sort of beat that
to death. Let's go ahead and move on.
I don't think there's anything. So we
haven't really talked about delegation
communication proxy. We'll get into that
a little bit later, but once again, it's
your server it's your storage server for
ACDC's contacts, OOBI's, challenge
response, and all that.
Okay, so at a high level, what are the
features we have in
in the Signify KERI architecture?
It's just the same things that you're
going to have in the heavyweight wallet
architecture. It's just all the events
are signed at the Edge. We've got client
creation boot and connect like we talked
about. Client creation, that's actually
something specific to the lightweight
wallet architecture, but all the rest
is applies to the lightweight and
heavyweight. Identifier creation,
rotation, interaction, I should have put
signing on there. Out-of-band identifier
generation and resolution, challenge
creation and response verification,
credential issuance, grant admit, and
the full IPX prop
flow if you're familiar with the other
verbs.
And we're going to get to the KERI
configuration. So that's sort of what
what we've got the capabilities of
this architecture here.
You will leave here knowing how to
configure a KERI server. We're about
20 minutes in. I we'll get to that. I'll
make sure we get to that. Question. So
credential issuance. Huh. So, is
for
the AID
they're
they're that issued it.
Is that No, that's a good question.
Let's actually go back. So,
which identifier does the issuance?
Is it the Signify controller that does
the delegation to the agent? No.
What's called a managed AID is what does
the issuance.
So, the Signify controller delegates to
the agent and it says, "Agent, make me
an identifier." And the agent says,
"Okay, well, you have to give me a
signed event."
And you So, you create the key locally
that's going to end up as this as the
stored encrypted seed.
When you have that in memory, it's
decrypted, you create the inception
event for a managed identifier, then you
send that to your agent, and your agent
says, "Okay, great. I'll create a
managed identifier record in my
database."
And this is the level at which you're
going to start to issue credentials.
So, it's actually one layer deep below
the Signify controller.
Does that make sense?
Or do you want to ask for now?
Yeah, so we'll have a demo later. It'll
probably clear it up a little bit.
Why are you generating the key and
sending the key
at that client and not generating it and
sending it at the agent itself? It feels
like the
generation of the key would be more
secure at the agent side. It's not
because the server can be compromised,
right?
We don't want any We don't We don't
store any keys here unencrypted.
The keys only ever exist at the Edge,
which is why it's called the signing at
the Edge architecture. I see. So, you're
encrypting the key, and then that
encrypted
key is stored there. Yes, the encrypted
key is stored in the agency, but
remember, the agent never has access to
the unencrypted key ever.
All signing occurs at the
Edge. This has implications when you use
HSMs (hardware-security-module).
Because you have to send your event to
the HSM to be signed.
HSMs are another signing at the Edge
architecture.
It's just the HSM is the Edge.
Question.
Well, think about it. If you If you lose
your lightweight client, you don't want
to lose your seed, right?
You just If All you have to remember So,
the reason why it's a lightweight
architecture, all you have to remember
is your passcode.
If everything fails and you lose
your phone, well, you've got a
server agent where you can As long as
you have a password manager and you have
your root passcode,
well, you can
reconnect to your agent and reconstitute
the keys locally by decrypting them. So,
storing them on the on the in the agent
is actually very handy.
Yeah.
You could store them in like a mobile
app if you wanted to do that and change
the storage model, you could totally not
even store them on the server. They're
just stored on the server from a
convenience perspective.
And really, if you could build an agent
replication or state, you know,
migration architecture if you really
wanted to on top of that.
Yes, 21 characters.
But, it's actually exactly 21
characters.
If you put in more than 21 characters,
it chops it off the 21. And if it's less
than 21, it doesn't let you do it.
[laughter]
So, it doesn't do any stretching right
now. It has to be 21 characters.
And I can we can go into the
dirty details of why that's the case
sometime.
Yeah.
Okay, so we went into the features
outline.
Okay, I'll show you a little bit of a
demo.
Correct.
Well, not Well, okay, let me
clarify. Let me give you a caveat.
Whenever you create an identifier, you
can specify witnesses.
Remember as backers
Well, yeah, yeah, it's not the agent
like I guess what you're saying here
what I'm saying is that
The agent is not a witness. The agent is
not a watcher. Well,
There's anything that stores Key Event
Logs acts a little bit like a watcher.
But technically in the way it's commonly
thought of this is not a witness. This
is not a watcher.
That's a separate service that's run.
Is that what you're asking?
Great. Okay.
Did you have a question?
All right.
So a quick demo to answer your question
to make it clearer what does the
signing? Let's actually run through a
wallet. So this is the wallet that I
made. Let me actually pop over to the
browser here. So what I'm going to do So
if anybody knows about the Signify React
TS example repository
in the Web of Trust community
you'll probably recognize this button.
This is the only thing recognizable from
back when RootsID originally
contributed the wallet. I did heavy
heavy coding with codex over the last 3
days
to get this in this in this state. So
we've got a heck of a lot more features
and it looks way better than the old
ugly one did. I think this is still kind
of garish, but
we'll connect.
Okay, so I'm going to connect. Now what
what I'm going to do here is I'm going
to paste in my passcode. It's kind of
hard to see I guess with some of those
the screen separations there,
but I'm going to paste a passcode in.
And ooh, I've got some There we go.
I'll just go ahead and show. So this is
a 21 character passcode.
Oh, that's fine. This is this is this is
a throwaway passcode. But thank you.
Good security consciousness.
Oh, thank you. Yeah. Good point.
All of that is luckily just dev stuff.
But thank you. Okay.
So
this
I mean you're making me think about
something I saw on X about a person who
Oh, yeah, they had a
a policeman took a picture of somebody's
Bitcoin private key and it was it
was on there
no not even the not even a picture,
but it was the body cam footage saw and
then somebody got like million dollars
taken out of their Bitcoin wallet or
something like that.
But thanks for the security
consciousness. Luckily, I don't have
anything worry worrisome in my
clipboard.
I There shouldn't be. You should double
check for me.
[laughter]
All right. If you find some, let me
know.
Now, this generate here. So, by the
way, this is open source Apache 2 stuff.
This will generate we can we you know,
I'll just make a new one.
So, and then I'm going to copy and
paste it so I can reuse it.
When I connect here, so what's going
to happen this pass code will
instantiate in memory a Signify Edge
signing client.
I'm going to click connect.
It's provisioning the agent. Now, I've
got the agent. This is sort of a
dashboard. I'm going to go to the
identifiers.
I have zero identifiers right now.
The Signify client AID in memory is not
assigning identifier.
It's not an identifier that will issue
credentials.
I have to create an identifier. So, I'm
going to click create identifier.
And I'm going to say Is this creating
one of those KERI
This is what? This is creating one of
those managed identifiers. Managed
identifiers, correct. This is creating a
managed identifier. I could change from
salty which is deterministic.
So, this is if you saw the health KERI
demo
they had
keychain versus random. Salty is
essentially random. I'm surfacing some
terminology that really should be hidden
from the user. I just went really fast.
The salty is deterministic, Randy's
random. So,
and we could make a delegated identifier
if we wanted to. I'll go ahead and put
some witnesses in there.
And if we would look at the advanced
options, we can sort of specify signing
threshold and things like that, but I
like to hide those options unless you
actually know you need to use them.
Okay, so we created a an identifier with
three Let me just sort of pop into the
details here.
It's a little bit hard to reach from the
back.
But this is our AID. This is our managed
AID. This is not the Signify controller
identifier.
The Signify controller identifier just
connected to the agent. And actually, I
can I have a page for that. So
if we go to the client, let's scroll up
a little bit.
This shows you some details about what
we've been talking about so far.
The controllerAID, which is derived
from my pass code,
is this AID right here. It delegated to
the agent AID.
This is a KERI delegation relationship
between these two identifiers.
And here's some more interesting stuff
about Okay, the sequence number of the
Technically, as you can see, since it
starts with E and if you know CESR,
they're both transferable identifiers.
So you could rotate keys for either the
controller or the agent.
And you can see the sequence number that
the controller's on. We're on sequence
number one.
And so you as you see, so remember how I
said delegated inception? The first
first event for the agent is delegated
inception. You can see the first message
it's showing in this here is dip, which
is delegated inception.
So this is the little control panel that
I added for the
to show both the Signify controller and
the delegated agent. I don't think
there's anything else that we want to
show here. Okay, so we created an
identifier.
And we can go in there. You can see
there's a couple interesting things you
can I can copy the agent out-of-bound
identifier, which if we KERL that, let's
actually show that.
I'm going to copy that. We're going to
go to
You can already kind of see where I'm
going here. Let me zoom in a little bit.
So what if we wanted to see
what the Key Event Log is for that
identifier we just created? Well, we
copied its out-of-bound
What is it What does it look like? If we
KERL that, this is running on my
computer now. This is a big old honking
CESR stream. It looks like the Matrix.
Let's format it so it's a little bit
easier to read. So, let's do
pipe it to a little colorizer. I went
kind of like JQ but for CESR. 2FA
annotate
colored
pretty
Okay. So, it's a little bit colorized.
I'll I'll I'll walk through this kind of
slowly.
So, you'll see
this is the first this is the inception
event for the first managed identifier I
created. It's an inception event. Notice
it's not a delegated inception event.
This is a dedicated identifier. That's a
managed identifier where you use
So, the root pass
code that you made is like the root
seed.
You generate another root seed for this
managed identifier.
It's encrypted and then sent to the
agent and you pull that back when you're
going to do a rotation for this managed
identifier. Is that making sense now?
Perfect. Okay. Any lingering
question on the relationship?
Yeah, just like
When I think of the AID, I think of
entity of some sort. Huh. I'm the
controller. The AID
is essentially me as a controller.
Huh. The AID of
the agent is the agent. The AID Those
two make sense, but I don't understand
why you
why I would have a bunch of managed
AIDs.
Like is it In the case of a university,
am I making
I don't know. Like what is the
use case where I Why would I have to
manage
several
AIDs?
So, it could be that one of your Let's
say you're a legal entity
and you one of your identifiers
is for your legal entity itself. And
another one might be for you as the CEO.
Another one might be for a different
role that you're playing for engagement
context role credential.
I think I know who this is.
Whoops. Let me put this on do not
disturb. Pardon me.
And it there's a there's a variety of
different reasons why you might have
more than one. But generally speaking,
it's not going to be very many,
depending on what you're doing.
Is it they should all be under the
the controller's
jurisdiction and so forth or purview or
whatever it I mean it could be. Maybe
you're working for a corporation and
they say we want you have an account for
this and an account for that and have
different identifiers. It really just
depends. Okay, so the root controller
could be an employee.
And then and then
they
this company makes
a KERIA server for their employees.
And then they manage other people
or something like that. They have roles
that might need to communicate with
other
entities or something. Well, you
wouldn't think of the corporation as
just one Signify controller and then
managed AIDs per employee. You would
think of cuz you would think of each
employee at that corporation as having
their own Signify controller. And maybe
one, usually probably one, one or more
managed identifiers.
Right. And the company would have
one or more KERI instances. Yeah,
that's right.
Okay. Question. I was just going to make
a comment on the managed ID discussion.
We discussed that as a same perspective
as we try to how do you do
prevent cross context correlation.
And so we've been looking at managed IDs
and like all issues.
I think that's the same scenario we're
discussing here. We have individuals
that have multiple managed IDs
that they can use in different contexts.
Oh, for sure.
Like you could have somebody that says,
I want my
whatever steady credential with under
this identifier.
Or that the state may issue multiple
steady credentials. Oh, yeah. Okay. Huh.
I see.
Huh.
But a But a credential is not an
Well, well, well, what he's getting at
is that he's What if I'm understanding
you right, Chris, is that the state
steady may allow issuing the same steady
credential to different managed
identifiers that you have cuz you might
want to segment for your own privacy the
usage of a given identifier. So you can
you can both issue your AIDs managed
AIDs in the back of the state for
endorsement.
So it's effectively your steady
credential duplicated
to whatever level you want to go. I know
prevent your ID from being a main
super cookie for tracking you and having
a different one. That's how it will be.
Okay. So
Like it's like So it's like sharding
your identity is Yeah. Like effectively
if
you know, I might want to have a
managed ID for my for my
university or another one for my
financials or another one for my
whatever. Just
like so sharding pieces of me. Yeah.
If I was But if I was And that's as an
individual, but as an employee,
I might shard my identity in different
ways that are custom to my company or
Right. my organization or what I'm
doing.
Yeah. That's right.
Go ahead. Basic question back to the
picture diagram.
So
the infrastructure provider for the
agency configuration
What prevents this individual to
mess with this with the signer
keys or I guess with the agent because
it's not saying your way Good
question. So, encryption. So, it is
because of the encryption.
Yes. The administrator
of the multi-tenant agency server
has access to zero keys. Because the
keys are always encrypted at rest
when they're on the agency.
The only time the keys are unencrypted
is after they've been pulled to the Edge
client and your master decryption key
decrypts them. Oh.
So, they're never even if somebody
compromised the server, they could still
never use your keys.
Got it. So, the signing goes up in at
the Edge always. Exactly. Oh, I thought
it was at the Edge. Okay.
It took me a couple little while to
understand it when I was first learning.
The And when And what's cool is you
actually know you learned more quickly
than I did. It took me a while to really
track this down and sort of ask the
right person and sort of figure it out.
And I didn't I didn't feel
comfortable with it until I read through
the code to see exactly how it works and
I could show you exactly where. But
yeah, all signing happens at the Edge.
So, okay. So, now let's go through some
of the slides, see if we've got some
more. Okay, so we've talked about this.
Edge controller signs events.
Sends to the delegated agent, which we
talked about is the agent. The agent is
in KERIA.
We've got it handles identifiers, all
these other capabilities that we saw.
Okay, we have two signing libraries. I
recently updated Signify Py to be on par
with Signify TS. Yes, the latest version
of Signify TS was released yesterday,
030.
And the latest version of Signify Py is
020. I should I should re-release that
just 030 to be sort of consistent. But
Signify Py is updated in Actually, no,
it's 040. Even worse.
I got to align the version numbers. So,
Signify Py is up is up late dated in pi
pi.
Signify TS has been updated in npm as of
yesterday.
And what I don't have on the slide here,
so there's KERIA, the most recent
version of KERIA has been released at
0.3.0.
There's going to be a 0.3.1 very soon
because while I was preparing for this
presentation, I found a delegation bug
or missing feature. And we fit we
patched that this morning. As soon as it
gets the PR gets approved, we'll patch
it in.
Anyway, so
yeah, that's that we've got two
libraries right now, Signify TS and
Signify Py. And Cardano
has Signify Java.
They have some clients who wanted a Java
implementation, so they implemented the
entire surface area in Java, in case you
want to know. Now, the Cardano
implementation has only ever so slightly
diverged from the Web of Trust
implementation. It's very, very close.
And so it's if you needed the Java
implementation, it's very doable to if
you wanted to use the Web of Trust
standard implementation.
Okay, so now this is These are the
gotchas. This is what's going to
save you time. And I was okay, so we
got to be done in 9 minutes here. I want
to get through all of these and some of
the config.
We've been answering questions
throughout. Please continue to stop me.
This is where you're going to need to
come back to me. You or someone on your
team will have to come back to me or
somebody from the KERIA community cuz
you're going to hit these problems.
What is the passcode? What are the Where
are the keys stored? And we've we've
cleared a lot of these up cuz
you're going to have to re-explain this
architecture to every team member. And
they're going to ask, "Where are the
keys?" They're going to ask exactly what
you asked, "Well, what if somebody
compromises the server? Is that a
problem?" You're going to have to
explain to them, "No, the keys truly are
at the Edge."
It's It's like it takes some individual
missionary work to get it between minds.
[laughter]
And you say, "Okay, what is encrypted
and decrypted and when?" We've already
We've already taken care of the major
misconception or misunderstanding that
people often have with KERIA. So, you're
already ahead of the curve.
And some people ask, "Okay, what about
storing the passcode? If I'm making a
web app, can I just store it in indexDB
or localStorage? That's a big no-no.
And the reason why
is any same origin JS code from you can
read and exfiltrate that passcode.
Now, if you want to use something like
Ionic Capacitor, they do have a
secure storage plugin that'll work with
the trusted execution environments or
other hardware you have on a device.
It's called the Capacitor secure storage
plugin. It does not save to indexDB or
localStorage.
Now, for a development time convenience,
sometimes to speed up development, you
might want to say, "Okay, I want to be
able to refresh the page." Maybe you
don't have hot module reloading figured
out for whatever stack you're working
with. If you want to store it
temporarily as a dev thing to make it
easy to refresh and not have to recreate
your state cuz it's annoying to have to
I'll show you exactly what I'm talking
about. I'm going to refresh here.
And boom, I have to put I'm I'm I'm
logged out. I have to go and put my
reconnect, which this can be annoying if
you're doing a ver- a very rapid
iterative development loop.
So, as you might you want to say, "Well,
when I refresh, I want to deep link and
go back to that deep link so that I can
quickly develop."
If you want to add that in a development
time, that's okay, but don't let it go
to prod. Do not let that go to
production.
And use the use the secure plugins if
you're going to use something like Ionic
Capacitor.
Okay, where are the keys stored? We beat
that one to death. We know that Signify
controller key is the Edge encryption
key and delegation key only.
AID root salts
that are only ever unencrypted at the
Edge, which is where all signing
happens. You can just think of it as an
HSM.
And when they are stored in KERIA,
they're encrypted.
They're encrypted before they're even
transmitted.
Okay, the other biggest one, you're
going to forget this. I every I forgot
this a couple times in the last couple
of days.
You need KERIA agent cores equals true
so that it properly responds to
preflight requests, the preflight
options requests.
So, make sure when you're viewing your
“keria start”,
when you're whether you're starting in a
Docker container,
whether you're running it local just the
regular raw Python virtual environment,
you need ker agent cores equals true.
you need “KERI_AGENT_CORS=true”.
You put that as environment variable in
your in your CI scripts, in your
deployment scripts.
We really should just make this the
default behavior. I need to do a PR to
make that the default behavior. I mean,
I don't know anybody that doesn't deploy
this way in production, so we'll
probably make that the default so that
you don't hit that over and over again.
Okay, multisig. How is multisig handled?
Multisig in KERIA is just like it is in
heavyweight wallets KERIpy
with the exception of
what transmit the messages. What's the
mailbox?
When you're doing multisig, you need to
know how to communicate with each
member, which means you need to know
where their witness or whatever's acting as
their mailbox is so that you can send
them your multisig notifications.
In KERIA, that's your agent or their
agent.
Other than that, it's the same.
There was one I said there's a
delegation but there let's see. Let me
think about
There has been some I'm trying to think
of some bugs we've had over the last
year. Yeah, for all intents and
purposes, it's the same except for it
goes through the agents instead of a
witness.
Okay.
Okay, this is the only the other thing.
So, we're looking at 5 minutes. Good.
We'll be done with KERI config. Okay. I
do have a blog post that goes through
this pretty exhaustively. So, if you go
to kentbull.com,
go to the January 26th Configuring KERIpy
Controllers, Witnesses, and KERI
Agents.
You can go there. It's just
kentbull.com right there that post.
And I go in detail, but we'll quickly
walk through the most important parts of
a config file.
If you want to start up a KERI agent
server, you need a config file that has
at least the date property.
And if you want and one other thing you
you must have this block right here with
the CURLs, which is controller URLs, cuz
what happens is it takes this value and
binds to that port.
If you don't have And this name right
here matters.
Let me just sort of go forward to
that.
This name has to correspond to the name
when you do “keria start --name "keria"”
name. These two names need to match up.
That's the hardest part.
And then the other hardest hard part is
that you must have a value here so
that it can pull out the host and the
port to bind to that port. That's what
Python reads to do the port binding.
As long as you've got the port open, the
host right, you can use 0000 if you need
to.
And these names match, then you're good
to go.
Now, the other parts of the config, you
might say, "What would I use
the other parts for?" So, IURLs are
essentially identifier or AID URLs. Who
do I What are the Who are the contacts
that I want to resolve on startup for
every single agent? Cuz this config is
the agency config.
The way that config works in KERIA is
you configure the agency,
and then it copies its config to every
agent. So, if you want to bootstrap
So, let's say you have witness preferred
witness infrastructure and preferred
credential schemas that you want every
agent in your agency to know about, you
put them in your IURLs section, and
there's actually a DURLs section
specifically designed for credential
schemas and partial ACDCs. Like if you
have a trust chain like the GLEIF trust
chain, and you want your agents to
pre-resolve it,
there's you can add There's an IURLs
section for identifiers, and you'll
notice
these are all witnesses. So, what I'm
saying is I want every single agent
that boots up here to resolve these
three witnesses so that I don't have to
through the steps of resolving them
every single
every single time.
Anyway, so there's some tocks. This is
some more some more advanced stuff if
you need to do some CPU tuning and IO
tuning. This is where you're getting
more low-level into the async. So,
tomorrow I have a talk, HIO async
frameworks. It's it's even lower level
than this. This is where we'll get more
into tocks, but this is more into the
KERIpy
async framework called HIO, hierarchical
IO that […] design. That's what these
are refer If you As long as you know
what it's for, you'll sort of that
that's enough to sort of start to ask
another things. Okay.
Now, we are So, we kind of understand
why to use KERIA. Use KERIA when you
need a lightweight wallet. KERIA is
signified when you need a lightweight
wallet. When to not use KERIA? When
you need a heavyweight wallet.
[laughter]
And we talked about configuring. Now, go
build your AI agents with security
behind them and your steady agents.
[applause]