All right, so this is a developer focus
description for the async, the runtime
foundation of KERIpy.
And what this is that's essentially
what's the process, what's the execution
model, how does this run?
And
if I'm going to read the source code,
what do I need to know
in order for me to effectively
contribute
to the KERIpy code base.
And to learn it or to extend it.
And hopefully by the end of this
presentation you will have enough of a
mental map and a mental model to know
how to effectively talk to Claude
or Codex or another AI in case you need
to go and relearn this later to
concretize your own learning to anchor
it in
or to potentially extend it, you know?
So, all right, that's you're we're going
to go over a lot what structured
concurrency is, why it matters, how it's
superior
to promises async await
call backs and go to.
And then some common gotchas for when
you're trying to use KERIpy and why
things are done the way they are.
All right, so
hello is it's Evan, right? No, no.
Keanu.
All right, so you probably know a
fair bit of this already.
All right, so I know I've talked to you
about this before Joe. I was just
probably talking to you when we say
stuff about structured concurrency.
How many would say they're familiar
enough with
currency to be able to explain it?
Keanu.
You work at the KERI Foundation.
Well
I think Trio
the only time I've really dove into the
code was when we had to port
into the web
base there. Okay. Because we had to use
Trio because it was async. It was
asynchronous so we had to adapt it
because in the weather it was sync, so
we had to convert it and that's what
we did in the tutorial,
but I don't want to
Say something that is completely
wrong, so Okay, I see.
Okay.
So this is this will be valuable for you
then because maybe you haven't had as
much experience with the Trio async
runtime.
Great cuz my if I even if I have one
more programmer
that really deeply understands Trio
after this, that will be good because I
got to get this knowledge out of my
brain.
Who's going to ask a question? So I
think structured concurrency is just
multi-threading and then how you
actually come to a
finality?
It's a good question. You're going in
the right direction. It's not
multi-threading. Okay. Are you familiar
with co- go co-routines?
Not in Python, no. So it's a lightweight
co-routine construct from go lang. I
just said the go co-routines. A lot of
people one of the reasons why go became
so popular is people like the simplicity
of the mental model with go co-routines.
Python co-routines are actually better
than go co-routines in my opinion, the
way Sam uses them in Trio.
So if you want to think about what the
unit the base fundamental unit of
concurrency in a structured concurrency
framework is, it's a co-routine
that is cooperative with the other
co-routines. Usually a thread
you'll have a lot of it's it's like
a fundamental
construct where it doesn't matter if you
block within one thread and the reason
why you use threads is because you want
to have a main thread that's not blocked
by work that will block that you put to
another thread.
If you want to adopt the mindset of
structured concurrency, you need to
think from a non-blocking mindset. Often
it's called a reactive mindset. So zero
of the co-routines should block.
And you might wonder, how is that
possible?
The way this is implemented at the IO
level with network IO and file IO
is in a fundamentally non-blocking way.
What and how do you do that? You
essentially chop up your IO reads and
writes into chunks and then you So,
it'll be blocking ever so slightly to
process one chunk and then it'll move
on.
But it's fast enough, right?
Exactly. It doesn't like it's like it
doesn't really block.
And not only that, but if you look
at the low-level socket implementation
in Hio,
it's it waits for a chunk and if
there's an error, it just waits and then
schedules itself for the next cycle of
the root scheduler to schedule that
co-routine again.
Okay. So,
we're we're still at the first two
slides two slides, so you're good.
So, we're talking about what structured
concurrency is. The fundamental unit of
structured concurrency, which we will
beat to death
in the rest of this as a doer, it's a
co-routine.
A non-blocking co-routine. And if you
look at the readme of Hio that we're
diving into, it says,
a waitless hierarchical structured
concurrent cooperative concurrency
runtime.
Now, you might say, let's dive deep into
structured concurrency. Well, let's go
all the way back to 1968.
You might have heard of Edgar Dijkstra.
He's very popular in the computer
science space. There's a Dijkstra
pathfinding algorithm and lot lots of
other things.
He wrote an article back in 1968 that
says, go to statement considered
harmful.
And it's actually not that long. This is
the whole article, this page and this
page.
And he says a key part statement, the
unbridled use
of the go to statement
has an immediate consequence that it
becomes terribly hard
to find a meaningful set of coordinates
in which to describe the process
progress. He's trying to say this is
very difficult to understand from a
procedural standpoint where I'm at in my
procedure if I've got go-to statements
that could take me to arbitrary places.
And we'll we'll give you a bit of a
I'm going to give you a visual here. So,
this is flowmatic. It's it's it's it's
like basic. It's like some of the early
programming languages and
this is a jump, but a jump is a go-to.
And it's saying, "Okay, when you get
down here, if this set of conditions
happens, go to operation two."
Well, that seems like it might be okay
till you get a lot of go-to statements.
And now how do you how do you
how do you understand what the
boundaries are here?
Have you ever heard of solid programming
principles? Highly cohesive, loosely
coupled? Where's the loose coupling?
That looks like tight coupling spaghetti
code.
Right? Well, that's where the name
spaghetti code came from. Right. We
don't like this. This is bad. This is
hard on humans. It's hard on LLMs.
Nobody likes it.
Now, the reason if we go back to couple
slides,
so go-to, the go statement in go for go
promises, callbacks,
they're all variations, if you look at
them closely,
of a go-to statement. And they the
problem is they break abstractions.
We as programmers endeavor
persistently
to have clean abstractions that let us
reason about the complexity of a
system that we're modeling. Like Sam
said earlier yesterday, all models are
wrong, but some are more useful some are
useful.
All of our models of abstractions of the
real world are wrong, but they're useful
to accomplish a certain end. They're
abstractions.
We try really hard with software
architecture to have invariants about
abstractions, conditions that are true
no matter where our system is at. And we
create state machines to ever so
specifically describe the behavior in
the states of our system.
Well, that only works if our
abstractions are stable.
Go to break sub fractions,
which means So, if you want to If you
want to look at So, that's what There's
a very good article by a man named
Nathaniel J. Smith, not related to Sam
Smith,
where he talks about structured
concurrency
in the context of a go to statements in
in the context of structured
concurrency. And he talks about
That's where this picture comes from.
He shows you how effectively a promise,
whether it's a JavaScript promise
or a
which is async await in JavaScript,
or in Python, where you have async
await, they're go to statements.
They really are.
And I'm not going to go into the deep
So, we have so much to cover today. I'm
not going to You just go read the
article. It's It height You're going to
be so happy you read the article. Let me
go to
There's actually a couple of articles
cuz he talks about what about timeouts
and cancellations. How do we How do we
thread that through the code without
making it explode and blow up and look
ugly? This right here, vorpus.org blog,
just search no sun structured
concurrency. You'll get these at You can
take a picture now or get it with the
digest that Kim's going to give
everybody later. This link is in the
notes.
What's fascinating is that Samuel Smith and
another excellent engineer, Charles
Lowell, who wrote affection, which is a
structured concurrency library in
JavaScript, also TypeScript, they both
cite this article as their inspiration.
I highly recommend and in the
wallet that I put out
in preparation for yesterday's talk on
KERIA,
it's a job TypeScript application. It
uses affection structured concurrency.
And we'll see a little bit of that code
later in this presentation.
So, you If you want to understand in
precise intricate detail why promises,
callbacks,
the go channel go lane go channels are
different kinds of
go to statements expresses concurrency
constructs, read this article. And
you'll At the end of it, you'll be
disgusted with the different kind of go
to statements. And you'll say, "How can
I repair my abstractions? How can I have
clean abstractions?" Highly recommend
this article. You're just going to love
it. It's kind of kind of long, so you
get a nice refreshment or give
yourself an hour or two.
Okay, so we feel like we understand
So, what is structured concurrency? Let
me get Let me jump forward to a couple.
There's a Let's see, do we have
it? It's a little bit further down.
Sam has a nice I should have brought
over So, I'll I'll show you sort of
this is a borrowed diagram from Sam
Smith.
So, with anything, what So, what's
interesting, you might say, "Well, let's
talk about root Python, the async
await." What it is the asyncio has an
event loop, and the event loop runs any
function that has async in the function,
right? That's how So, the way in Python
you use their native async support
is it's that it'll just run a
generator for you. And the way you
declare a function as a generator is you
mark it an async function.
The async function is the only way you
can run
This is not Hielo. This is just regular
Python. The only way you can run an
await statement inside of a function is
if you declare it
with async as async def, right? That's
the signal to the Python runtime to plop
it into the asyncio event loop,
so it'll get scheduled. If you don't put
async in front of it,
it won't get scheduled, and then it'll
never get run. Well, now let's take that
kind of that mental model, and let's do
the Hielo version of it.
The root scheduler is called a doist.
The doist is what will run all of your
async tasks. There are two kinds of
async tasks in Hielo.
There's the do-doer and the doer. Now,
the do-doer is an aggregation
construct. You can run many child tasks,
and it can schedule them. So, the
do-doer is like a little bit of a
combination of a scheduler
and a task. It has a recur It has a
function where it'll perform work and it
has the ability to add more tasks to
itself. You'll see a little bit of
similarity between Hiero's structured
concurrency design and other async
frameworks like Trio and Curio
as and affection as we go on. But this
is So at a high-level architecture
diagram, this is what we're dealing
with. Primarily three concepts.
The scheduler,
a task aggregator that's also a task
itself,
and a task.
This is the fundamental unit of
execution in Hiero.
The doer. This is your task.
You can see this like a task group.
Schedulable task group.
Okay, and did we talk about
So the guy who wrote this article about
fixing this problem.
So there's
Why would we use structured concurrency?
This slide says a couple of benefits.
The biggest benefit is my first bullet
point here. Program flow or task flow
follows lexical scope. Now, what does
that mean?
It's
it means that the execution of the
program will follow your intuition as a
programmer.
You're going to write a function. You
expect control flow to go from the
beginning of the function to the end.
And when that function is over, you
expect operations you've created in that
function to have completed. Unless
you're doing threads or processes, in
which case you might return a handle
from the function to sort of go later,
but structured concurrency, usually the
mental model is
if I have a function that
fires off a bunch of tasks,
all of those should complete by the time
the function returns. Okay. And so what
you're doing is you're turning the
function
into a bit of a almost like a scheduler
of a bunch of subtasks. Are you familiar
with Erlang and a process supervisor?
No. Okay. That's a good mental model.
Erlang or Elixir?
No. so it's there's a process super
supervision model.
But I'll I'll leave that terminology
aside.
The way to think it'll be clearer as
I get further into the code examples,
but essentially
the idea is that
if I enter into a function
and that function has tasks in it,
there's a guarantee that structured
concurrency provides that all those
tasks will finish or be canceled
by the time that I leave that function.
What that does is now you don't have any
So, the promises break this
because what happens if
my
my outer scope cancels and returns and
then my promise returns later. Well, now
it's a different scope. It's a different
function scope. You might use closures
or other things to try to transfer state
to callbacks to promises as a kind
of a callback.
But, promises break this. So, what
essentially what this is saying
is that
your function is a kind of abstraction.
That function
you're not going to break the boundary
of that function cuz by the time that
function returns, everything in it will
be completed and you'll see that in code
in just a minute. Another thing,
so child tasks cannot outlive their
parent scope.
A function is like a parent scope.
All tasks you spawn within that will
finish before their parent returns. And
Heo enforces this with the dot done
attribute. Go ahead.
You When you say lexical scope, that
just makes me
my brain I go to the program task flow
can't outlive. Like, when the variables
that you declared in that scope go out
of scope,
the task outflow is also complete. Yes,
exactly. Precisely.
That's right.
Yes. Now, now that's a common structured
closures and stuff. Like, you basically
say you don't have to deal with any of
that because
everything happens in context with stuff
that's in context with it.
Yeah. You don't have to pass any of that
state around cuz it's
you will you just avoid that problem.
Yes, that's correct.
Okay. This
make sense this seems much more simple.
Exactly.
That's why people use it.
That's the whole selling point for
structured concurrency.
But it feels more complicated for some
reason. It will Well, well, you know
Venkat Subramaniam, he's one of the most
popular speakers in the JVM space. He
says it's unfamiliar. It's not that it's
difficult, it's unfamiliar.
Cuz once you learn structured
concurrency, you're like, "Oh, that maps
more onto how my brain thinks."
So, there's a little bit of upfront
learning curve, but then you're like,
"Oh, this is so straightforward. I like
this."
What do you call that concept in the
Java world?
Is that a like a task?
So, they're they're trying to do I think
there's a fiber, if I remember right.
There's
JVM 22, I believe, is trying to do some
integration with some structured
concurrency, but it's ugly. It's not
very nice.
And Pythons and JavaScripts are very,
As far as their Trio is the best Python
structured concurrency library out
there. It's not the most usable, but
as far as the most intuitive, by far the
most intuitive. David Beazley, a big
name in the space has space has one
called Curio that you'll see referenced
later. And then Nathaniel Smith has one
named Trio.
And then there's Sam's.
I've looked at all the other ones. Sam's
is the best.
It's not the most usable as far as
like there's there's nice wrapper
functions because the other ones have so
much more adoption, they hit a bunch of
problems, and there's a little bit more
wrapper functions to adapt them into the
async await stuff. The async await is a
dumpster fire. Does Java have async
await?
Or
They better never get it. It's a
dumpster fire. I hope It's too bad that
it infected Python. It's future. I think
that's where it is. Async await, the
JavaScript form of async await, was
forced upon the world because of the
limitations of the browser execution
engine. It was a mistake to put that
into the Python runtime itself. They
should have done structured concurrency.
The Guido, if there's any mistake that
Guido made, the benevolent dictator
for life until he resigned
in Python, it was putting async await
into Python.
They shouldn't have done that. It's
really ugly and garish. It works, but
it's over it's overly simplified.
They should have they should have
because people were complaining about
generators. They were saying they're too
hard.
But, you know, you can you can you can
make frameworks that abstract the hard
parts and still preserve the structured
concurrency guarantees. So, Python had
an opportunity
the whole language ecosystem had an
opportunity to do adopt structured
concurrency and they missed it. And now
there's there's libraries.
Okay, so other important guarantees of
structured concurrency, if you spawn in
a lexical scope, you will join before
that lexical scope returns. And
indeed and here that means
if you have a do-doer and you spin up
some child processes, those will get
to the done state before the do-doer
finishes. So, the doist
will own all of its children will
complete before the doist returns.
And
one some nice consequences of this is
then we have straightforward execution
handling. Failure cancellation
propagation throughout the task tree is
very intuitive from child tasks up to
parent tasks.
And now you can intelligently respond to
both failures and cancellation signals.
And there's actually a
sister article to the one that I
mentioned earlier, the note the notes on
structured concurrency go to statement
considered harmful. There's one on
timeouts and cancellations. And then
there's one on control C and interrupts.
You want to read all three. They're so
well written.
Okay, so and exceptions are carried all
the way up through the scheduling tree.
This is one of the major benefits of
structured concurrency is that you can
have error propagation all the way up to
the root scheduler and handle it there
or in any of the parents. It's a It's an
intuitive, straightforward way to handle
exceptions.
So, consistent, predictable exception
behavior. Very, very awesome and
amazing.
Okay, so there's Trio nurseries from the
guy who wrote the article that you're
going to go read. And this is a This is
an example from his article
about the So, he uses async with the his
async with is essentially a doist or a
do doer for and he and he or just think
of it as a as a as a doist.
So, you start one task, which might
have a child task, which might have a
child task.
And all of those complete before the
outer bounding lexical scope of the
async with returns.
And because it's a context manager, that
means you can have startup and teardown
logic that will complete predictably for
all these tasks, for any resources that
you need to open or close. It's kind of
Java started to go in this direction
with the try with resources, with the
auto closeable interfaces, but they
didn't go to full structured concurrency
like this.
Okay, so I talked about Hiero and doers
a bit. We went here. We'll sort of
breeze past this. You already know the
doist, doer, do doer. Let me
double-check our time here. Oh, we've
only got 19 minutes left.
So, now we're getting into the Hiero
internals. You get some of the at a high
level and an object level what the
benefits are. Let's Let's anchor this in
some code.
So, we mentioned the doist is the root
scheduler, the code routine tasks are
the doers and do doers.
We won't get into the details of time.
It's really fascinating. It's really
interesting. I highly recommend you read
the source. I had to read it a couple of
times.
And this is before AI came out, by the
way.
Now you can ask AI and it'll walk you
through it much faster than I learned
it. But the you need to
understand the outer scheduler has
its own concept of time.
And it accumulates time. There's only
you'll see the one sleep in the entire
system. There's only one sleep, and it's
in the doist, the root scheduler. And it
keeps track of its own cycle time, so
that and you don't need to worry about
completely understanding this, but just
anchored in your brain somewhere, the
doist keeps track of time so it can have
deterministic scheduling of its array of
tasks.
In order to make it deterministic, it
has to keep track of its own sense of
elapsed time from the start. You always
start at zero and increase.
If you keep track of your own time and
your own sort of talk, essentially your
your next how long you're going to
sleep before you advance to your next
execution of your array of
coroutines. You have to have an internal
concept of time. This came and bit me
and cost me 40 40 to 80 dollars in
in AI tokens with Codex.
Because the it wasn't able to model
reality and realized that oh, HEO has
its own concept of time and I actually
hit that as a bug.
[laughter]
So, you realize LLMs are going to
struggle with structured concurrency.
And if you don't know how to tell it to
do the right thing, you might waste tens
of dollars of tokens like I did. I'm
glad it wasn't hundreds.
So, remember, doist has its own concept
of time, but we won't get into that
here. It's another presentation.
All right, so we're going to anchor this
in with some actual
commands. And we're going to go through
the KERIpy code base. If you've used
KERIpy,
you've done KLI.in.set.
What this does is it calls into what's
called KLI.py this main function. This
is the entry point for the command line.
The important part is it says run
controller.
That's important because it calls the
root scheduler.
Here, run controller has these three
lines, defines the talk, which is the
run rate of the cycle time, how
quickly the root scheduler iterates over
all of its tasks.
Which means this is 1/32 of a second, so
it'll 32 times a second it'll run its
entire task list. Unless there's like
something that takes some time to
execute. Here's the instantiation of the
root scheduler. And then we say root
scheduler.do. This is a life cycle
function. This is the life cycle
function that runs the system.
So, this is the entry point of the Hio
runtime.
Okay, we don't have to worry about those
other parameters just yet. Let's get
through this.
And so, here's the whole class outline
of the doist. Here's the do. The do
calls all of these other functions.
These enter, recur, exit.
So, think if for enter think
resource allocation and exit resource
closing. That's what the enter and exit
context is. There's an enter and an exit
for every task
in the Hio ecosystem. So, every doer has
an enter and an exit.
Which think about it. Now, that means it
can be used as a context manager. Cuz
what does a context manager do? When you
do with this,
what you're doing is you're saying,
"Give me a before and an before to
allocate resources and an after to clean
up." That's why people use context
managers or try with resources in Java
or languages like that, so that you can
have automated cleanup.
And so, what the enter and the exit do
is it allows you to make arbitrarily
smart your coroutines.
Python coroutines by themselves are dumb
and stupid. You can't add this nice cool
logic to it. This is a big selling point
of Hio
is that your tasks have an enter and an
exit.
J- just about everything else in the
space only has a recur.
Go ahead. So, can you provide Can you
implement handlers to those They're
essentially events, you know, when you
enter or when you exit then you can
attach handlers and then react to it?
It's it's it's Think of in terms of
subclass. You subclass the doer You
subclass and then you override those
functions. That would be equivalent of
handlers. Okay, so now let's go deeper
into the do function. You'll see.
So, the red arrows
are the life cycle functions. Remember I
said enter, exit, recur?
Enter.
where are we? Recur, I guess I made this
one special cuz I'm going to go there
next. There's enter and exit, startup,
teardown.
We've got the recur, which we're going
to jump into later. Here's the only
sleep in the system. There is one sleep
in the entire duet run time. It's this
right here. This is what accumulates
time, so essentially starts to
track the time elapsed to know when to
schedule the next co-routine.
So, you and also, let's see.
One thing to be aware of, that self.that
enter, what it does is it takes all of
your tasks and runs enter on every task.
So, by the time that finishes, all your
resources have been provisioned for all
the tasks that are going to run. After
that one line? After that one line, yes.
And what it does is it advances every
single It advances every single
co-routine to be primed to be ready,
essentially.
So, that readies all the tasks for
execution, and then recur begins the
infinite while loop to run all of your
tasks until you get a an abort an
interrupt signal, which will then
trigger exit. Like control-C will
trigger exit, and it'll exit all of the
child tasks, and then their nested
tasks, and then it'll finally exit the
duet.
That's one of the That's one of the cool
things about structured concurrency.
Okay, so we're going to jump in. Let's
jump in. So, now this is recur,
remember? So, we went from
that we're going into the blue arrow, or
the teal green arrow.
This is the recur function. The main
thing here is So, what actually runs
We're still in the scheduler. When are
we going to get to the task? Well, right
here, this send. And that send right
there, that's the Python generator API.
When you run cuz remember, the
co-routines are just generators.
And the generator the syntax to run a
generator
is this send right here.
So, you don't have to It's You can ask
Claude about or Codex about it.
There's also a really excellent So,
Luciano Ramalho, the guy who wrote the
Python reference manual,
his 2016 version of the book has a
really great chapter on co-routines. And
then when the whole Python language
community went the wrong direction to
the oversimplified async await,
for the 2022 version of the Python
reference manual, he did not include
that awesome content on co-routines, but
it's on his website. So, you can go to I
think it's fluppy.com
and you'll find the chapter 16, I think,
on the co-routines. It's it'll go
through that in exhaustively in-depth.
It'll teach you everything you want to
know about Python co-routines.
High-density, high-value content.
Anyway, so this is what runs it. We
won't worry about the rest of the stuff.
So, this interest interestingly enough,
last note on the root scheduler, this
tick advances you forward that next 1/32
of a second. It starts the next time it
schedules the time sleep, after which
the next iteration of all the tasks will
occur.
Okay, so now let's go into the
individual task. What it does, that dot
send calls you might be familiar with
other dunder methods, the underscore
underscore methods in Python.
It calls the call method of a doer.
And what the doer does is it says
self.do. So, what that send does,
this
the and it's dog, I won't get into the
syntax here. Dog stands for doer
generator. Okay, [laughter] there's some
Samisms here that it takes a little bit
of time to get accosted accustomed to,
but this is essentially the generator
that is the subtask.
The dog. So, we're doing the send
and that eventually results in self.do.
Now, why is that important?
The doer.do is the entry point into the
life cycle of one task. And let's let's
look at that. Here's the doer.do.
So, look at that. We've got an enter,
exit, and a couple of other life cycle
functions for different reasons that we
can get
we don't have time to get into, but
there's there's a clean, there's an
abort, there's a cease for when the
generator And the important thing is
that
Okay, you see the enter and the exit,
startup teardown, and you see the recur.
So, self.recur. This will actually
execute the self, but there's another
important thing
that you need to know a little bit about
Python generators to know how this
works.
See how we say is generator function,
Self dot recur.
What that means is if you have a yield
statement, this is how Python works. If
you put a yield or a yield from in a
function body,
it turns that into a generator.
If you're going to do anything with
IO, the network, files,
that yeah that's usually some where
you're going to have to wait. And
usually you use some sort of yield or
yield from or async await. You need to
drive that
in a way to where it can be paused and
resumed later. That's what the generate
That's what generators are used for in
Python. So, you need to use yield from
syntax to drive the generator function.
The generator function will stay inert
and it'll never execute unless you have
a yield from.
So, if you have a recur function in a
task that needs to call some business
logic that's going to execute like a
network call or a file call, you need
this yield from. This is what runs
you can put synchronous logic in here
and the in your in your recur and it'll
it'll execute this line, but when you
have async logic, you must it'll it'll
call the yield from.
Now, let's we're going really fast and
we I know we only have 10 minutes left,
so I'm going to do my best to just keep
on going.
If it's uncomfortable, if you don't
aren't quite tracking, it's okay. Let's
get to the end and then we'll we'll get
to some questions.
So, we went to the from the doist.do
to the recur
of the of the of the of the main event
loop or scheduler. And now we're going
to the individual task do. And the
individual task do is taking us to the
recur of the task.
So, and you'll see it's empty except for
return false. You have to subclass it if
you want to do work, right? So, the
the main doer construct is almost
like an abstract class in the sense that
you need to subclass it, override the
recur, and that's where you call your
business logic function.
And the false there is interesting. So,
if you return false, it'll keep
running until you return true. Because
the way that you end something is you
return true cuz it's the done or not
status. So, return true sets done to
true in the root scheduler for that
task.
That's why the default is to return
false.
Now, this is an example
from the KERIpy code base. If you've
used KERI it all, you probably have to
deal with database migrations. We have a
doer that does database migrations. We
have a recur.
And so,
we Okay, we open up the database.
And then after that, so really this
database stuff should be in an enter
function. Whoever wrote this wasn't
trying to fully embrace the life cycle
functions. This is set up that really
should be
in a
What do you call it? And you notice,
where's the cleanup?
We need an enter and an exit function.
So, this is not as good as it could
be, but it's sort of sufficient for now.
So, we run all this business logic, we
run database migrate, return true.
Runs the database migrations, return
true, and it's done.
So, this is a basic task. If I do CLI
migrate run,
this will that'll trigger this.
It'll migrate your database version.
Now, if you're going to look through the
rest of the KERIpy code base, you
might say, "Why do we use so many do
doers, but not many doers?"
And it's because
of one function, doing.doify.
[laughter]
That's kind of funny.
Yeah, it's it's Sam has a really
fascinating naming policy.
But what doify does,
it essentially allows you to use yield
from in the body of a function. Remember
how I said structured concurrency says,
"Program flow follows lexical scope."
The reason why doify is used is because
it allows that sort of intuitive program
flow to follow lexical scope
contract to be met. And it's easy to
essentially schedule a lot of subtasks
in one lexical context that makes
intuitive sense.
And so, I'll give you an example here.
Oh, so and actually there's a
difference. So, this is the do doer
function. You'll notice there's a
critical difference. So, the reason why
you use doify is because there's there's
something that
I think is my opinion it's missing
from do doer.
I think Sam argues differently. He
argues for a different or
way to arrange things.
Personally, I think that the way that we
use doify
is evidence
that we should add the missing part
here. See here we have self.recur, but
we don't have the generator check.
Remember the generator check? If I go
one slide over, here's the doer.
We say if is generator yield from. So,
what this means is a do doer will not
allow you to use yield from in its
recur. That's why we use doify all the
time. And Sam has this argument about
hierarchical state machines is the right
place to use state to essentially
manage multiple sets of doers, and then
you have a scheduler doer that manages
other doers as a set of doers within a
do doer. There's an argument there, but
I don't think it's very intuitive.
I understand the argument. Maybe I just
need to maybe I'm just unfamiliar and I
need to learn that. But to me, the fact
that we use doify so much is
evidence that we should add
this is generator
in the doer and see now we're in do doer
right above here. We should put that is
generator check and run it that way in
my opinion. And you'll see why. So, now
let's get to the code. But notice the do
doer has the same life cycle functions.
Enter, exit, clean abort sees, and we
call recur.
So, the do doer
And you'll notice this return self.done
for when a task is done, true or false.
The difference between the do doer and
the doer that is the do doer you can add
it's extend or remove. You can add tasks
to it or remove tasks to it. So, it's an
aggregation construct. The doer is not.
So, you can see how the do doer is a bit
of a combination between a scheduler
and a task, but the doer is just a task.
Okay, so
There's There's There's an example. So,
back to the K Alliance Sept.
Inside of the init function for the
Incept doer, what you'll notice is a do
doer. We call doing.dot doify on the
main function that runs everything.
What that does
Here's the Incept do. You see we have a
yield from yield from. It's
pretty intuitive to co-locate a lot of
that logic. Rather than create a
complicated state machine and worry
about the state of this doer and that
doer and sort of schedule them at the
right time, we just locate them in the
same lex- lexical cons- scope.
That's pretty easy for humans to
understand that program flow,
right?
That's why it's so handy. That's why in
my opinion
we this really should be a recur
function, and the recur should allow you
to use these yields and yields from
in the body
of the do doer's recur.
That's not how it works. I actually did
go through the trouble
in the did:webs repository in our tests
to do it the way that Sam recommended,
and it's kind of interesting. It does
make you clean up your code a little bit
cuz if you And so, I can see There
There's an argument there. And what it
does is essentially the mental model is
if you're going to do things the right
idiomatic way according to Sam's
idea, every place where you have a yield
from should essentially be a separate do
doer, or sorry, a separate doer.
You would You have at least one, two,
possibly three more here. And what you
do is you would add all of those
You would See how we have a list of
doers here, and then we send it when we
say
call the constructor we init doers
equals doers.
What you would do instead of having all
those yield froms in one function, you
would make separate doers for that sub
part of the task, and you'd have that be
part of the task array that you send to
yourself when you're scheduling
yourself.
So, you can You can see it sort of force
you to lift things out, and make
dependencies more explicit. It's kind of
like smaller functions versus larger
functions. So it is more hygienic in
some senses, a little bit more
convoluted. So it's a bit of a
trade-off.
So
Now I'm I'm just mixing affection. So
affection is a JavaScript structured
concurrency library. Now that you
understand
the yield from syntax and the yield and
whatever, now you can see what it looks
like in JavaScript cuz JavaScript has a
construct that's like yield from.
If you see yield star in JavaScript,
it's the same thing. It runs a
co-routine
from that spot. So this is using the
affection
structured concurrency library
just like we you know how we did
doing.do.doify.
This is part of why I lean in favor of
making do doer.recur do allow yield from
because in affection in the structured
concurrency library in TypeScript
JavaScript
this whole function is like a doified
function.
You can have as many yields yield stars,
which are yield froms, as you want and
just sort of naturally proceed forth in
an execution chain in one function.
And so you'll see I'm saying yield from
list identifier service and we'll look
at that one layer deeper.
This actually it wraps the Signify
client. You'll see it has a Signify
client right here.
This is the wrapper. The This is another
thing that I think is sort of missing
from HIO that we could add to it.
Wouldn't be that hard to add it. Sam has
actually been experimenting with the
wrappers
More recently with trying to
integrate async await into HIO. It's
already done in the affection. We have a
we say call promise and turn it into a
generator.
This allows you to preserve the
structured concurrency guarantees
even when you use promises in
JavaScript. You'll have promises at sort
of the edge of your architecture and all
the nice stuff in between you'll have
your structured concurrency guarantees.
Just call a library you're importing
that you can't control.
Exactly. Precisely. Promise. Yeah. And
if you look at the wallet that I demoed
yesterday for my I a I need a really
need to wrap up. Oh.
okay, let me just run through the end.
Okay, the last thing is
Look just look at these in the slides
later. You'll see this weird
convention used everywhere in curio pi
the self.wine talk and yield. And what
it is there's something with all
generators in JavaScript and in Python
where you need to prime it. Prime it
means advance to the first yield. You
don't want the priming of your generator
to run business logic.
You don't want it to come down here, so
you put this yield at the front. I think
that should be handled by a framework in
my opinion.
It's kind of weird to force people to
manage that, but that's why this exists.
And
Okay, and I would say there's
Oh, get we'll we'll cut it there.
That's that's that's heel.
[applause]