Just really quickly as we get our
conversation just started, I wanted to
Give a couple of quick ground rules.
First of all some of my questions
might be fairly open and broad and
lead to some pretty long-winded
potentially long-winded answers. So just
be conscious of the time and the
respectful of everybody and make sure
we give everybody a chance to chime
in. Also, all the questions, even if
I direct maybe at one person, they're
all open to all of you. So, if you feel
like you want to say something about it,
by all means, jump in anytime. So, with
that, our the theme for this
conversation, this chat tonight is
in effect, what does KERI make
possible that isn't possible without
KERI? So, in that frame,
the first question I have is a little
bit of an ex existential question, I
guess. Why are you here?
And what I mean by that is kind of
what's the story again being respectful
of the time and all that. What's the
story that leads you to sitting in this
chair at this time? What's your aha
moment with KERI? What brought you to
this point? I'm going to just kind of
open this one up as a bit of an
introductory question for everybody.
Alan, I want to start with you. Well, I
guess I should start by saying that I
I genuinely believe that we should all
be our own identity providers and I
don't see how you can do that without
either KERI or something very similar
and that's why I'm here to see that
happen.
Great. And did you have a particular aha
moment with KERI when you fi founded
and or was it more of a gradual thing
for you or
it's been a gradual thing and a
continuing education by Sam
it's a it's a continuing process I can
tell you
that's good Thomas
I would have to say for me the aha
moment coming from the blockchain
space was realizing that what Sam has
invented is all of the things that we
value about blockchain
without the negatives.
Okay, cool. Yeah. And when did you
actually first get introduced to Sam or
to KERI in general?
It's it's going to be about four
years now.
Yeah.
Okay. It's been a while. All right,
Nico.
Yeah. So, you know, this kind of brings
me back to Sovereign, right? I was
introduced by Timothy Ruff
randomly messaging me on Twitter as a
pseudonmous account whether or not I
wanted to invest and the opportunity and
failure of sovereign was the exact
catalyst for what led me to KERI.
Obviously like the opportunity of
decentralized identity was massive and
not realized there. And I knew there
was something beyond a blockchain when I
was posting, I remember on the Telegram
of Sovereign about something like a
microleddger and Timothy actually
messaged me in a sideh show like who
told you about microledders? It's like
it's like no, I just came to it on my
own idea and we started talking about
the implications of what could be beyond
how do you scale a chain beyond this
sort of one chain to rule them all. And
then subsequently, you know, when
things are looking their bleakest
Sam comes out with the white paper and
Immediately it strikes me like, "Oh
my god, this is it. This is the endgame
of how identity needs to be created at
scale in a decentralized way." And I was
pleading for the rest of the sovereign
people to recognize what this was. And
no one else saw it. So we created
key state Capital to solve that problem.
I started working in the telco space
only a few years ago and not very deep
Into it and I'm a little bit of an
outsider in those circles. But the
thing that was shocking to me is that
large companies have invested billions
maybe tens of billions is a better
estimate in complying with regulations
like from the FCC related to
shaken in the United States.
And after 10 billion dollars of
investment they haven't solved the
problem even a little bit. It's like
almost as bad as it was to start with.
The only way to solve the problem is
with KERI.
I agree.
I want to ask a little bit about you
all come from it seems pretty different
problem spaces. Maybe there's some
overlap in some cases but what
solutions have you evaluated or seen
attempted to some of the problems that
you're particularly interested in?
And how have they what solutions
and how have they what solutions
have you seen attempted and how
have they failed
without now let's not get into vendor
bashing and stuff like that you know
we'll try to be nice as much as we can
but you know what have you seen as
failures and we'll go from there and
this is open to all of you so whoever
would like to jump in first I
I think for me I in particular when I
was working primarily in the blockchain
space was focused on consensus systems
So thinking about again how do you
scale recognition of an event
globally right and we went across many
different various obscure consensus
systems some that like are more than
proof of stake you have DAGs you have
parallel crystal streams it's it's it's
some crazy structures out there but I
think the bottom line is that you
need a system that is expressive enough
to if someone wants to define the limits
of consensus they can do so in such a
way that it can compose with another
consensus system because it all it is
governance right I'm going to push back
what
I'm going to push back I think with
KERI coming from the blockchain space
and consensus I think with KERI you
don't actually need consensus all you
need is one honest watcher to tell you
someone's lying.
I Wait, so hold on.
Well, maybe I misinterpreted what you
said.
No, no, no. I was leading there.
Okay. Okay.
Right. In the sense that like you don't
need consensus.
What you need is convergence.
Convergence on the truth.
To your question.
For me the failures that I have
for me the failures that I have
seen in the decentralized identity space
is when the logic of digital identity
was applied to decentralization of
finance where
Blockchain networks tried to do the
same thing they did with a token with
your identity. then you end up just
locking an identity into another network
with varying actual decentralization
And relying on purchasing of a token
for that identity to work and then not
really being able to use it outside of
that ecosystem. So for me the
failures are trying to apply what we've
applied to decentralized finance to
identity and that just does not work.
And why not like give us a little more
detail on Well, well, because
effectively your identity is once again
siloed into a network. It's relying on a
token. It's also non-existent once
that network fails or that chain
crashes. And it has no meaning or
authenticity outside of that network.
So I need multiple identities
across multiple chains of multiple
tokens that have multiple levels of
security. it just isn't the right way to
go about decentralized identity.
I'd like to comment that one of the
failure modes that I see and that I'm
deeply concerned about right now is the
idea of business wallets.
I think this is one of the most
dangerous and worthless efforts
that the world has ever come up with.
That's strong words, but I think the
that's strong words, but I think the
whole EU business wallet initiative is
destined for failure.
And part of the reason why is because
it's not respecting the first
principle which is you have to
have transparency. If you wrap a border
around an organization and say we're
going to think of everything inside this
organization as being atomic. We
can't decompose it in any way and we're
just going to say the organization
projects its identity outward and
everything inside of it is irrelevant.
you end up no matter what your key
management strategy is, no matter what
your credential formats are, whatever,
you end up in failure mode. And so in
some ways, this is a shout out to
Carla. I think the fundamental
principles of VLES
are deeply true. Those principles are
that an organization doesn't just have
authority because it exists. And people
who belong to an organization don't have
authority just because they belong to
the organization. They actually have
authority because they got delegated
authority from somewhere. And if you
can't track that down, you end up with a
massive failure mode for the whole
world.
Alan,
yeah, I see something that is a
continuing failure in the world
generally, which is something I call
identity theater. And I call
someone up and they say, "Oh, what's
your email address? What's your mailing
address?" They ask me a bunch of
questions that somehow are supposed to
prove that I am me. And I'll say, "So,
did that really prove that I am me?"
And they just laugh at the other end,
but they continuously do it. I went
through an airport the other day,
and they checked our passports five
times on the way through to the gate.
And
why
it's it's why it's it's just it's just
Security theater, identity theater,
whatever you want to call it, but it's
The SAD thing is that's
the that's the best that the business
world has at the moment. And they
seem to think it's okay.
Better things are coming.
Good. Okay. Speaking of theater, I'm
glad you brought that up because one
of the questions I wanted to ask and I'm
going to direct this specifically at
Thomas and Allan to start with just
because we heard your presentations
earlier today and both of you talked
about in different ways. Allan, you
mentioned kind of taking a bit of a
step-wise approach to getting KERI out
into the world and Thomas, you mentioned
a version of KERI maybe that's not
fully implemented as KERI as it is
defined. What do you see as the risks of
what you might call KERI theater where
where it's not fully KERI but that's
out there in the world but some form of
it? What do you see as potentially risk
that we need to be aware of in that sort
of situation?
I'll go first. I think it should be
Really as much of caring as is
necessary to make it fully secure and
privacy protecting. but there's
nothing wrong with that being built into
existing legacy applications to add this
layer of trustability onto existing
transactions that are at risk.
So but no it really if it if it's
not as much care as is needed to
make it secure and safe then that's
not going to be good enough.
Yeah.
I would agree. I think there are
scenarios perhaps whereby
You can take on the risk of not using
all of KERI. The KERI light method
that I mentioned that the Swiss
government are using from my perspective
is actually where you shouldn't be
taking those risks because you're
dealing about with digital identifier
people. I also think that the KERI
Light approach is just
The byproduct of someone on their
journey through KERI. I was about to
say that
it's it's almost part of that learning
roadmap to some extent
from my perspective but I would I
would emphasize that for digital
identifier for humans for people for
governmentsized
systems
Anything but real full KERI with all
of the five W's is a risk.
Fair enough. Nico, you looked like you
had something to
Oh, no. He took everything I wanted to
say. How rude. That's great. Daniel,
anything to add here?
I once proposed a KERI light
posture in our ecosystem and
there's certain conditions under
which you could operate with
less than what KERI provides, but I
don't think they apply at an ecosystem
level. I think that was a mistake.
Okay, good. My next question,
what well,
I'm going to open this up a little more.
I was going to say one thing, but I'm
not going to limit it to one thing and
put too much of a boundary on it. What
what have you taken what will you take
away I guess from this conference
that either enhanced your understanding
of KERI will change the way maybe
you approach or describe KERI or
what are you taking away with you from
being involved in this conference for a
couple of days the first inaugural KERI
conference
I would say first and foremost
If it's not perfect,
still put it out there. I mean, I think
the KERI Conference is a little bit of
a microcosm of that, right? It's our
first step at making a carryon only
conference. I think we did a great job
considering, but there's definitely ways
we can improve on it. There's definitely
ways that it can be expanded beyond
this. And the same thing with all
of the open threads that Sam's designs
has allowed us to pursue now this blue
sky of opportunities
that exists now in the world
because of this architecture.
The level of coordination and
communication that's necessary to
optimize our attention about what really
matters is one of the most important
choke points I think of our ecosystem.
That and money. So we need more money
too. So
indeed
I'm I'm going to take away how delighted
I am that the KERI community is as
not only as big as it is but growing so
fast and that's must be very
encouraging for everybody here but
especially Sam because it's his baby
and it's it's getting to a
difficult teens age I think but It's
maturing nicely.
Yeah. And I'll just personally add on
to that I'm I've been super
impressed how deep so many of you
guys already are in KERI and
understanding of I feel like I'm I'm
certainly a little bit of imposttor
syndrome even sitting in this chair in
the position that I'm in. Anyway
Thomas, you want to
One of my takeaways from some of the
conversations that I've been privy to
and observed is there's there's almost a
need to take all of the technical
contributors
Behind the various libraries and
lock them in a room so that they can
have effectively a technical standup
and have these conversations because
I've seen just actually through the
hallways from one session to another
devs talking to each other and
finding a path to solve a problem that
they've been dealing with and that's
just happened walking from one room to
another so I think not only is KERI
conference important to talk about
the specifications to talk about the
opportunities where revenue streams may
exist and what everyone is building
but also give the devs that are
typically only engaging in an online
environment that opportunity to lock
them in the room. Maybe not lock them,
but stick them in the room and allow
them to have that same dialogue that
I've seen happen just between rooms with
a with a focus kind of agenda. I think
that'd be extremely productive.
I like that. Yeah. Daniel,
I'll just say that I'm super
excited about the is it five
engineers, Sam, that you've you've got
working on your five Ws or maybe it's
five W's but three engineers or four.
Anyway those five W's are really
awesome and I'm looking forward to it.
That's maybe one of the things that I'm
most jazzed about. Wait, also I didn't
get a chance to see the mobile wallet
yet.
You didn't?
No.
Where's Keanu?
Or no, Jay.
So, so I want to see that. But also, and
you'll arrange that
regrettably as well. With Sam's
crippled voice right now. It was
that's why we recorded all the sessions
so you can see all of them,
right?
And additionally, I mean, I think
the transfer registry primitive
that's going to unlock a lot of new
opportunities. It's very interesting.
I'm curious to see how that fits with
the rest of the stack.
Cool. Yeah. So the theme that as we
introduced it is what's possible now.
That wasn't possible before. And
let's flip that for a minute and talk
about and some of you or maybe all
of you have had a chance to talk about
this to some degree. So, let's maybe
unpack it a little bit more. What isn't
possible right now with KERI and what
needs what do we need to change to make
KERI possible? Let's start with Daniel
and move work our way down or anybody
else want to chime in if you if you
don't.
Well I'd like to see the
the developer experience be one where a
developer says I heard that KERI was
interesting. I'm eating a sandwich on
my lunch break.
I wrote a you know a KERI online or
I asked chat GPT and three minutes
later I have something that you know
plugs up end to end or whatever. That
to me feels like a utopia. We're
working hard on that. But it will be
a while because there's just so much to
learn and there's so many things you
have to glue together. And I remember
Back in 2017, I saw the first demo of
a wallet that showed a proof
request and a response
You know in decentralized identity
circles. And it was such a from the
outside it was a really boring demo. It
was like somebody holds up a wallet
and they click a couple of buttons and
then they get a green light and they
showed it. And I freaked out when I saw
it because I knew there were like 2700
things that had to be right for that
demo to work and that's kind of how I
feel today.
Nice. And maybe applying this to your
specific space like what still
needs to happen yet for KERI to be
fully realized there? Well, in telco,
the demo that I showed everybody
when I kind of showed a canned video
included Google you know, a Google
handset verifying something for
KERI. Google built that. They signed
it. They showed it at this
worldwide conference, but it's not in
general distribution yet. I would really
love to see that happen. And Apple, who
started working on it, I'd like to see
them finish what they started.
Nico.
Yeah, I it's kind of a specific one
actually. But I
really am looking forward to when
someone builds an ambient watcher
network cache
where you can just propagate key state
to there and then just repeat that
when that comes online and it's
sufficiently decorrelated I think the
network effects of KERI and the
possibilities of multiple roots of trust
and their credential sets interacting in
the combinatorial explosion, right? The
Cambrian the KERI explosion, right?
Is that's when the value proposition of
is that's when the value proposition of
KERI really comes alive for me at least
in a theoretical sense. I don't know
there's so much that is possible to be
built with these data structures. It you
could talk about this all day. Please
continue.
Thomas, go ahead. I'd have to second
what Daniel said. I think one of
the biggest risks is there's a snowball
effect happening with KERI and
developers are hearing about it. They're
going to explore the ecosystem and maybe
they're going to shy away because it's
not the most ideal developer friendly
experience, especially when it comes to
troubleshooting and tracing out errors
within your code. And I mean, Fergal
actually ran a whole session on this. So
there's there's there's that element
of the experience to the developer. I
mean I think a lot of us see that as
just a pain we have to deal with for the
time being but we understand that the
journey is worth it. Outside of that
for me I would also like to envision the
ability to download the wallet and for
there to be a gossip protocol that
allows me to just choose which agent I
want to connect to. I'd love to see
that level of adoption and the
infrastructure roll out and I think SEDI
is actually one of those initiatives
that will drive that type of
infrastructure roll out as well.
Well, there's a scenario that
may be solvable and may have an answer
that but I don't know what it is yet.
So, I'm going to put this out as a
question to everybody. So the
scenario was that the u the governor of
the state of Utah has himself a SEDI
credential and a watcher network
detects duplicity.
What happens next?
Impeached.
It's a good question.
I'm looking for answers. We can't have
any political leader who says two
different contradictory things,
right?
That doesn't happen in politics.
Yeah. If anybody wants to try to throw
an answer out there,
I think you stumped him, Alan.
His people will do a rotation for
Should we revoke or revert? Oh, no.
Revise. Is it revise?
Actually,
it's a it is a bit more of a general
purpose question though where you have a
a regular human out there and
u some watcher network somewhere detects
duplicity on their key and this is
just some person who's going to inform
them what to do and
well you need to your wallet you should
have a local watcher that is informing
your wallet of any changes to your
key state that you didn't source And so
it can compare the two and see that your
witnesses don't agree with what you did.
And so it'll tell you, hey, there's bad
stuff just happened. What would you like
me to do about it? I can do a rotation,
repair it. Do you want to call? You
know, all of those are things are part
of the user experience that needs to be
developed to make it. That's what the
wizard in the five W's is for is to
figure out so that you can suggest to
people the right thing to do. One of the
things in critical physical security
that we had to figure out is that when
bad stuff is happening, the
security people that are monitoring the
cameras get overwhelmed very quickly.
And so you can't give them a menu of
options. You have to give them like one
button, press here, and then good stuff
happens. And so you have to figure out
what that press here does so that when
there's an emergency, they don't go,
"Crap, there's duplicity. My life just
ended." They need to be able to say,
"Oh, everything's okay." Right? So you
have to figure out. So you have to have
enough intelligence to be able to say,
"Okay." Right? And rotations are safe.
You can rotate a lot. It doesn't hurt
you to rotate. It's just friction. And
so you can try to reduce that
friction but make it so that it and you
know it's like that what's the worst
thing that can happen right you know is
that you rotate when you didn't need to
right but as long as you know I mean rot
rotation too much becomes a security
problem in and of itself but you can
manage that
but of course the pre-rotated key then
has to be stored somewhere else and so
yes that's why I said there's friction
there so you have you have to the
regular human.
Yeah. So, but that's why that's
why there's various things that we have
to work on to figure out all the
different friction points and figure out
how to solve those and it's
not those aren't trivial problems. So,
yes, it's it's it's a hard problem yet
to be solved.
Maybe the answer eventually is we all
have a little chip and that's where we
keep our pre-rotated key.
I want to throw in one other thing.
Go ahead.
Movie with Keano Reeves in it. That's a
really dystopian view of putting stuff
in your brain.
I want to throw in one other thing I'm
really looking forward to that we can't
do today.
And that is I'm looking forward to
the postquantum support in KERI.
I want Falcon to be in. Part of
why I want it to be in is because I can
see the train wreck happening everywhere
else.
And I know that we have a great story,
but it will be even greater when the
train wreck starts to have casualties
everywhere else and we say, "Come on
over." I we're ready. I mean, it
would not be that hard to add it in.
So that's just a little bug in
so that's just a little bug in
everybody's ear. Let's let's get that in
quickly. Something that just occurred to
me that I would love to see is a login
with KERI button
just everywhere.
Wouldn't we all? Yeah. Get rid of get
rid of the login with Google and GitHub
and all the other stuff and right
login with KERI.
All right. I actually don't have any
further questions. I wanted to open up
maybe to the group to ask questions
of our illustrious panel here. those who
haven't had a chance to maybe ask
questions or hear from some of our
guests.
I guess not. I guess we've covered it
all. We are coming to the end of or I
guess we are at the end of our
conference. We've had a chance to hear
from pretty much all of you at one point
or another and it's really been an
amazing experience. For me
personally, as a kind of new to the
KERI ecosystem, the KERI world,
it's it's really encouraging to see how
many other people have been thinking
about this for a long time and have been
working on this for a long time.
I've got a lot of catching up to do and
we're excited as a as a KERI Foundation
team to get in to start addressing
some of these problems that you guys
have brought up. So, in the last just
maybe few minutes, I'll give you guys
each a chance to kind of give your
closing statements and your last
little messages to the KERI Conference
are our first ever KERI Conference. No
time limit.
Dangerous.
Well, I'll go first by just saying
that all of the thanks goes to Sam
Smith. I mean, none of us would be here
without Sam. and I'm
looking forward to next year.
Indeed.
I think
one thing that's kind of come up in
some conversations I've been having with
fellow colleagues
From the W3C space that I just
wanted to share is
There's been a lot of work there in
standardization and for me there was
kind of a moment that shifted across the
last couple of months where what I
what I can acknowledge from the W3 three
spaces they have standardized the data
model and that's been that's been useful
for a lot of development work but I
believe that what we standardized here
with KERI is the trust model and
from my perspective that is something
that for me is what's keeping me here
keeping the team working hard
and I look forward to continuing the
journey.
Yeah, just in the same way building
off of Allan's sentiment I just
want to thank you, Sam, and also
everyone else here who's put their
blood, sweat, tears, and time into this
protocol and into the people. You
all make it an absolute pleasure to be
on this stage with and to share in
this sort of co-creation of a what
I view as a beautiful new future.
And
and
it's a joy. It's a joy to be in this
space and I couldn't be happier. The
duplicity game is a foot.
I'll just say that I think we all
need to protect our own identities and
reputations urgently.
If I were malicious I would,
Point AIS at a bunch of different
communities and have them wreak havoc.
Yeah.
And we have the tools to protect
ourselves, but we're not using them yet.
It would be great if we toolled up
GitHub so that you couldn't make a
contribution unless you could prove who
you were. It would be great if you
know our remote interactions were
protected and I'm seeing I don't know
how many of you are on the various W3C
mailing lists but they like us are
vulnerable to the assumption that
well-intentioned humans are the ones
that are going to show up and they're
having AIS show up in the you know in
the comment streams and the email
threads and so forth.
and they've shut those down. But
this is just going to get worse. And so
I think it might this is kind of a an
invitation or a shout out to people that
maybe it's time for us to solve our
own community's
Reputation and trust problem
before any havoc occurs.
And to the extent that's true for
our community, it's true for every other
community out there, too. So, the world
really needs what we have. Let's go give
it to them.
Well said. And a big thanks to our panel
today, our guests, and a big round of
applause for all our guys here.