Samuel Smith ｜ The Future of KERI ｜ KERI Conference 2026
So I guess I talked too much
yesterday,
so I guess I'm gonna be swallowing the
mic today.
Anyway, like to thank everybody for
showing up. Today we're going to
talk about a little bit about the
future. So, I did the past yesterday,
the present. Today's a little bit about
the future, a little bit about the past.
And I have a little teaser there. saving
the internet. I mean, the reason I
started doing identity was I wanted to
save the internet. I wanted to fix the
broken internet. And I didn't realize I
had to had to work on identity to do
that. And I know other people probably
knew that better than I did, but I
didn't realize that. So, one of the
things that the future of the KERI
suite is about more and more
applications that use ACDCs,
right? And those gave my talk la
last night talked a little bit about
what an ACDC is. So I just want to
review it a little bit. An ACDC is this
generic
graph structure for representing data.
And when we represent data in graphs, we
get all kinds of useful properties. And
so we've got a vertex and edges. And we
can use those to do all sorts of fun
things. But the most important thing
that ACDCs provide is perpetually
verifiable issuances. That's the hard
problem. It's solved that wasn't solved
before. And now that we have perpetually
verifiable issuances, we can do all
sorts of things we couldn't have done
before.
Each fragment is separately
authenticatable.
So that provides something that a normal
graph data structure doesn't do. Lots of
people have graph data structures, but
the whole data structure source from the
same source. Where with ACDCs, every
every node in the graph can have a
different source. So you can use them
for a lot of different things that you
couldn't use a graph data structure for.
And these are the things that you
can do with it. Delegable, attenuable,
aggravable, revable, revocable,
transferable, authority. And so we have
some talks today. Phil's going to be
talking both Phil's Phil and
Phil Windley about authorizations. We're
going to talk about stuff like that
so that's some of the things that now
that we have solved identity we solve
basic issuances now we can start to do
more complicated things with ACDCs and
so I see the future people are going to
find more and more things to use ACDCs
for. So the idea is we with ACDCs we
can have highfidelity modeling of real
world authority structures. Can you guys
hear me? I can't tell. Okay.
I can't hear myself because normally I
talk really loud and my whole head
resonates with my own sound. So it
sounds like nothing's happening. So one
of one of the things that we can do with
ACDCs is we can bridge AC KERI and
ACDCs solve the cross trust domain
transfer problem in an elegant way and
that's a hard problem to solve.
Recursive privilege escalation attacks
are a
Negative
consequence
of using identity systems that don't
solve the cross trust domain transfer
problem. Instead, what they do is just
increase the size of the one trust
domain because since you can't bridge
trust domains, make your trust domain
bigger. And that means now that you can
do recursive privilege escalation
attacks. If you keep your trust domains
small and bridge them properly, then you
don't have recursive privilege
escalation attacks. And so with KERI,
we can solve that problem. So the idea
is
that we have two trust domains and we
use ACDCs
to move data trust authority between
those domains. That was a cool effect,
right?
So perpetual identity leads to
perpetual issuances means, and I'm going
to steal Daniel Hardman's phrase,
lossless trust transfer.
We don't lose trust when we use carrying
ACDCs to move trust across trust
domains.
So if I have ephemeral identity, then I
only get ephemeral in issuances. That
means every time I trust I do trust
transfer, it's lossy. And that's what
we're living with right now in the
internet.
So now that I can have lossless conveyor
of trust, I can also use it to bridge
ephemeral trust domains and the bridge
doesn't lose anything. Normally when you
take cables and connect them together,
every connection is lossy. And so the
longer the connections, the less
signal you get. But if I have really
high fidelity connections, then I lose
it in other places. And so this is this
allows us to take any application that's
currently using the current stuff
right and we can bridge it better. So a
lot of the discussions people have is
well I want to use ACDC with whatever it
is
you know the some existing system. Well,
it's okay for us to use it to bridge
those existing systems as long as we
understand that we don't corrupt the
ACDCs with lossy stuff, right? And so
I already mentioned that the whole
idea is we can remove this is
like the bane of current security.
This thing recursive privilege
escalation attack vulnerabilities. It's
it's horrible and we can we can mitigate
that.
So I'm going to talk about when we talk
about end to end right in the in the in
the world we talk about edges but we
also talk about ends and in KERI
they're pretty much the same thing
because each AID is its own identity
provider we're using keys at the edge
the edge is where authentication happens
oh I guess I can do that there are no
third party IDPs no relying parties no
trusted intermediaries.
So we remove a whole layer of
infrastructure. It just goes away. Now
if somebody says you got to have it, you
got to have a relying party. You got
to have an ooth server. Fine. Leave it
in there. But don't use it to expand its
trust domain. Go. Well, you want to
bridge these two trust domains. Don't
bridge them with more lossy stuff.
Bridge them with KERI and ACDCs.
So in KERI an end to end, and an edge to
edge, they mean the same thing, right?
The middle doesn't matter, the middle
is just a store and forward network.
So that leads us to the next thing
that's going to happen in KERI more
and more and this is authorization.
What do I mean by that? Well I got this
word down here. I love I love making
anacronyms. I know somebody
said that's problem for people to
understand but you guys you guys you
guys are the tech people. So edge
verifiable access control. So what does
that mean?
Well,
I'm defining authorization
to access a resource is granted by the
resource controller. So I'm going to say
there's some authority that has
authority over a resource and if some
other entity wants to get access to that
resource that authority controller
grants that access and that access comes
through an authorization.
So each authority is itself an edge in
KERI with respect to other authorities
resources because it's all edgetoedge
end to end.
So each authority can authorize access
by any other edge to its resources via
an ACDC. That's the whole point of
delegable aggraable authority is that
you grant authority to somebody and now
they can access your resources
because you're the you're the you're
authority who can grant that access.
Each issuer in ACDC graph is potentially
both a resource authority and an edge.
Mutually authenticated edge accessor and
resource authority prevent impersonation
attacks. A lot of the impersonation
attacks come because there's a mis
there's a misunders a misconfiguration
of how those two talk with respect
to each other. You look at how VPNs, you
know, common VPN problem is that I
have a VPN and I give an edge access
through the VPN, but the VPN isn't
mutually authenticating in a strong way.
So, the edge thinks that it's talking to
the VPN, but it's not. It's talking to
an impersonation of the VPN. So, when it
when it grants access, it thinks, "Oh,
okay. I can now share my other
credentials to what'sever on the other
side of the VPN. But I'm not I'm not on
the VPN I thought I was because I don't
have strong mutual authentication. I've
got a shared secret and that and that
means now that I'm going to disclose to
that other end my credentials to
get further into the system and I and
and rinse and repeat, right? But if we
have strong mutual authentication at
every edge, then there is no recursive
privilege escalation attack.
So, so we basically, you know do
this with ACDC. So, I'm going to show us
I'm going to show you how we can use an
ACDC. This is a proposal.
I haven't written a white paper on it
yet. I started writing a white paper on
it but I haven't finished published it
yet of how we can just repurpose ACDCs
as generic authorizations.
So if you so there those of you
who aren't familiar with an ACDC these
are the top level fields version type it
set a UYU ID the issuer the ACDC the
registry for the ACDC state the schema
section attribute edge and rule section.
So if in the
in the there's two registries here.
There's an issuance registry
and we can now add a usage registry and
the way we manage that is in the
attribute section. The attribute section
itself has a set a UYU ID the issue AID
and it also can have a registry
identifier and then a resource map. The
resource map over here looks like
object capabilities. You basically have
a route and then a set of capabilities.
So it's a list of things like read,
write, execute, whatever it is standard
standard access control. All we do is we
just augment ACDCs to have a resource
list and it and we can implement any
sort of authorization
system and but what we get are some
properties that you that are
difficult to get in other ways without
ACDCs.
So this stuff is actually in the
spec but I'm pretty sure almost nobody's
read it. The right here the
issue ID people know about but in the
spec we actually have a registry
identifier defined but this registry
identifier is different from that
registry identifier. This is the issuer
registry. This is the issue registry.
Why does it why does the issue want a
registry?
That's right. So if the issue wants to
know if they it so let's say here's the
use case somebody gave me an
authorization let's say this is my
authorization
I want to know if my authorization's
been compromised
now in ACDC if I want to present it
requires at the very least signing it so
compromise looks like an a compromise of
my signing infrastructure now if it's a
token compromise Looks like somebody
just steals the token. It's an easy
compromise. You know, it's much harder
to steal my private keys. But let's say
someone has stole my private keys.
They can then present
my authorization someplace and I don't
know that they've stole my private keys
unless I require that a verifier check
that the presentation is anchored in my
registry. So every time I do a
presentation I anchor in the registry.
The verifier checks that the issuer
issued it by checking the issuer
registry but checks that the presenter
actually says I want ultra security when
I present. So don't verify the
presentation unless I anchor the
presentation. Makes the presentation
less ephemeral. But it also means now
that if I have really re really
strong security over presentations and
if somebody steals my private keys as a
as a presenter,
I know that they stole them because they
the only way that they can they can gain
access is to anchor it in my registry
that I control. And so that's that
allows me to detect compromise of my of
my credentials.
So here's here's showing what I just
said. Here's the issuance registry
With a presentation. The issue just
signs the presentation. The verifier
checks it checks its observer checks the
registrar controlled by the issuer says
okay it's good. The ACDC is fine.
This is what it looks like over here in
terms of the Key Event Log of
the issuer and then the re the reg
registry.
But if and then we have the registrars
and the and the observers.
But if I'm doing a usage registry, what
does it look like? Well, the
presentation itself gets anchored in a
in a in a registry that's controlled by
the issue. So this one is
controlled this registrar is the issue's
registrar and now the verifier checks
here. So the verifier would have to
check two registries has to check the
issuers's registry and the presenter's
registry.
But that makes it so
that both the issuer and the user
can detect if either one has been
compromised and the verifier knows it.
So basically any presentation gets
anchored in the in the in the issue
registry
and you can see the state of the
presentation and you can share one
registry for all your presentations
because it's one controller of the
registry.
So this is this is a another
difficult problem in authorizations
and that's when you have delegation
and we didn't solve this problem from
the vLEI
in this in this explicit way but this is
in the spec
So but it solves the problem of
chained authoriz authorizations in a
delegation chain where the delegate
issues an authorization and then the
delegates authority to issue the
authorization gets revoked. So the
question is
What happens when a delegate's
authority or delegate's authority to
issue authorization is revoked. What is
the status as any authorizations or
entitlements that it issued before its
authority was revoked? Are they revoked?
Well, that would be really bad
in some cases,
right? Let's say I'm a company and I
issue a purchase order. My purchases
agent while he works for me issues a
purchase order. Purchase order has a
90-day expiration on it. It's valid for
90 days, right?
And then I fire the guy because he
wasn't showing up for work, right? Do I
have to go through every purchase order
that he signed off on
and reissue it? Well, if it's on paper,
everybody assumes that it's still valid,
right? But if it's electronic, if it's
digital of an ACDC and it's got in a
revocation registry, I could revoke all
of them and then reissue them. But maybe
I'm okay with what he issued. I The
reason he got fired wasn't because he
was misuing purchase orders. He got
fired because he violated HR or
something, right? So everything that he
did officially is still good. But he
doesn't work for me anymore. But if I
revoke his authority, I break the chain
of authority. And if I don't have any
other mechanism, then I am forced to
reissue everything that he did.
So that's a that's a hard problem of
delegation. And we don't solve these
these problems in general in
decentralized identity. If I have a
database, I can solve any problem. If I
have a centralized database, all
problems are all of these problems are
easy. It's just software. But if it's a
distributed decentralized, I have to
solve it cryptographically. I have to
figure out how I'm going to do it in a
decentralized way. So the way how do we
do that?
Well, here's a way that we can do that.
This is how we do it. We do it with
something called a bound blinded
ACDC register.
So, we have this
situation.
We have this situation here. We have an
issuee AID.
There the issue issues is
the issuer of another ACDC. So we have
a chained set of ACDCs. There's an
edge pointing back from the delegated
one back to the delegating one. Okay. So
that's the setup. So now we have
the issuer uses this bound blinded state
registry
and the thing that it adds is the
sequence number and the SAID
of the key state of the issue who is
also the issuer. Right? Right. The guy
in the middle is both an issuer and an
issue. He's an issue of his delegator
and he gets to issue stuff himself.
Right. So it's a delegated chain but
what we're doing is we're binding
the key state of
the issuee at the time
we give him authority
right so right here we issue to him
authority and we bind his key state. And
then when we revoke his authority we
also bind his key state. What that says is
is between two and five.
He has the authority to issue things
and here's his registry. He can issue
things in his registry. So in this list
right here, he can do things
to this other thing and they all
work. But once but number six
here, he doesn't have authority anymore.
So even though he's got an update event,
that update event, the bottom one's not
not verifiable because he doesn't have
authority to change that. So we have
a problem.
So with this,
the only way that this works is if the
issuances over here
are all time expired. Well, it's kind of
I'll just point at it. Maybe it's better
to just do it over here. Can you see my
cursor?
No.
Oh, it's Yeah, revocation recovation.
Oh, it's not showing up. All right. It's
probably because this thing's on. So
so what happens is that the type
of ACDC that he can issue here have to
have some sort of timeout because they
themselves can't be revocable because we
have an ambiguity about what we do about
it when we revoke his authority. But as
long as it times out or something then
it'll just selfrevoke.
So how do we solve that problem? That's
the that's the harder problem. So this
is not in the spec. This is actually a
proposal for the spec. We add
another we add another event. Oh
No that's the next one. So the way
we can solve it's not written up
in the spec but this is an easy
modification of the spec is that because
there's an edge right here
that points back to the issuing
authority
we can do a reversion of authority. So
let me give the example. Let's say
that I'm a I'm a lieutenant of a of a
company and I take one of one of the
members of the company and I give him an
order and I say you're going to go over
there, right? And he goes over there,
right? He has authority to do it. I told
him to do something. Let's say that I
I resend that order. He can't he
can't do that anymore.
What do I do at that point? Well, the
authority to do that still rests in me,
the lieutenant. I can I can go
over there and do it or I can I can, you
know, authorize whatever it is myself.
So, the authority always reverts to me
as the higher authority. So what we do
is that when a subordinate or a
delegate loses authority because we've
revoked it, any outstanding issuances
that were validly issued that we want to
dynamically revoke the revocation now
becomes the responsibility of the
delegator. It just reverts back to the
delegator. And because we have an edge,
we know who the delegator is. And so all
we have to do is make a policy change
that says in this case
where I revoked there you go where I
revoked his authority
right here.
So that I need so you see this one
over here is issue I can't revoke
because he's been revoked over here in
number five. But guess who can revoke
it? See the line that comes back here?
He can revoke it. And a ver verifier
just needs to know that's
the policy.
It just looks it up and says, "Oh, okay.
The approximate delegate doesn't
have authority because it's his
authority has been revoked. The chain's
broken." But any subsequent actions on
that ACDC are still the responsibility
of the delegator. And so the delegator
can revoke it. So now we can have
dynamically revocable credentials and
break the chain and still dynamically
revoke them. Yeah.
Well, well, since there's always edges,
you can the reversion of authority
can go all the way up to the top of the
chain. You can break you can break the
leak as many times you want and you just
keep you just rinse and repeat all you
just ascend the chain. So now you have
an elegant solution
for dynamically revocable delegated
credentials all the way down. You can
break the chain any number of times and
still control those credentials
dynamically.
So we have solved a really hard problem
that in ephemeral authorizations isn't a
problem because no authorizations last
long enough that you care. But if I'm
doing perpetually issued authorizations
that last indefinitely unless they're
revoked and I'm doing a chain, I need to
solve that problem.
So that's the solution. You revert
the authority to the delegator when the
delegates authority is revoked and that
allows you to continue to control those
those issuances.
Now we can do it even better. This
requires something not in the spec.
So this is a proposal to add in the spec
and that's just adding one additional
one additional update. It's called a
transfer event. So if we look over here,
where did I put it? Yeah, here we go.
There we go. Where is it? Incept…
Oh, I forgot where I saw it. There it
is. Oh, number three. I can't see it.
Yeah, number three is transfer event. So
we have an inception event and a
transfer event. Those are analogous to
an inception event and a rotation event
in a Key Event Log. So in a transaction
event log, we now have meta control
events. We had the
inception event which establishes the
who's the who's the authority over the
registry. Now we have a transfer event
that says we can transfer we can
transfer authority to a different
AID. So that allows us to do a an
authority transfer. So it's not just
reversion. We have a reversion of
control. The reversion allows us to
issue a transfer event. Now we have a
new dele delegate that now is a control
of all those credentials that are
controlled by that registry. So we could
do a seamless transfer all the way down
at every level. And all we have to do is
add one event. And the main thing in
this event is just that it's it's got
Whoops. It's got the issuer. It's got
the new the new issuer AID, not the
issuer back here. The issuer at the at
the end.
Yeah.
Well the cryptographic context
is that every event
in all of these registries is anchored
to somebody's Key Event Log.
So that's perpetually verifiable
because all of the all of the security
mechanisms that protect the key event
log protect everything anchored to the
Key Event Log.
Right? So post transfer you want to
minimize the number of nodes you have to
recurse through in order to get your
verifications to work.
Well, you're not minimizing them be
you're not changing the number because
you have a train a chain. So you always
have to verify the whole chain. Yeah.
So,
so you didn't increase the length of the
chain, you just switched a branch in the
chain,
right? So, there's a dead branch in the
chain because the employee got fired.
They're gone, right? And I don't want to
maintain his logs forever.
Well,
his K logs, right?
No, you don't have to maintain his key
event logs, you know. Well, yeah, you do
have to maintain his Key Event Logs for
as long as those issuances are valid
because that's the only way you can
verify the original issuance.
That was my question.
Yeah. So, so, so, so you wouldn't do it
for you, you wouldn't do it for
something that was more that
was,
you know, this would allow something
that's longer lived
like let's say an employee issues a
purchase order that you want to be
dynamic revocable, but you're you're
not going to have it sit out there for
more than a year, right? So, you could
transfer to a new employee. It still
lasts a year, but you could still revoke
it if you found out there was something
wrong with it. If you're the
state of Are we out of time? Oh, you're
just asking questions. Okay. Let me
let me Yeah, go ahead. I guess
I was just curious because you
nailed it with key rotation can already
transfer control. You're just So, is
this analogous to a sort of
Well, the difference here is that
is that key rotation is
Heavy weight transfer because you're
talking about control of the AIDs.
Yep.
Right. And so in the case of an employee
leaving, you would at very least have to
have a multi-IG
so that multiple employees controlled
the AID and one of them rotated out.
This allows you to avoid any of those
issues
because you're doing it on the registry
level.
You're doing on the registry level
instead of the KEL level. So, it's a
much lighter weight, easier to manage
situation for doing things at scale.
What I'm wondering though is that it
could this be a point of failure if
someone were to key compromise and then
Transfer a registry toward a
malicious controller out.
Well, well, anytime you compromise keys,
you can do something malicious, right?
But you can't do it without being
detected, right?
Which means you recover from it,
right?
So that's the point.
Okay. I'm just trying to understand if
it opens up potentially any like
vulnerabilities, but I'm not
not any not any new ones.
Okay, good.
All right. does. So this now
means that we can maintain control over
issuances out at the edge of our graph
authorizations
and they can survive for long periods of
time and we have dynamic control over
them and we can change control over them
dynamically.
Not all issuances benefit from that.
There's some you don't want to do that
for. But in the cases where you have
really long lived things like
guardianship, right? So this is an
example of guardianship. You have a
child who has parents that are that are
guardians over the parents and they get
divorced. Who's the new guardian?
Do you want to reissue the birth
certificate to the child or do you want
to transfer control of the birth
certificate to the new guardian? You
want to transfer control. You don't want
to reissue the birth certificate
and lots of authority structures in
corporations
that have to do with things like who has
control over the domain name registrar
for the company.
Do you want to reissue all your domain
names every time that person moves? Or
do you want to have some mechanism that
you can transfer control?
And do you want that mechanism to be a
multi-IG group where you have a group of
IT people that all have, you know,
a threshold control? You could do it
that way or you could do it this way. In
some cases, this is going to be more
scalable because it's not it's not
requiring tight coordination for key
management.
All right. And any so this so
this would be in version 1.1 of the
ACD spec. My proposal would be to add
add another event. So basically we're
just adding one event so we can do
control transfer on a registry. And I
didn't think of it a year ago when I
wrote up the registry, but as I was
thinking about this problem some more, I
said, "No, no, we probably should
add that one." And I actually changed it
three or four times because I kept
trying to decide what I needed. And I
realized that it just needs to just the
only thing it needs to have is the
issuers's AID. Everything else is the
same as the inception event.
It just declares a new issuer.
So it's the event type is the only thing
that changes. Any
other questions before I move on?
Yeah.
Does VI authority fit into this somehow?
Yeah, we right now vLEI don't solve
these problems. So with the vLEI, what
you have right now is you have a
grace period. when you're issuing QVI
loses its authority, all of the VI they
issue are still valid for a grace
period. Carla wants to answer.
Go ahead, Carla. Oh, get it, Mike.
Yes. And I knew that this was coming
Because Kevin told me that you were
working on it. And so we have been
looking at a way in order to be able
not to have to go back to the legal
entities
your QVI is leaving the system
you're going to have to hire a new QVI
and recreate everything that you
have. And so this way we can transfer
control to GLEIF and then as the legal
entities hire their new QVIS we can
transfer control again to the new
that's what happens is GLEIF now becomes
the authority not the QVI
and then you don't have to make the
transfer control be forever. It can just
now be a dynamic time period to give you
a grace period to find a new QVI and
reissue. But now the grace
period now is dynamic instead of fixed,
right? Right now it's fixed to what? 90
days. Yeah.
Okay. Sam, I'm gonna give you a
practical example of I work for a civil
engineering firm. I have my engineer
stamp. I've stamped the bridge as being
ready to build or meeting spec. I leave
the company. What is the company going
to do? H I'm trying to see that how that
hierarchy would work, especially
considering that in the traditional
world, we just file those blueprints and
that engineer stamp is always on there
and we consider it valid.
Well, right now the engineering stamp
doesn't isn't dynamically revocable.
There's no mechanism to do that. So,
this only applies to engineering stamps
that you already need to dynamically
revoke.
So if you and because it's very
difficult to do dynamic revocation
almost no real world issuances have
dynamic re revocation but because now
we're doing this stuff crypto actively
all of a sudden all sorts of use cases
where we want them to be dynamic
revocable but we never thought it
possible so we didn't and we just lived
with it now become good applications. So
we're talking about using ACDCs in new
ways. You can re refactor
multiple licensing regimes to have
dynamically revokable licenses and it's
practically workable.
So there should be some b some business
opportunities there.
Yeah. So the basic idea of this transfer
is the basic idea of this transfer
registry
that you create with that you're
delegating or changing transferring
control over a set of identifiers to a
new identifier. So it creates a
registry.
No, you're changing control of the
One identifier, the reg registry's
identifier. That's what you're changing
control of.
Yeah, I misspoke there. That's right.
Okay. So just the registry that you
might have already issued many
credentials from and so is essentially
or one credential that has state changes
and you don't you don't want to reissue
that credential. You want the credential
to continue to have viability. You just
want to change who has the authority to
change the state of the credential.
That's all you're doing.
Got it?
And you're doing that. And so I want
to point out something out here. See
this event right here, the transfer
event. See it has two arrows going to
it. That because a validator first has
to verify that the that the reverting
authority approved it and has to verify
that the new authority approved it.
And then once that happens then they
they don't care because it's just the
new authority.
All right. Any other questions? All
right we'll go to the next one.
So, so is this then do you need
reversion in place in order to have a
properly functional transfer registry
of this type? Yes, there's another type
of transfer registry that we haven't
defined yet that I have and I have a
outstanding issue on KERIpy that's
different from this. Okay,
this is reversion for a hierarchy of
authorizations and delegation, not a not
not a replacement for asset transfer.
Ned's going to give a talk on secure
asset transfer later today. So you can
ask one clarifying question. Yes.
So previously earlier in this talk you I
thought there was another methodology
where it was like two through four was
valid. So that's a different style where
it's a different style of dealing with
the same problem. Just one is the same
in order.
It's the same thing. It's just this says
once you're invalid, what do you do with
the ACDC of the controlling authority?
It nobody's in charge of it. So you can
revert back to the this delegator and
now the deleg delegator is in control.
But that now imposes a burden on the
delegator to have to make control it
from that point on.
Right. I just thought I understood
previously like to answer his question
about you know the
use case where you could potentially
just keep
Just a certain set subset of the
issue issuances of the credentials
previously.
Yeah, that works as long as the
delegated credentials expire on their
own. if they're dynamically revocable
and you break the chain, you can't
revoke them after you broken the chain.
So, it works for conventional
issuances that time out. If I have a
food handlers permit that times out in a
year, I can fire the employee that
issued it and it's still valid, but
it'll expire in a year. But if I have
something that I want to be able to
revoke any point in time, then I can't I
can't break the chain and still I have
to define what that means. So, I can
define I could say, well, it means X,
right? But we want to make it so that we
can actually verify and enforce it
cryptographically.
I sound like somebody that doesn't
have a voice. All right. So,
So I'm going to move on because
we're going to run out of time. I have a
couple more slides. So, the other thing
we can do is that edge verifi evac can
also mean edge verifiable agent control.
Now, here's the thing.
An agent
is an authorized
delegate
of a natural person, a legal
entity, right? An agent can be another
natural personal legal entity. It can be
a piece of software. It can be an AI.
The term agent means so nothing in
anything that I showed you before is any
different if it's a person or an AI
that's in the delegation chain. It all
works the same. So now if you're worried
about whether your agentic AI has
permission to do X, you can
cryptographically verify that it had
permission to do X and you can revoke
its permission to do X and any verifier
can verify that. It doesn't matter.
You just give the agent an AID, a
delegated AID,
right? So that's the original meaning of
the word agent. So when see people say
agentic AI, they're just software agents
that are a little bit smarter than
software agents used to be, right? The
ACDC mechanisms are exactly the same.
They don't change. So if I want to do
EVAC, I do evac.
So you may want to have regul
regulations require attributes in your
chain that says this agent is a person
versus an AI. you might want to disclose
that. But as far as verifying their
authority and what they do with it, it
ACDCs accommodated without any
changes. Yeah. So, one of the other
problems with delegation is controlling
the recursion of delegation. And so
there's a bunch of, you know, weird
stuff in X509 for how to do that. I'm
just wondering what mechanisms exist
here to manage the
the degree of delegation that a
delegate.
What do you mean? What do you mean by
recursion? Like how many levels
a delegate can delegate to another
delegate?
Oh yeah. So in KERI
When you have ACDCs
they're edge operators and so you can
have an edge operators that says do not
delegator you can have a configuration
for a delegated AID that says do not
delegate. So you can say how many layers
down you can have delegation. Right? But
I'm familiar with that. It's like is it
is it do you have a whole policy engine
for how far you delegate? Well, actually
you can have a whole policy engine with
ACDCs because we have edge operators. So
you can you can make it as complicated
as you want or as simple as you want,
right? But ACDCs don't care,
right? It's up to the user application.
The cryptographic verifiability is I
have an edge. The edge has properties.
The properties can define whether that
edge allows further delegation or not.
Does that make sense? Did you guys
understand?
Yeah. Okay.
All right.
Safety. So, I'm going to change topics.
I have a couple of questions. All right.
Back here. Well, I guess it's the same
with natural people and
organizations to natural people.
How would you enforce if possible
attenuation such that you know
subsequent delegates or delegates do not
acquire more powers than the
so there's two governance mechanisms
that we use in ACDCs for that one is
called an ecosystem governance framework
okay so for the LEI the vLEI there are
200 pages of documents that say this is
what you can do with these ACDCs they
define the delegation what you can
delegate how much you can delegate how
many layers of delegation what the
ACDCs are who does that right that
doesn't have to be encoded into the
ACDCs themselves because the schema
for the ACDC which is an immutable
schema is defined to be the schema and
then you look up the ecosystem
governance framework for that schema and
you go oh this is how I use these guys
So, so in a real world you're
probably going to have quite fixed
well-rigidly defined ecosystem
governance frameworks because that's how
the real world works. We don't go
around and say, "Hey I want to be
a real estate agent." Agent, right? Hear
the word agent. What are the rules for
real estate agents? How can they
operate? What things can they can
and do? Well, there's a whole body of
regulation about it. We don't have to we
don't have to we just have to say, well,
we're going to make it so they can
verify that they're an agent. We can
reference all the regulations that apply
to them as an agent. Now, we've modeled
the real world authority that already
exists, but we just made it so that they
can do the verification
quickly and securely without
impersonation or fraud. We don't have
to build all of that the rulemaking
stuff if we don't if we don't have to.
There's no reason to do that. But if we
want to add
some of that because it's practical,
then we can encode it in the edge logic
with edge operators. But we want to we
want to make that as we want to minimize
that. What tends to happen is people try
to model all of the stuff in the world,
real world, in data and then they get
data that can't that is ambiguous. They
get ontologies that don't that aren't
that are broken.
Yes. Yeah. We've been toying with
with this delegation structure a bit
more from an application perspective,
right? An agentic AI is not one thing.
It's a spectrum, right? So in other
words, there are rule based on the lower
end and you have loose guidelines and we
want to see if the agent that
is taking control and delegating to
further agents did it right in the
context of those guidelines. Right. So
it is a loosely defined structure. Well,
it Well, I Yeah.
All right. Something was wrong with that
one. So, so trying to build other
systems, you're welcome to do that. I'm
just saying that we can't solve the
problem that ACDC solves right now.
Whatever you're doing isn't solving that
problem because you don't have you're
not you if you're not using ACDCs to
solve it and you're not doing this then
I know what you're not able to do. But
you can certainly do other things. Does
that make sense? I'm not prescribing for
you how you want to solve identic AI.
I'm just saying that if you want to
solve the act of modeling the authority
chain in a cryptographically verifiable
way and the elements of that chain
happen to be agents, it doesn't change
it doesn't change the mechanism. The
mechanism works just as well either way,
right? Yeah.
The guardrail is that you want least
privilege built into the system so that
there isn't an opportunity for a
delegate to introduce more privilege
than what was delegated to him
originally.
And is the mechan is the enforcement
mechanism on the shoulders of the
verifier or there's something intrinsic
in the structure that prevents that? No,
because the only people the only person
that enforces it is the verifier.
Otherwise, what you're going to have to
have is a policy engine that the
verifier asks to enforce it for them.
Right. So, you've just moved the
enforcement someplace else, but it's but
it's still it's Yeah,
that's the part that I think a lot
of the industry will have difficult
accepting.
Yeah, I'm I'm sure they will. And
Phil, I think you're going to talk about
some of that, right? Or he's writing a
book on it. So, I don't I'm talking to
you, Phil Wley.
I don't think he heard me. Hey, Phil.
Phil.
Oh, he asked a question and I said,
"You're writing a book on authorization
policy for ag."
Okay. All right.
Later.
It's all right. I
Sorry. What was the question? I
apologize.
Well, well, I just I just explained how
we could use ACDCs to do delegate
authority, and Ed asked, "Well, lease
privilege for the delegate to
be able to do stuff. How do you enforce
that? And I said, right, well, right now
the in a decentralized system, the
verifier can enforce it or you could
have a policy engine that the verifier
refers to that enforces it. But
but that's you know that
yeah so basically I think there are
two big avenues of how you would do this
with delegation. One is delegation as
data. The other one is delegation as
policy where you essentially write new
policies for the delegation
instead of relying on a broad set of
policies. in delegation as data ACDCs
especially with what you've described
today are really nice because you
can put all of the delegation in the
ACDC the credential and then you know as
you've pointed out you can keep that
from expanding you can revoke it you can
revoke the whole chain when necessary so
yeah I think that's I mean that's a
broad approach right as you write it
policies that interpret the data in the
delegation credential.
Yeah. And to Ned's point, that's not how
most people do it now. So they may not
like it,
which is a valid point.
So I'm going to change topics for the
last five minutes.
The internet is a dangerous place.
What we want, what I would like, I hope
some of you want this is a digital re
Refu god with my voice I can't say it
refuge
An online shelter,
an internet sanctuary,
a surveillance asylum.
Well, we're protected from all of these
things when we go online, when we use
the internet. We want to be able to use
the internet and be safe
and I messed that up. It hit two
things. So,
so if we think about those
safe is to require accountability of the
participants.
If they're not accountable, it won't be
safe.
If you if you can act in any way you
want and there's no there's no
repercussions, there's no consequences,
it's going to incentivize bad behavior.
And that's what the internet is. That's
what the internet is in a safe place cuz
we there's no accountability on the
internet. It never it never came with it
in the first place. And everybody
assumed that well people will just act
the way they normally do. I have a
really good example of this. My
daughter who you all saw sing, right?
Yeah. She has a pretty substantial
internet presence, lots of followers,
and there's a lot of trolls that will go
onto her
Instagram or Tik Tok or
all kinds of really horrible things.
Well, you know what my wife likes to do,
who you all met, is when they're do
really horrible things and they say
stuff like that occasionally, she will
go research them and they're always
using some, you know, alias. They think
they have anonymity. She'll go figure
out who they are and then she'll go ask
them, "Why did you say this about my
daughter?"
And they will sKRAMble for the hills.
It's just like, "Wait a minute. You know
who I am? you know that I said this
vulgar thing and sometimes they're just
average people in your neighborhood who
act like they don't do this. Well, why
do they do it on the internet? Because
they can get away with it. But and
what she always likes to say to them is,
"So, if you met my daughter in person,
would you say that to her in person?"
When they go, "Of course not." Well,
then why do you say it online? And the
difference is there's no accountability
online. So, if you want safety, you have
to have accountability. Here's the other
thing that people don't don't believe me
when I say this. Privacy requires
accountability. People think privacy
requires being able to hide. You can't
have privacy if without accountability.
Here's why. Second parties to repeated
interactions can correlate the first
parties. If I interact with you, even
though we're both anonymous, the
interaction themselves is enough to
correlate.
So guess what? I can't interact
and have privacy.
I can't.
So any interaction system that does not
enable first parties to hold second
parties accountable is fundamentally
incompatible with privacy.
You can't get there unless you start
with accountability.
And you and you don't get privacy by
hiding. You get privacy by interacting
with
digital refuges
Surveillance asylums where the
participants
hold each other accountable and you can
trust that they'll act in the way you
want and everybody else is excluded.
That's the whole point. If I want to
interact with him or her, right, and I
can hold him accountable, then I have a
trusted interaction. If I can't hold
them accountable, I can't trust it. But
what I want to do is I want to have that
interaction and not have anybody else
surveil it.
And that's and that's what we really
want. We want contextualized
confidentiality with accountability. And
how do we do that? Well, there's a
protocol called the trustbanning
protocol that combined with the KERI
suite allows us to create and control
safe relationships where interactions
protected from surveillance by third
parties and second parties are held
accountable for any information shared
with or by them. And so my
breakout talk this today will be
talking about the TSP protocol
and how we can do that. So that's I got
Keep going.
We only got a minute.
Oh, go ahead. Five minutes. 10 minutes.
Okay.
You can have some of my time.
All right.
Okay. So when I do this analysis, I
always use this model. I find, you know
what they say all models are wrong,
but some models are useful. I find this
a very useful model. Any
interaction on the internet involves the
first party and second party.
I can encrypt the communications between
the first party and the second party
so that the content isn't observable by
any other party.
But if I'm using the internet, what I
can't protect is the metadata of the
fact that I sent data over the internet.
It has to be routable.
Routing tables are public. Routing
information is subpoenaable.
All of that metadata is not protected.
The Supreme Court even said so. Right?
Reasonable expectation of privacy is
limited to content,
not non-content metadata. Non-content
metadata is how you get from first party
to second party. So, so if I can if I
can correlate out from the metadata who
the first party and second party are,
I've already defeated privacy in
general. There's no privacy on the
internet ever. Never has been, never
will be. If you use that definition,
right? But what I can do is I have
privacy where I can make it so that
I that they don't know who the first
party and the second party are because
the first party and second party they
see aren't the first party and second
party that matter.
And so the basic idea is I don't use
clandestine means to get privacy. I use
covert means
and covert means you have a cover
identity that basically
provides a layer of protection to some
activity that you're doing that isn't
observable. Clandestine just means
you're not observable. But any
information that's broadcast is
eventually observable. So clandestine
can only be used for epherrmal
applications. And I spent 20 years and
20, you know, millions of dollars of
federal money building clandestine
surveillance mechanisms
and at some point we said, "Oh, we
got to make them covert because we
need persistent literal
surveillance." That was the name of the
program. And when we went from ephemeral
to persistent surveillance, we had to
change our concept of operations.
And that's what I'm saying is we have to
change that. So this is the model. And
then and to get from first party, second
party, I have to have an intermediaries.
The intermediaries
can surveil stuff that a third party
can't. Your ISP is an intermediary.
So given that model, these are the
two principles that we use. One is end
toend verifiability which tells me that
I know who the parties are. The parties
know each other and the other so and if
I have KERI then I get ambient
verifiability any day anywhere anytime
by anybody of who it came from. So I
can hold the source accountable
right non-repudiation.
Now the duel of that is what I
call only at end viewability. I need to
be able to send information to somebody
and have reasonable confidence that
they're the only ones that got it.
Because the only way I can hold the
second party accountable is if I know
they're the leaker of data.
Because if I send encrypted data to a
second party that they can decrypt, they
have the data. I no longer have any
ability to restrict where that data
goes. There's no technological mean
means that allows me to protect that
data once the second party has it. I
have to trust the second party. So I
have no privacy of any information I
share with the second party if the
second party can share it with somebody
else. So there's no longer technology
here. It's all legal, regulatory, and
economic.
So if any information that I interact
with or share in the internet once it
gets to the second party the second
party wants to collude with anybody they
want to then I have no privacy.
The only privacy only comes if I can
trust the second party to respect
the terms and conditions that which is
called confidentiality of the
information I give them. So what I need
is a mechanism for sending information
from here to there
that is asymmetric. So I need to use
hybrid public key encryption so that I
have asymmetric encryption and I send it
to one end. I don't use group
encryption. I don't do I don't do shared
secret encryption. I use hyper
public key which is technically shared
secret encryption but I don't but the
key on my end is ephemeral. So I have a
reasonable confidence that only the
targeted one got it and I can I can in
include information in it that makes it
unique to that end which they can get
rid of if they if they're smart but it
makes it really hard for them. So I said
reasonable confidence. What that means
is that I have this property of end only
viewability. The end that I intend to is
the only one that can view it. So
there's one data one where one time by
one body and that means that it's
undeniable. Now they can deny it.
Plausible deniability.
I can't prove, may not be able to prove
it, but I know. And guess what I do when
I know? I break the interaction. I
exclude them from my interaction
profile. I stop talking to them. I stop
sharing data with them because I can't
trust them. So the whole point is I need
to be able to control who I talk to and
who talks to me. And I need to do it in
a mechanism that allows me to decide
that and to and to control the
boundaries of that. And that's the way I
do it. And so the TSB protocol
lets you decide with whom they interact,
what they share and why. And so you have
control over your internet presence and
your context when you do this. And we
use relationships graphs. And this will
I've got, you know, this is actually
into my talk for this afternoon. So,
I'll stop there.
Great. Thank you.