My name is Samuel Smith.
If anybody
can't remember my name,
[laughter]
it's because you're more identity
challenged than my parents thought I
would be than they gave me that name.
Anyway, that's all right. Great. So,
I'm going to talk about the trade space
of KERI, not in detail,
but I'm going to talk about why
we solve
the privacy problem using bulk issuance
instead of other mechanisms. And
I'll and I'll give you the shorthand
to the trade space.
KERI's policy is security first always,
which means if we're ever in a situation
where we're going to make a trade, and
we're going to trade for weaker security
or stronger something else,
we're not going to make that trade.
We're going to always trade for stronger
security. We're not We're not going to
say, "Well,
that security's okay.
It We can We can We can do this because
the
the trajectory of technology for
security is that every weak trade for
security is a bad trade. May not to May
not be today, but in your lifetime it'll
be a bad trade. So, so let's try to be
creative about solving the other
problems without starting off by saying,
"Well, it's easier to solve those
problems if we just throw security under
the bus."
Actually say, "You know what? If my
constraint is I'm not going to throw
security under the bus, what's the best
I can do? And is it good enough?" And
that's really And that's really the
the difference in the in the ethos.
So
for those of you know,
With KERI, each AID controller is
its own identity provider.
So, we use this phrase keys at the edge.
Each edge self-authenticates.
What that means is there are no
third-party IDPs, no relying parties, no
trusted intermediaries.
Every interaction is end-to-end or
edge-to-edge, depending on your
your mental model, right? If I have
a network and I have people at the edge
trying to get in, it's called an edge.
If I'm trying to communicate across a
network, it's called an end, but they're
the same thing from KERI's perspective.
So,
in my plenary this morning,
I ended with this idea of reputable
autonomic pseudonymity in control over
confidential contexts.
The way we solve privacy
is with this one, control over
confidential contexts. And bulk issuance
gives the user precise control over
confidential contexts. So, they get to
decide
what the reach and scope of their
disclosure are in terms of their
correlatability.
We understand that every piece of
information that we share over the
internet
is correlatable.
There is no such thing as
no correlation.
Unlinkability is not the same as
uncorrelatability.
So, you know, we called it Rhapsody. So,
let's see how we use ACDC's for this.
ACDC's And I think most of you are
familiar, but I recognize some faces
in here that maybe haven't actually sat
through,
you know, something about ACDC. So, I'm
going to give a couple of just short
introductions cuz I've got a lot of
detail to go through, and if
if you thought this was going to be a
high-level talk like the plenary this
morning, I'm really going to disappoint
you.
This is I'm This is I'm going to This is
going to go fast.
So, think of an ACDC as a graph fragment
that has
edges that point to other graph
fragments.
And so, if you take graph fragments and
connect their edges, you get a graph.
That's the point.
But, the edges are part of the ACDC.
And the reason for that is the
authority and the authentication for
each graph fragment includes its edges.
So, you authenticate the
attributes which are the node and its
edges, and that is an ACDC. And now I
can compose
arbitrary data structures from graph
fragments because all data can be
graphed. Right?
And the edges It's called a label
and the edges It's called a label
property graph because the edges have
properties.
The edges can be blinded. They can be
private edges. They can They can have
operators. They can be grouped together.
They can be aggregated. They can be used
in various ways. The edges have
their own set of individual attributes
that are metadata about the way you
compose the information
in a secure way.
And other approaches to composing
information don't allow you to securely
compose the information from multiple
sources. They put it all in one data
structure that under the hood is
actually a graph, right? If I have a
nested
set of JSON blocks, it's it's a graph,
but it's not composable in a secure way.
It's It's all or nothing.
And so, ACDC says, "No, that's a bad
idea. We need to We need secure
composition."
ACDCs are designed to solve
problems where you need perpetually
verifiable issuances. Can you use an
ACDC with a bare signature
with a short crypto
Absolutely. You don't have to anchor
your ACDC's in a in a in a transaction
of an Oracle or a KEL to make them
perpetually verifiable.
But we have to solve the perpetual
verifiability problem.
So let's solve the hard problem first.
So I use this sometimes that people are
familiar with it. If I have a bunch of
rocks, a bunch of gravel, and a bunch of
sand, and water, and I want to get all
of that into a jar, and get the most
that I can get in there,
what do I put in first?
The water, right? I put the water in,
right? No, I put the rocks in first,
then I put the gravel, then I put the
sand, and then the water fills in the
blanks. So ephemeral applications are
the easy thing. Everybody knows how to
do ephemeral application. Nobody solved
the perpetual verifiable problem before
carrying ACDC in a
decentralized way. Obviously, if you
have a database and a central authority
to the database, you can solve any
problem you want. It's easy, right? But
it but it doesn't that's not the
hard problem of decentralized data. The
hard problem of decentralized data is
how do I solve
how do I solve perpetual issuances
without a centralized authority?
Right? Each fragment is separably
authenticatable. That means the graph
doesn't have a single source. Every
node, every fragment can come from a
different source. They can all come from
one source or different ones. That
allows me to do delegation, all sorts of
things.
Right? So I have
delegable, tenable, aggreable,
revocable, transferable authority.
Can we break that down?
Okay.
Well, I haven't talked about
well, I haven't talked about
aggregating, but notice that if I have
multiple ones going in one thing, I've
aggregated. If I have a chain, that's
that's a tenuous that's a tenuous
delegable. And transferable means that I
can
I can change who's who's in control.
And actually I'll talk about that in my
plenary tomorrow. All right.
What this allows us to do
what this allows us to do
for verifiable credentials, which are
all about authority,
is that we can have high fidelity
modeling of real world authority
structures.
Not authority structures that are the
best we can do because we have a broken
model, which is
current security, current OAuth
OIDC. It's all broken models because it
says, "Well, this is what we can do with
the technology we have. We have to use
the secure sessions. We have to use
encryption. We have to use things like
Diffie-Hellman, TLS key exchanges, and
we have to do ephemeral stuff because we
don't know how to solve the perpetual
perpetual verifiability problem. And
then we'll make the rest of the world
change their authority structures to
match that."
And what ACDC say from the
beginning is, "No, no, that's not the
way real world authority structures
work. Real world authority structures
have these properties."
And it doesn't matter whether it's
organizational identity or personal
identity, right? If I'm a parent and
I have a child and I want to do
and I want to have
you know
control over what my child is allowed to
do, then I'm then I've got a delegable
attenuable authority structure.
Right?
It looks like organizational identity.
So those are the problems we're
solving.
Oh, I should have
This was supposed to be animated. I
messed up. Okay.
I'm not going to talk about this stuff.
I put this on the slide because I'm
going to talk about blind
bulk issuance.
But a lot of people say because I spend
a lot of time
talking about
about the other things that ACDCs do,
that we actually don't support all of
the least disclosure mechanisms that
ever all the other credentials do. We
just don't support a particular type of
proof stuff because we feel that it's
it's it makes an unfortunate security
compromise. So, we have we follow the
principle of least disclosure. We have
something called gradual
gradual disclosure
that allows us to progressively
disclosures
so that we can negotiate how much
information is disclosed in a particular
context. Now,
control over confidential context. That
means I don't disclose any more
information than I need to,
right?
to facilitate a transaction. And that
transaction might be negotiating over
what I'm going to disclose.
And so, I can have multiple
interactions and transactions to
negotiate the full set of disclosures
and how I do those disclosures. And so,
we have something called compact
disclosure, mediated disclosure, partial
disclosure, nested partial disclosure,
full disclosure, and selective
disclosure. Those are all disclosure
mechanisms that don't exist anywhere
else except in ACDCs, except for
selective disclosure. They have one
mechanism for selective disclosure and
nothing else. And so, it means you
can't model real-world authority
structures when it comes to disclosing
information. You need more you need more
capability. And then, you can do com-
combinations of the above. And then, we
have bulk issued instance disclosure,
which I'm going to talk about today. So,
so I'm only going to talk about one of
the things on this list. And then, we
have contractually protected disclosure,
which you've heard about, right? There's
several people that have mentioned that.
You've seen demos of contractually
protected disclosure. So, that is
essential if we're going to have a
comprehensive approach to privacy.
Comprehensive approach says you invert
the economics. One of the ways you
invert the economics in is impose
liability
on the recipient of the disclosure. They
don't get a safe harbor. They don't get
to do things like de-identify the data
and then and then they can do whatever
they want with it. You attach
strings to the data and those strings
are enforceable which changes their
their behavior. So, we're changing
behavior of the recipient of the
disclosure, not trying to minimize the
disclosure and then hoping they can't
use it against us. We actually say you
can't use it against us and if you do,
this is what we're going to do to you.
Right? So, we need to have a contractual
projected disclosure and we need to have
one that the recipient will agree to.
And that's why we need graduated
disclosure so that we can gradually move
into a situation where we're we're
mutually agree. And then we have
bindable ACDC state registries. Those
are a little bit a part of bulk issuance
so I'll talk about those a little bit as
well. So, that's the full set
of mechanisms
and there's a lot. And that's why often
people look at ACDCs they
go, "Oh, there's a lot there." Right?
But if we want to really do it right, we
have to do all of those things.
All right. So, let's talk about
infrastructure.
Just to remember, we have
we have controllers, they have witnesses
and watchers. That's for KERI. That's
key to it. ACDCs
are built on top of KERI. So, when we
talk about ACDCs, it's another protocol,
it's another set of infrastructure, it's
a bunch of new stuff that you have to
learn about.
So, we have registrar and observer
and this is what they look like.
And then we have
We can do bulk issuance with the
registrar and observer if we if we do it
right. And we use sparse Merkle
trees to be able to do that. Sparse
Merkle trees are technically a type of
zero-knowledge proof. We do use
zero-knowledge proofs. A digital
signature, a conventional digital
signature, is technically a type of
zero-knowledge proof.
Just nobody calls them that, but if you
look at the math, a digital signature is
disclosing that somebody who knew a
private key and a nonce
created the signature without disclosing
either the private key or the nonce.
It's a zero-knowledge proof. A Merkle
tree, you can do an inclusion proof or
an exclusion proof
of entry in the tree without disclosing
all of the tree. That's a zero-knowledge
proof, by the book. Right? So, we take
advantage of those. We just don't take
advantage of the ones that have weak
security because the crypto periods for
for perpetual verifiable
issuances. But, if the application
fits an ephemeral application, I have no
problem with using zero-knowledge proof.
I use them all the time. I just don't
call them that because most people don't
call them that either.
We also have something called a user
presentation registry, which is also a
new thing that nobody else does as far
as I've never seen anybody do it, which
allows presenters to detect compromise
of their proofs that are in their
credentials that they're
presenting. So they themselves
will protect it from fraud, not just the
issuer. So, what does an issuance
registrar registry look like? Here's the
block diagram. You have Let's see, can
you see my cursor?
No. No. All right.
Oh, well.
Oh, I have a thing.
Let me Let me pull this up.
I got distracted.
No, that works.
There it goes. There we are. Okay.
There we go. How fancy. All right. So,
So, we have
an issuer,
an issuee,
and we use that terminology is a
little bit odd because we don't want to
get confused about a data subject or a
holder. We're really talking about the
the ACDC is targeted. We have untargeted
and targeted ACDs, and if it's targeted,
then we're issuing it to some entity,
and that's the issuee.
The issuee makes a presentation.
The presentation can either be bare
signed, which means
it's ephemeral,
or it can be anchored, which makes it
so that they can detect if they've
been compromised because a verifier will
have to check to see if the presentation
is anchored. This is an unanchored
presentation.
The issue The issuer
creates a regis- a registry of the state
of the ACDC, puts it and puts it's
hosted by a service called registrar,
and then an observer,
Which is controlled by the verifier,
the registrar is controlled by the
issuer,
notice that this model the witness
watcher governance structure. So, we
learned a lesson. We shouldn't have
shared governance.
So, we have witnesses that are
controlled by controllers, watchers that
are controlled by verifiers. We split
the verification between two places.
We do the same thing with ACDCs. We have
registrars controlled by the issuers,
and observers controlled by the
verifiers,
and the ACDC state goes to the observer,
the observer gets it from the registrar,
the verifier checks the state against
the presentation says, "Oh yeah, that
credential hasn't been revoked." For
example, if I if I have dynamic state
ACDCs. So, that's not a new concept.
Here's what it looks like from a
a cryptographic point of view the data
point of view. So, what I have is I have
the Key Event Log of the issuer.
And I have events in the Key Event Log
and I just show different types of
events in set, interact, rotate. But
each event in the Key Event Log can have
a seals.
These we call these anchoring seals.
They basically are hashes. They're
actually technically saids of things I
want to anchor.
The they are privacy preserving because
I don't know what the hash is. It's
a cryptographic hash. I can't infer what
what the hash is of unless I know
what it is to begin with. But I can
cryptically verify once it's disclosed
to me what it is that it's in that it's
there, right? So, so I have a
cryptographic anchoring of
a registry. A registry is essentially
another type of log. We call them a
transaction event log. It is a hash
chain data structure.
But it's
managing not key state but ACDC state.
So, if my ACDC is dynamically revocable,
I have issued and revoked are the are
the two states. And I have this new
thing called no change and that's
because this is a blinded state tail.
So, I can issue events to the regis-
registry that are blinded. I don't know
what the state is.
A third-party observer can't
correlate the state just by looking at
the registry.
Only second parties that I disclose
to can figure out what the state is.
And so, I can have So, a given issuer
can have a registry per
per ACDC that they issue to manage
the state.
So, blinded state registry.
So, these are the fields in an ACDC.
The top-level fields.
And the S A E and R are we call them
sections because they typically are
expanded to block of other things.
But we have attributes, edges, rules. I
but we have attributes, edges, rules. I
talked about edges. We have schema.
We have a registry field that points to
the registry that governs this
ACDC. ACDCs don't have to have
registries. If they're issued and
they expire with time, they're not
dynamically revocable, they don't need a
registry. So, so the registry field's
missing.
Empty.
I then have in my registry, I have a
registry inception event,
which defines governance for the
registry. So, what is governance? Well,
it's the issuer AID. It says this
registry is governed by this AID. And
then it has a set like everything, has a
serial sequence number, has a date time.
And then I can issue blinded updates.
The blinded updates
have
A prior
connection so that
change age
sequence number. And then has this blid,
which is this blinded ID.
So, I don't know what the state is if I
look at the registry. The registry's
blind to me. Third party looks at it and
says, "Okay, you got a registry got
events in it. I don't know what I don't
know what ACDC it manages. I don't
know what it's doing because all of that
important information is blinded over
here."
So, my blinded attribute block is where
I get that information. So, I have this
the blid. I have a UUID, which means the
blid is universally unique. It's called
a salt I call it a salty nonce.
I have the set of the ACDC and then I
have the state.
So, the only way I know the only way I
can get this is that the presenter,
the issuee, unblinds it
for me and gives it to me. And they only
unblind it after
for example, if I'm a verifier, I agree
to the terms if it's contractually
protected disclosure or after we
negotiate what it is or what parts that
I that, you know, that I'm going to
disclose. And now they can at least
verify that the ACD is validly issued,
but may maybe the ACDC used selective
disclosure to only disclose one field in
the attribute block. But now I can at
least look it up and say, "Yeah, it was
Professionally verifiable because
because it was
I can trace it I can trace it." So, this
is what it looks like.
I've got the Key Event Log.
I've got the events in the registry. So,
I've got an incept. Incept is vacuous.
It just creates the registry. Why is
this useful?
Well, I don't want the creation of the
registry to be correlatable.
So, if I'm the state of Utah and I'm
issuing birth certificates,
born, I create a registry on their
birthday,
then I've correlated their birth date to
the registry creation. That's a
really bad thing to do. So, I want to be
able to do is just create registries
bulk
that are just placeholders.
And so, on day one of SEDI, the state of
Utah will create enough registries for
all the citizens of the population of
the state of Utah for the next
however many years they want to do that.
And now they're only correlated to the
date that's went into place.
Anybody that's born before that date,
their registry is created on that date.
Anybody born after that date, their
registry is created on that date. A lot
of mechanisms that people build for
privacy don't actually consider the
statistical correlatability of the meta
data that they use when they build their
systems. And so every time I look at
something I go is there metadata there?
Yes, there is. That metadata is
inherently correlatable. It will defeat
any mechanisms I use that are
cryptographic because I just have to pay
attention and I can correlate it. So I
So I have to build into the system
anti-metadata correlation mechanism. So
bulk issuance, this is bulk issuance.
That is a Sorry.
Oh, no. I got to go redo that.
So it's helpful to focus All right.
I got to go slower. 1 2
4. There we go. All right. What else is
on here?
Well, I update See all these updates?
They just have these blinds in them.
The blinds are blinded. I don't know
what the update is. Look over here. This
one
is an update but it doesn't have
I
update my registry with
nothing.
Well, if I wanted to make sure that like
let's say
that as the state
once a day
I create updates whenever I issue new
birth certificates.
Now the update is correlatable to the
birth certificate. So I want to do is I
want to have a bunch of registries that
I just update randomly.
So that there's no correlatable
information but the fact that I had an
update.
A lot of mechanisms for verifiable
credential that have revocation
registries, you look at the metadata
when the transaction was posted to the
to the registrar or the verifiable data
registry, it means you can
correlate out the information you're
trying to protect. You don't actually
have to have anything. You don't have to
break anything. You just have to pay
attention. You just have to be a good
data scientist.
Since I Since I started my life as an AI
data scientist, I always think about
those things first. I'm late comer to
cryptography. I go, "Well,
cryptographers don't think about data
science. They don't know how to They
don't really think about statistics.
They don't know about much of the
statistical stuff that they use. They
just know that there's certain things
that they can get away with." And I'm
sorry for criticizing cryptographers.
Anyway,
so I wanted to do that and I keep
hitting the wrong one. All right, one
more time. Sorry about this.
I guess I could just exit out of the
animation. All right.
Here we go. It's on here. All right, so
No, this is the wrong This is No, that
won't work. That's a different one. All
right, here we go.
Go slow.
It's sensitive. All right, so what
I have here is the one that's actually
issued. It's some update.
And then I can I can update it with the
same state,
but somebody looking at it doesn't know
what the update means.
So this example actually came up
with when I was talking to some people
a few years ago for Swiss ID, and they
looked at the existing KERI stuff and
they said, "Well, yeah, one of the
problems they have with at the point in
time pretty much all of the verifiable
credential systems on the planet is that
if you know what the state is at any
point in time,
and there's only two states,
and there's an update, then you don't
have to actually be disclosed the
update. You can infer, cuz there's only
two states, that the update changed the
state and what the current state is.
So the example is I apply for a job
someplace, and I'm using a verifiable
credential
that's privacy-preserving,
and I disclose that I'm an employee of
a company,
and then they don't hire me,
but they put me on the list of saying,
you know,
we want to keep track cuz we really like
this guy, but he just won't Timing
wasn't quite right, right?
But, since now they know the registry
can then
watch it. And if there's a new state in
there, and they know that there's only
two states issued and revoked, guess
what? They know when I get fired.
Might be 5 years from now, and then they
go, "Oh, he got fired. Let's see if he
wants a job with us."
So, I need to have my state updates be
blinded
so that there's no statistical
correlatability. Has nothing to do with
cryptographic correlatability or
cryptographic linkability. It is I don't
have any metadata that is statistically
correlatable. So, that means I have to
be able to update my state
with blinded updates
in a way that it and the user can
request this. The user can go back to
the issuer and say, "Hey, you know what?
I did three presentations of my state. I
want you to issue a new one
so that decorrelates everything that I
just did." Because now they can't go and
look and see the latest state cuz the
latest state is after the one they had,
so they don't know what the state is.
They don't know if it went to revoked
or it went to some other state. They
just know they don't know it. And then
when you revoke it, you just you just
keep you can just keep updating it every
once in a while, and they go, "Oh, well,
it may must still be employed
because his registry is still updating,
right? He didn't abandon the registry."
So, it gives you perpetual protection
from metadata correlation because
the registry can live forever and
protect you.
All right, so Is it
derived from something? Yes, it's a blo
it's Well, it's it's HD an HD
process. So, so what we're trying to do
is minimize the key management. So, the
issuer and the issuee exchange a salt.
And then you use the salt to derive the
blinding factors.
So, you don't have to have any
interactions.
What happens is the issuee can go
look at the look at the registry, see
that there's a new event, and they can
figure out what it is cuz they know the
salt.
And so they can they can actually try
all the combinations of state to figure
out which one it is without them
having
to have any ongoing interaction. So I
hate interactions. If you ever pay
attention, I think interactive protocols
are bad idea. I want non-interactive
protocols in general. So that's a
non-interactive way to allow them to do
it is to use a salt. All right. So
shared blindness state registry. So
maybe you say registries are expensive.
I don't want to have all these
registries. Well, because the state's
blinded and the blind includes the
actual ACDC that the registry's for,
there's no reason you can't share one
registry across any number of ACDCs. So
there's an issue where I could use I
could use one registry for all of the
credentials I issue. Now, that means
that the registry might get heavyweight
over time and I start to get what looks
like blockchain bloat, so I might bloat.
So I may want not want to do that if I'm
issuing a lot, but I can certainly can
decide what the granularity I want to
manage that, right? So that's the
advantage of a blinded
state registry.
Yes.
The salt?
You know, exchange something like a
symmetric key exchange? Yes.
But it's not for security, it's for
privacy. So KERI says it's okay to use
shared secrets
for confidentiality because every
encrypted thing that you send somebody
is has to use a shared secret. Does that
create a class of algorithm which has
salt and symmetric salt exchange
for which
you know, the cryptog- cryptography
community doesn't know what that is.
I'm not sure I understand the
question. I'm just drawing a parallel
between symmetric key exchange protocols
and salt exchange protocols.
And are they different? No, it's just a
secret.
And how are they secure? Have they been
looked at by cryptographers?
Well, anything that you would exchange
with Diffie-Hellman is just a secret.
So, the security of the exchange is
whatever Diffie-Hellman gives you. It
doesn't Diffie-Hellman doesn't care what
what secret you're exchanging.
Diffie-Hellman is anonymous, but it's
not, right? Yeah.
So, it doesn't care.
Yeah, so basically you can use your
salt can be the shared key that
the Diffie-Hellman gives you. So, that's
the easy way to do it. Okay, I think
there's a man-in-the-middle attack, but
I don't know. Yeah. Isn't Isn't that why
you designed SPACK, though?
Well, no, but yes.
[laughter]
SPACK solves a lot of other problems.
You can certainly do an out-of-band
salt exchange.
And the reason you can do that is that
when you do the identity assurance,
if you're doing IAL level three identity
assurance, it has to be an in-person
thing, and then you can exchange the
salt then, and it's out-of-band. And
then you don't have to worry about
Diffie-Hellman. But that's it.
Well, it scales for SEDI
because you can't get a SEDI credential
unless you do the IAL at the start.
And that means you can exchange the
salt. That's physical registration
stuff? Huh? You physical registration
Yeah. Yeah.
And I'll talk about that. Yes, I have
a slide on that.
Right, so let's talk about
this infrastructure. I have registrars
with registries. I have observers. All
our observer is doing is it's keeping
track of the registry state. So, it's
asking the registrar, what are
you registries you have? What state do
you have? And now it has a local cache
copy, and then when a verifier wants to
verify something, he goes to his
observer and says, "Tell me
what the state of this ACDC is."
So for this to work,
you want to use bulk updates. That means
you don't update
instantaneously, you update like say
once every 24 hours.
Otherwise, if you update it instantly,
then the observer
could correlate
a change to some registries
and not others. But if all the
registries, 100% of them update
at the same clock time,
because that's when they when you
broadcast the bulk update, then there's
in the time of update. Right? So every
time you do anything,
if you want to make it so that it's not
statistically correlatable, you have to
do it in a bulk
or herd privacy protected way. You can't
do things one-on-one because
because the act of doing any kind of
interaction one-on-one leaks
correlatable metadata and it can't be
defeated. You will correlate around
whatever else you're doing because you
leaked it, right? So even Tor, you can
correlate around Tor because guess what
metadata Tor leaks? Anybody know what
metadata Tor leaks?
Variable packet size.
Right? You get enough of that, you can
figure out
Tor. So Spac, DSP protocol, we
have
uniform size packets. So there's
no So packet size can't be used for
correlation and we have no packets that
are just like vacuous blinded updates,
so you can whiten your time of arrival,
time of departure. And that's built into
the protocol because otherwise,
you do all of this work to
cryptographically
encrypt stuff
and to try to protect your metadata from
being correlated and then your protocol
just leaks it all away. So the
basic idea is want registries that bulk
update the observers.
The observers can't infer anything
because it's bulk updated, so you have
her privacy.
What is the weakness here? The weakness
here is that if an observer is malicious
and the issuer is malicious,
they can collude
and the observer can say, "Did you issue
this? Did you change the state of this
particular
point?" Right? So, there's so you
depend on repressing observers and
issuers from correlating, but there's no
phone home here.
The issuer can't force an observer
because there's no phone home.
Because all it needs is the
information in the registry to do the
ver- verification. So, so there's no
built-in mechanism for the observer to
trace anything in the system. It
requires criminals
to get together and form a criminal
thing, and as long as you make it
sufficiently legal, it might happen
sometimes.
But then you are in the boat of,
"Well, you've got fraud in the system."
And guess what? You can catch You
can catch them because
be- because they're they're
they're they're they're colluding
against the law and
and you have you have repression. But
yes, it won't it doesn't make it
impossible. Right? There's no technical
thing that makes it impossible in the in
this, but what it does is it means that
there's no easy way for them to do it.
So, the first step in SEDI is an
identity assurance process. What is
identity assurance?
Identity assurance solves one problem.
It's called the cheap pseudonymity
problem.
Anybody can create
a pseudonym, a cryptographic pseudonym,
and prove control of the creating AID,
right?
And as soon as they use the AID for
something and they did it for bad and
they say I'll just abandon and create a
new one.
Right? So, nobody can trust an AID that
anybody can create. Decentralized
identity has a big problem. The problem
is
anybody can create as many AID
IDs as they want and then abandon them
whenever they want to. So, nobody can
trust them, right? So, they're only good
ephemerally. If I want them good for
long-term, they need to have a
reputation that says there's a reason
why you can trust this.
So, the So, what GLEIF does is
provide with